<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><documents><document><year>2004</year><authors>Peter E. Hydon1  | Elizabeth L. Mansfield2 </authors><title>A Variational Complex for Difference Equations</title><content> An analogue of the Poincar&amp;eacute; lemma for exact forms on a lattice is statedand proved. Using this result as a starting-point, a variational complex for differenceequations is constructed and is proved to be locally exact. The proof uses homotopymaps, which enable one to calculate Lagrangians for discrete Euler&amp;#x2013;Lagrangesystems. Furthermore, such maps lead to a systematic technique for deriving conservationlaws of a given system of difference equations (whether or not it is anEuler&amp;#x2013;Lagrange system).</content></document><document><year>2004</year><authors>Guillaume Charpiat1 | Olivier Faugeras2  | Renaud Keriven1| 3 </authors><title>Approximations of Shape Metrics and Application to ShapeWarping and Empirical Shape Statistics</title><content> This paper proposes a framework for dealing with several problems relatedto the analysis of shapes. Two related such problems are the definition of therelevant set of shapes and that of defining a metric on it. Following a recent researchmonograph by Delfour and Zol&amp;eacute;sio [11], we consider the characteristic functionsof the subsets of R2 and their distance functions. The L2 norm of the difference ofcharacteristic functions, the L and the W1,2 norms of the difference of distancefunctions define interesting topologies, in particular the well-known Hausdorff distance.Because of practical considerations arising from the fact that we deal with image shapes defined on finite grids of pixels, we restrict our attention to subsets of2 of positive reach in the sense of Federer [16], with smooth boundaries of boundedcurvature. For this particular set of shapes we show that the three previous topologiesare equivalent. The next problem we consider is that of warping a shape onto anotherby infinitesimal gradient descent, minimizing the corresponding distance. Becausethe distance function involves an inf, it is not differentiable with respect to the shape.We propose a family of smooth approximations of the distance function which arecontinuous with respect to the Hausdorff topology, and hence with respect to theother two topologies. We compute the corresponding G&amp;acirc;teaux derivatives. They define deformation flows that can be used to warp a shape onto another by solving aninitial value problem.We show several examples of this warping and prove propertiesof our approximations that relate to the existence of local minima. We then use thistool to produce computational definitions of the empirical mean and covariance ofa set of shape examples. They yield an analog of the notion of principal modes ofvariation. We illustrate them on a variety of examples.</content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Laurent Baratchart1  | Maxim Yattselev1 </authors><title>Convergent Interpolation to Cauchy Integrals over;Analytic Arcs      </title><content>We consider multipoint PadГ© approximation to Cauchy transforms of complex measures. We show that if the support of a measure         is an analytic Jordan arc and if the measure itself is absolutely continuous with respect to the equilibrium distribution         of that arc with Dini-smooth nonvanishing density, then the diagonal multipoint PadГ© approximants associated with appropriate         interpolation schemes converge locally uniformly to the approximated Cauchy transform in the complement of the arc. This asymptotic         behavior of PadГ© approximants is deduced from the analysis of underlying non-Hermitian orthogonal polynomials, for which we         use classical properties of Hankel and Toeplitz operators on smooth curves. A construction of the appropriate interpolation         schemes is explicit granted the parametrization of the arc.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Emmanuel J. C|ГЁs1  | Benjamin Recht2 </authors><title>Exact Matrix Completion via Convex Optimization      </title><content>We consider a problem of considerable practical interest: the recovery of a data matrix from a sampling of its entries. Suppose         that we observe m entries selected uniformly at random from a matrix M. Can we complete the matrix and recover the entries that we have not seen?                     We show that one can perfectly recover most low-rank matrices from what appears to be an incomplete set of entries. We prove               that if the number m of sampled entries obeys                                                                                           </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>David Cohen-Steiner1| Herbert Edelsbrunner2| 3  | John Harer4</authors><title>Extending Persistence Using PoincarГ© and;Lefschetz Duality      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Guangliang Chen1  | Gilad Lerman1 </authors><title>Foundations of a Multi-way Spectral Clustering Framework for Hybrid Linear Modeling      </title><content>The problem of Hybrid Linear Modeling (HLM) is to model and segment data using a mixture of affine subspaces. Different strategies         have been proposed to solve this problem, however, rigorous analysis justifying their performance is missing. This paper suggests         the Theoretical Spectral Curvature Clustering (TSCC) algorithm for solving the HLM problem and provides careful analysis to         justify it. The TSCC algorithm is practically a combination of Govindu&amp;#8217;s multi-way spectral clustering framework (CVPR 2005)         and Ng et al.&amp;#8217;s spectral clustering algorithm (NIPS 2001). The main result of this paper states that if the given data is         sampled from a mixture of distributions concentrated around affine subspaces, then with high sampling probability the TSCC         algorithm segments well the different underlying clusters. The goodness of clustering depends on the within-cluster errors,         the between-clusters interaction, and a tuning parameter applied by TSCC. The proof also provides new insights for the analysis         of Ng et;al. (NIPS 2001).      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Michael Gnewuch1  | Henryk Wo&amp;#378 niakowski2| 3 </authors><title>Generalized Tractability for Multivariate Problems Part;II: Linear Tensor Product Problems, Linear Information, and Unrestricted         Tractability      </title><content>We continue the study of generalized tractability initiated in our previous paper &amp;#8220;Generalized tractability for multivariate         problems, Part I: Linear tensor product problems and linear information&amp;#8221;, J.;Complex. 23:262&amp;#8211;295, 2007. We study linear tensor product problems for which we can compute linear information which is given by arbitrary continuous         linear functionals. We want to approximate an operator S                     d             given as the d-fold tensor product of a compact linear operator S         1 for d=1,2,&amp;#8230;, with &amp;#8214;S         1&amp;#8214;=1 and S         1 having at least two positive singular values.                     Let n(&amp;#949;,S                                 d                  ) be the minimal number of information evaluations needed to approximate S                                 d                   to within &amp;#949;&amp;#8712;[0,1]. We study generalized tractability by verifying when n(&amp;#949;,S                                 d                  ) can be bounded by a multiple of a power of T(&amp;#949;               &amp;#8722;1,d) for all (&amp;#949;               &amp;#8722;1,d)&amp;#8712;&amp;#937;&amp;#8838;[1,&amp;#8734;)Г—&amp;#8469;. Here, T is a tractability function which is non-decreasing in both variables and grows slower than exponentially to infinity. We study the exponent of tractability which is the smallest power of T(&amp;#949;               &amp;#8722;1,d) whose multiple bounds n(&amp;#949;,S                                 d                  ). We also study weak tractability, i.e., when                               .            </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Peter H. van der Kamp1 </authors><title>Global Classification of Two-Component Approximately Integrable Evolution Equations      </title><content>We globally classify two-component evolution equations, with homogeneous diagonal linear part, admitting infinitely many approximate         symmetries. Important ingredients are the symbolic calculus of Gel&amp;#8217;fand and Diki&amp;#301;, the Skolem&amp;#8211;Mahler&amp;#8211;Lech theorem, an algorithm         of Smyth, and results on diophantine equations in roots of unity obtained by Beukers.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Hans-Christian Graf von Bothmer1 | Kristian Ranestad2  | Frank Sottile3 </authors><title>Linear Precision for Toric Surface Patches      </title><content>We classify the homogeneous polynomials in three variables whose toric polar linear system defines a Cremona transformation.         This classification includes, as a proper subset, the classification of toric surface patches from geometric modeling which         have linear precision. Besides the well-known tensor product patches and BГ©zier triangles, we identify a family of toric patches         with trapezoidal shape, each of which has linear precision. Furthermore, BГ©zier triangles and tensor product patches are special         cases of trapezoidal patches.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>S. Smale1 | L. Rosasco2 | J. Bouvrie3 | A. Caponnetto4  | T. Poggio5 </authors><title>Mathematics of the Neural Response      </title><content>We propose a natural image representation, the neural response, motivated by the neuroscience of the visual cortex. The inner         product defined by the neural response leads to a similarity measure between functions which we call the derived kernel. Based         on a hierarchical architecture, we give a recursive definition of the neural response and associated derived kernel. The derived         kernel can be used in a variety of application domains such as classification of images, strings of text and genomics data.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Pawe&amp;#322  Pilarczyk1 </authors><title>Parallelization Method for a Continuous Property      </title><content>An automated general purpose method is introduced for computing a rigorous estimate of a bounded region in &amp;#8477;            n             whose points satisfy a given property. The method is based on calculations conducted in interval arithmetic and the constructed         approximation is built of rectangular boxes of variable sizes. An efficient strategy is proposed, which makes use of parallel         computations on multiple machines and refines the estimate gradually. It is proved that under certain assumptions the result         of computations converges to the exact result as the precision of calculations increases. The time complexity of the algorithm         is analyzed, and the effectiveness of this approach is illustrated by constructing a lower bound on the set of parameters         for which an overcompensatory nonlinear Leslie population model exhibits more than one attractor, which is of interest from         the biological point of view. This paper is accompanied by efficient and flexible software written in C++ whose source code         is freely available at http://www.pawelpilarczyk.com/parallel/.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Daniel Wilczak1  | Piotr Zgliczy&amp;#324 ski2 </authors><title>Period Doubling in the RГ¶ssler System&amp;#8212;A Computer Assisted Proof      </title><content>Using rigorous numerical methods, we validate a part of the bifurcation diagram for a PoincarГ© map of the RГ¶ssler system (RГ¶ssler         in Phys. Lett. A 57(5):397&amp;#8211;398, 1976)&amp;#8212;the existence of two period-doubling bifurcations and the existence of a branch of period two points connecting them. Our         approach is based on the Lyapunov&amp;#8211;Schmidt reduction and uses the C                     r            -Lohner algorithm (Wilczak and Zgliczy&amp;#324;ski, available at http://www.ii.uj.edu.pl/~wilczak) to obtain rigorous bounds for the RГ¶ssler system.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Klaus Meer1  | Martin Ziegler2 </authors><title>Real Computational Universality: The Word Problem for a Class of Groups with Infinite Presentation      </title><content>The word problem for discrete groups is well known to be undecidable by a Turing Machine; more precisely, it is reducible         both to and from and thus equivalent to the discrete Halting Problem. The present work introduces and studies a real extension         of the word problem for a certain class of groups which are presented as quotient groups of a free group and a normal subgroup.         As a main difference to discrete groups these groups may be generated by uncountably many generators with index running over certain sets of real numbers. We study the word problem for such groups         within the Blum&amp;#8211;Shub&amp;#8211;Smale (BSS) model of real number computation. The main result establishes the word problem to be computationally         equivalent to the Halting Problem for such machines. It thus gives the first non-trivial example of a problem complete, that is, computationally universal for this model.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>P. Wojtaszczyk1| 2 </authors><title>Stability and Instance Optimality for Gaussian Measurements in Compressed Sensing      </title><content>In compressed sensing, we seek to gain information about a vector x&amp;#8712;&amp;#8477;            N             from d         &amp;#8810;         N nonadaptive linear measurements. Candes, Donoho, Tao et al. (see, e.g., Candes, Proc. Intl. Congress Math., Madrid, 2006; Candes et al., Commun. Pure Appl. Math. 59:1207&amp;#8211;1223, 2006; Donoho, IEEE Trans. Inf. Theory 52:1289&amp;#8211;1306, 2006) proposed to seek a good approximation to x via &amp;#8467;         1 minimization. In this paper, we show that in the case of Gaussian measurements, &amp;#8467;         1 minimization recovers the signal well from inaccurate measurements, thus improving the result from Candes et al. (Commun.         Pure Appl. Math. 59:1207&amp;#8211;1223, 2006). We also show that this numerically friendly algorithm (see Candes et al., Commun. Pure Appl. Math. 59:1207&amp;#8211;1223, 2006) with overwhelming probability recovers the signal with accuracy, comparable to the accuracy of the best k-term approximation in the Euclidean norm when k&amp;#8764;d/ln&amp;#8201;N.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Michal Marvan1 </authors><title>Sufficient Set of Integrability Conditions of;an;Orthonomic System      </title><content>Every orthonomic system of partial differential equations is known to possess a finite number of integrability conditions         sufficient to ensure the validity of them all. Here we show that a redundancy-free sufficient set of integrability conditions         can be constructed in a time proportional to the number of equations cubed.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Ricardo S. Leite1 | Nicolau C. Saldanha2  | Carlos Tomei2 </authors><title>The Asymptotics of Wilkinson&amp;#8217;s Shift: Loss of Cubic Convergence      </title><content>One of the most widely used methods for eigenvalue computation is the QR iteration with Wilkinson&amp;#8217;s shift: Here, the shift s is the eigenvalue of the bottom 2Г—2 principal minor closest to the corner entry. It has been a long-standing question whether         the rate of convergence of the algorithm is always cubic. In contrast, we show that there exist matrices for which the rate         of convergence is strictly quadratic. More precisely, let                    be the 3Г—3 matrix having only two nonzero entries                    and let                    be the set of real, symmetric tridiagonal matrices with the same spectrum as                   . There exists a neighborhood                    of                    which is invariant under Wilkinson&amp;#8217;s shift strategy with the following properties. For                   , the sequence of iterates (T                     k            ) exhibits either strictly quadratic or strictly cubic convergence to zero of the entry (T                     k            )23. In fact, quadratic convergence occurs exactly when                   . Let                    be the union of such quadratically convergent sequences (T                     k            ): The set                    has Hausdorff dimension 1 and is a union of disjoint arcs                    meeting at                   , where &amp;#963; ranges over a Cantor set.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Marian Mrozek1| 2  | Roman Srzednicki3 </authors><title>Topological Approach to Rigorous Numerics of Chaotic Dynamical Systems with Strong Expansion of Error Bounds      </title><content>A new algorithm for obtaining rigorous results concerning the existence of chaotic invariant sets of dynamical systems generated         by non-autonomous, time-periodic differential equations is presented. Unlike all other algorithms the presented algorithm         does not require the numerical integration of the solutions and as a consequence it is insensitive to the rapid error growth         in the case of long integration. The result is based on a new theoretical approach to the computation of the homology of the         PoincarГ© map. A concrete numerical example concerning a time-periodic differential equation in the complex plane is provided.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Kurusch Ebrahimi-Fard1  | Dominique Manchon2 </authors><title>A Magnus- and Fer-Type Formula in Dendriform Algebras      </title><content>We provide a refined approach to the classical Magnus (Commun. Pure Appl. Math. 7:649&amp;#8211;673, [1954]) and Fer expansion (Bull. Classe Sci. Acad. R. Belg. 44:818&amp;#8211;829, [1958]), unveiling a new structure by using the language of dendriform and pre-Lie algebras. The recursive formula for the logarithm         of the solutions of the equations X=1+&amp;#955;         a         &amp;#8826;         X and Y=1&amp;#8722;&amp;#955;         Y         &amp;#8827;         a in A[[&amp;#955;]] is provided, where (A,&amp;#8826;,&amp;#8827;) is a dendriform algebra. Then we present the solutions to these equations as an infinite product expansion of exponentials.         Both formulae involve the pre-Lie product naturally associated with the dendriform structure. Several applications are presented.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Hongzhi Tong1 | Di-Rong Chen2  | Lizhong Peng1 </authors><title>Analysis of Support Vector Machines Regression      </title><content>Support vector machines regression (SVMR) is a regularized learning algorithm in reproducing kernel Hilbert spaces with a         loss function called the &amp;#949;-insensitive loss function. Compared with the well-understood least square regression, the study of SVMR is not satisfactory,         especially the quantitative estimates of the convergence of this algorithm. This paper provides an error analysis for SVMR,         and introduces some recently developed methods for analysis of classification algorithms such as the projection operator and         the iteration technique. The main result is an explicit learning rate for the SVMR algorithm under some assumptions.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Raphael Hauser1  | Tobias MГјller2 </authors><title>Conditioning of Random Conic Systems Under a;General Family of Input Distributions      </title><content>We consider the conic feasibility problem associated with the linear homogeneous system Ax&amp;#8804;0, x&amp;#8800;0. The complexity of iterative algorithms for solving this problem depends on a condition number C(A). When studying the typical behavior of algorithms under stochastic input, one is therefore naturally led to investigate         the fatness of the tails of the distribution of C(A). Introducing the very general class of uniformly absolutely continuous probability models for the random matrix;A, we show that the distribution tails of C(A) decrease at algebraic rates, both for the Goffin&amp;#8211;Cheung&amp;#8211;Cucker number C                     G             and the Renegar number C                     R            . The exponent that drives the decay arises naturally in the theory of uniform absolute continuity, which we also develop in this paper. In the case of C                     G            , we also discuss lower bounds on the tail probabilities and show that there exist absolutely continuous input models for         which the tail decay is subalgebraic.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Gabriela Jeronimo1| 2 | Guillermo Matera2| 3 | Pablo SolernГі1| 2  | Ariel Waissbein4| 5 </authors><title>Deformation Techniques for Sparse Systems      </title><content>We exhibit a probabilistic symbolic algorithm for solving zero-dimensional sparse systems. Our algorithm combines a symbolic         homotopy procedure, based on a flat deformation of a certain morphism of affine varieties, with the polyhedral deformation         of Huber and Sturmfels. The complexity of our algorithm is cubic in the size of the combinatorial structure of the input system.         This size is mainly represented by the cardinality and mixed volume of Newton polytopes of the input polynomials and an arithmetic         analogue of the mixed volume associated to the deformations under consideration.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Saugata Basu1 </authors><title>Errata for Computing the Top Betti Numbers of Semialgebraic Sets Defined by Quadratic Inequalities in Polynomial Time      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>David Cohen-Steiner1| Herbert Edelsbrunner2| 3  | John Harer4</authors><title>Extending Persistence Using PoincarГ© and Lefschetz Duality      </title><content>Persistent homology has proven to be a useful tool in a variety of contexts, including the recognition and measurement of         shape characteristics of surfaces in &amp;#8477;3. Persistence pairs homology classes that are born and die in a filtration of a topological space, but does not pair its actual         homology classes. For the sublevelset filtration of a surface in &amp;#8477;3, persistence has been extended to a pairing of essential classes using Reeb graphs. In this paper, we give an algebraic formulation         that extends persistence to essential homology for any filtered space, present an algorithm to calculate it, and describe         how it aids our ability to recognize shape features for codimension 1 submanifolds of Euclidean space. The extension derives         from PoincarГ© duality but generalizes to nonmanifold spaces. We prove stability for general triangulated spaces and duality         as well as symmetry for triangulated manifolds.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Elizabeth L.  Mansfield1</authors><title>Algorithms for Symmetric Differential Systems      </title><content> Over-determined systems of partial differential equations may be studied using differential&amp;#8212;elimination algorithms, as a         great deal of information about the solution set of the system may be obtained from the output. Unfortunately, many systems         are effectively intractable by these methods due to the expression swell incurred in the intermediate stages of the calculations.         This can happen when, for example, the input system depends on many variables and is invariant under a large rotation group,         so that there is no natural choice of term ordering in the elimination and reduction processes. This paper describes how systems         written in terms of the differential invariants of a Lie group action may be processed in a manner analogous to differential&amp;#8212;elimination         algorithms. The algorithm described terminates and yields, in a sense which we make precise, a complete set of representative         invariant integrability conditions which may be calculated in a ``critical pair'' completion procedure. Further, we discuss         some of the profound differences between algebras of differential invariants and standard differential algebras. We use the         new, regularized moving frame method of Fels and Olver [11], [12] to write a differential system in terms of the invariants         of a symmetry group. The methods described have been implemented as a package in \MAPLE. The main example discussed is the         analysis of the (2+1 )-d'Alembert&amp;#8212;Hamilton system                      u_{xx}+u_{yy}- u_{zz}&amp;amp;=&amp;amp; f(u), u_x^2+u_y^2- u_z^2&amp;amp;=&amp;amp;1. (1)</content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors> Dima Grigoriev1</authors><title>Approximation and Complexity: Liouvillean-Type Theorems for Linear Differential Equations on an Interval      </title><content> Let  u,v  be solutions on an interval I  of linear differential equations (LDEs) P=0 , Q=0 , respectively. We obtain a lower bound on the approximation of v  by u  in terms of bounds on the coefficients of LDE S                     i                     =0  (for several i ), satisfied by the i th derivative of v  and by the i th derivative of a basis of the LDE P=0 . One could view this result as a differential analog of the Liouville theorem which states that two different algebraic         numbers are well separated if they satisfy algebraic equations with small enough integer coefficients. Unlike the algebraic         situation, in the differential setting, in order to bound from below the difference |u-v| , we need to involve not only the coefficients of P,Q  themselves, but also those of S                     i             .      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>L. Baratchart1| V. A. Prokhorov2 | E. B. Saff3</authors><title>Best Meromorphic Approximation of Markov Functions on the Unit Circle      </title><content> Let E \subset(-1,1)  be a compact set, let &amp;#956;  be a positive Borel measure with support \supp &amp;#956; =E , and let H                     p                     (G),         1&amp;#8804; p &amp;#8804;&amp;#8712;fty,  be the Hardy space of analytic functions on the open unit disk G  with circumference &amp;#915;={z \colon |z|=1} . Let &amp;#916;                     n,p              be the error in best approximation of the Markov function   \frac{1}{2&amp;#960; i} &amp;#8712;t_E \frac{d &amp;#956;(x)}{z-x}   in the space L                     p                     (&amp;#915;)  by meromorphic functions that can be represented in the form h=P/Q , where  P &amp;#8712; H                     p                     (G),         Q   is a polynomial of degree at most n , Q\not \equiv 0 . We investigate the rate of decrease of &amp;#916;                     n,p                     ,         1&amp;#8804; p &amp;#8804;&amp;#8712;fty , and its connection with n -widths. The convergence of the best meromorphic approximants and the limiting distribution of poles of the best approximants         are described in the case when 1&amp;lt;p&amp;#8804;&amp;#8712;fty  and the measure &amp;#956;  with support E=[a,b]  satisfies the Szeg&amp;#337; condition   &amp;#8712;t_a^b \frac{\log(d &amp;#956;/ d x)}{\sqrt{(x-a)(b-x)}} dx &amp;gt;- &amp;#8712;fty.        </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Mike  Shub</authors><title>Editorial      </title><content/></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>T. Y. Li1 | Xing  Li1</authors><title>Finding Mixed Cells in the Mixed Volume Computation      </title><content> In practice, finding mixed cells in certain polyhedral subdivisions plays a dominating role when a polyhedral homotopy is         employed to approximate all isolated zeros of polynomial systems. This paper gives a new algorithm for the mixed cell computation         via a new formulation of the underlying linear programming problems. Numerical results show that the algorithm provides a         major advance in the speed of computation with much less memory requirements.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors> Levent TunГ§el1</authors><title>Generalization of Primal&amp;#8212;Dual Interior-Point Methods to Convex Optimization Problems in Conic Form      </title><content> We generalize primal&amp;#8212;dual interior-point methods for linear programming (LP) problems to the convex optimization problems         in conic form. Previously, the most comprehensive theory of symmetric primal&amp;#8212;dual interior-point algorithms was given by Nesterov         and Todd for feasible regions expressed as the intersection of a symmetric cone with an affine subspace. In our setting, we         allow an arbitrary convex cone in place of the symmetric cone. Even though some of the impressive properties attained by Nesterov&amp;#8212;Todd         algorithms are impossible in this general setting of convex optimization problems, we show that essentially all primal&amp;#8212;dual         interior-point algorithms for LP can be extended easily to the general setting. We provide three frameworks for primal&amp;#8212;dual         algorithms, each framework corresponding to a different level of sophistication in the algorithms. As the level of sophistication         increases, we demand better formulations of the feasible solution sets. Our algorithms, in return, attain provably better         theoretical properties. We also make a very strong connection to quasi-Newton methods by expressing the square of the symmetric         primal&amp;#8212;dual linear transformation (the so-called scaling) as a quasi-Newton update in the case of the least sophisticated         framework.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>H. Z. Munthe-Kaas1| G. R. W.   Quispel2 | A.  Zanna3</authors><title>Generalized Polar Decompositions on Lie Groups with Involutive Automorphisms      </title><content> The polar decomposition, a well-known algorithm for decomposing real matrices as the product of a positive semidefinite matrix         and an orthogonal matrix, is intimately related to involutive automorphisms of Lie groups and the subspace decomposition they         induce. Such generalized polar decompositions, depending on the choice of the involutive automorphism &amp;#963; , always exist near the identity although frequently they can be extended to larger portions of the underlying group.                      In this paper, first of all we provide an alternative proof to the local existence and uniqueness result of the generalized               polar decomposition. What is new in our approach is that we derive differential equations obeyed by the two factors and solve               them analytically, thereby providing explicit Lie-algebra recurrence relations for the coefficients of the series expansion.            </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Peter J.  Olver1</authors><title>Joint Invariant Signatures      </title><content> A new, algorithmic theory of moving frames is applied to classify joint invariants and joint differential invariants of transformation         groups. Equivalence and symmetry properties of submanifolds are completely determined by their joint signatures, which are         parametrized by a suitable collection of joint invariants and/or joint differential invariants. A variety of fundamental geometric         examples are developed in detail. Applications to object recognition problems in computer vision and the design of invariant         numerical approximations are indicated.       </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>A. Iserles1</authors><title>On Cayley-Transform Methods for the Discretization of Lie-Group Equations      </title><content> In this paper we develop in a systematic manner the theory of time-stepping methods based on the Cayley transform. Such methods         can be applied to discretize differential equations that evolve in some Lie groups, in particular in the orthogonal group         and the symplectic group. Unlike many other Lie-group solvers, they do not require the evaluation of matrix exponentials.         Similarly to the theory of Magnus expansions in [13], we identify terms in a Cayley expansion  with rooted trees, which can be constructed recursively. Each such term is an integral over a polytope but all such integrals         can be evaluated to high order by using special quadrature formulas similar to the construction in [13]. Truncated Cayley expansions (with exact integrals) need not be time-symmetric, hence the method does not display the usual         advantages associated with time symmetry, e.g., even order of approximation. However, time symmetry (with its attendant benefits)         is attained when exact integrals are replaced by certain quadrature formulas.       </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>J. Demmel1| B. Diament2 | G. Malajovich3</authors><title>On the Complexity of Computing Error Bounds      </title><content> We consider the cost of estimating an error bound for the computed solution of a system of linear equations, i.e., estimating         the norm of a matrix inverse. Under some technical assumptions we show that computing even a coarse error bound for the solution         of a triangular system of equations costs at least as much as testing whether the product of two matrices is zero. The complexity         of the latter problem is in turn conjectured to be the same as matrix multiplication, matrix inversion, etc. Since most error         bounds in practical use have much lower complexity, this means they should sometimes exhibit large errors. In particular,         it is shown that condition estimators that: (1) perform at least one operation on each matrix entry; and (2) are asymptotically         faster than any zero tester, must sometimes over or underestimate the inverse norm by a factor of at least   , where n  is the dimension of the input matrix, k  is the bitsize, and where either    or    grows faster than any polynomial in n . Our results hold for the RAM model with bit complexity, as well as computations over rational and algebraic numbers, but         not real or complex numbers. Our results also extend to estimating error bounds or condition numbers for other linear algebra         problems such as computing eigenvectors.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>G. W. Wasilkowski1 | H. Wozniakowski2</authors><title>On the Power of Standard Information for Weighted Approximation      </title><content> We study weighted approximation of multivariate functions for classes of standard and linear information in the worst case         and average case settings. Under natural assumptions, we show a relation between n th minimal errors for these two classes of information. This relation enables us to infer convergence and error bounds for         standard information, as well as the equivalence of tractability and strong tractability for the two classes.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Suzanne Lynch Hruska1 </authors><title>A Numerical Method for Constructing the Hyperbolic Structure of Complex Henon Mappings      </title><content>For complex parameters a,c, we consider the Henon mapping                     given by                    and its Julia set, J. In this paper we describe a rigorous computer program for attempting to construct a cone field in the tangent bundle over         J, which is preserved by DH, and a continuous norm in which                    uniformly expands the cones (and their complements). We show a consequence of a successful construction is a proof that H is {hyperbolic} on J.  We give several new examples of hyperbolic maps,  produced with our computer program, Hypatia, which implements our methods.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>F. Alvarez1 | J. Bolte2  | J. Munier3 </authors><title>A Unifying Local Convergence Result for Newton's Method in Riemannian Manifolds      </title><content>We consider the problem of finding a singularity of a differentiable vector field X defined on a complete Riemannian manifold.         We prove a unified result for theexistence and local uniqueness of the solution, and for the local convergence of a Riemannian         version of Newton's method. Our approach relies on Kantorovich's majorant principle: under suitable conditions, we construct         an auxiliary scalar equation &amp;#966;(r) = 0 which dominates the original equation X(p) = 0 in the sense that the Riemannian-Newton         method for the latter inherits several features of the real Newton method applied to the former. The majorant &amp;#966; is derived         from an adequate radial parametrization of a Lipschitz-type continuity property of the covariant derivative of X, a technique         inspired by the previous work of Zabrejko and Nguen on Newton's method in Banach spaces. We show how different specializations         of the main result recover Riemannian versions of Kantorovich's theorem and Smale's &amp;#945;-theorem, and, at least partially, the         Euclidean self-concordant theory of Nesterov and Nemirovskii. In the specific case of analytic vector fields, we improve          recent developments inthis area by Dedieu et al. (IMA J. Numer. Anal., Vol. 23, 2003, pp. 395-419). Some Riemannian techniques used here were previously introduced by Ferreira and Svaiter (J. Complexity, Vol. 18, 2002, pp. 304-329) in the context of Kantorovich's theorem for vector fields with Lipschitz continuous covariant derivatives.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Jeongoo Cheh1 | Peter J. Olver2  | Juha Pohjanpelto3 </authors><title>Algorithms for Differential Invariants of Symmetry Groups of Differential Equations      </title><content>We develop new computational algorithms, based on the method of equivariant moving frames, for classifying the differential         invariants of Lie symmetry pseudo-groups of differential equations and analyzing the structure of the induced differential         invariant algebra. The Korteweg-deVries (KdV) and Kadomtsev-Petviashvili (KP) equations serve to illustrate examples. In particular,         we deduce the first complete classification of the differential invariants and their syzygies of the KP symmetry pseudo-group.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>W.D. Kalies1 | K. Mischaikow2  | R.C.A.M. V|erVorst3 </authors><title>An Algorithmic Approach to Chain Recurrence      </title><content>In this paper we give a new definition of the chain recurrent set of a         continuous map using finite spatial discretizations. This approach allows for an algorithmic construction of isolating blocks         for the components of Morse decompositions which approximate the chain recurrent set arbitrarily closely as well as discrete         approximations of Conley&amp;#8217;s Lyapunov function. This is a natural framework in which to develop computational techniques for         the analysis of qualitative dynamics including rigorous computer-assisted proofs.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Ronald DeVore1 | Gerard Kerkyacharian2 | Dominique Picard3  | Vladimir Temlyakov1 </authors><title>Approximation Methods for Supervised Learning      </title><content> Let &amp;#961; be an unknown Borel measure defined on the space Z := X Г— Y with X &amp;#8834; &amp;#8477;d and Y = [-M,M]. Given a set z of m samples zi =(xi,yi) drawn according to  &amp;#961;, the problem of estimating a regression function f&amp;#961;  using these samples is considered. The main focus         is to understand what is the rate of approximation, measured either in         expectation or probability,   that can be obtained under  a given  prior          f&amp;#961; &amp;#8712; &amp;#920;, i.e., under the assumption that f&amp;#961; is in the set         &amp;#920;, and what are possible algorithms for obtaining optimal or         semioptimal  (up to  logarithms) results.  The optimal rate of decay in terms         of m is established for many priors given either in terms of smoothness of         f&amp;#961; or its rate of approximation measured in one of several ways.  This optimal rate is determined by two types of results.          Upper bounds are established using various tools in approximation such as entropy, widths, and linear and nonlinear approximation.         Lower bounds are proved using         Kullback-Leibler information together with Fano inequalities and a certain type         of entropy.  A distinction is drawn between  algorithms  which employ knowledge         of the prior in the construction of the estimator and those that do not.         Algorithms  of the second type which are universally optimal for a certain range         of priors are given.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Martin N. Huxley1  | Jovisa Zunic2| 3 </authors><title>Different Digitisations of Displaced Discs      </title><content>The digitisation                    of a real disc                            having   radius                    and  centre                    consists of all integer points inside                    , i.e.,                    In this paper we show  that there are                                                                                                                                                </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Francis J. Narcowich1 | Xingping Sun2| Joseph D. Ward1 | Holger Wendl|3</authors><title>Direct and Inverse Sobolev Error Estimates for  Scattered Data Interpolation via Spherical Basis Functions      </title><content>The purpose of this paper is to get error estimates for spherical basis function (SBF) interpolation and approximation for         target functions in Sobolev spaces less smooth than the SBFs, and to show that the rates achieved are, in a sense, best possible.         In addition, we establish a Bernstein-type theorem, where the smallest separation between data sites plays the role of a Nyquist         frequency. We then use these Berstein-type estimates to derive inverse estimates for interpolation via SBFs.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Peter J. Vassiliou1 </authors><title>Efficient Construction of Contact Coordinates for Partial         Prolongations      </title><content>Let V be a vector field distribution or Pfaffian system on manifold M. We give an efficient algorithm for the construction         of local coordinates on M such that V may be locally expressed as some partial prolongation of the contact distribution C(1)q, on the first-order jet bundle of maps from &amp;#8477; to &amp;#8477;q, q &amp;#8805; 1. It is proven that if V is locally equivalent to a partial prolongation of  C(1)q, then the explicit construction of contact coordinates algorithmically depends upon the determination of certain first integrals         in a sequence of geometrically defined and algorithmically determined integrable Pfaffian systems on M. The number of these         first integrals that must be computed satisfies a natural minimality criterion. These results provide a full and constructive         generalisation of the Goursat normal form from the theory of exterior differential systems.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>C. Beltran1  | L.M. Pardo1 </authors><title>Estimates on the Distribution of the Condition Number of Singular Matrices      </title><content>We exhibit some new techniques to study volumes of tubes about algebraic varieties in complex projective spaces. We prove         the existence of relations between volumes and Intersection Theory in the presence of singularities. In particular, we can         exhibit an average Bezout Equality for equidimensional varieties. We also state an upper bound for the volume of a tube about         a projective variety. As a main outcome, we prove an upper bound estimate for the volume of the intersection of a tube with         an equidimensional projective algebraic variety. We apply these techniques to exhibit upper bounds for the probability distribution         of the generalized condition number of singular complex matrices.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Matthias Aschenbrenner1  | Raymond Hemmecke2 </authors><title>Finiteness Theorems in Stochastic Integer Programming      </title><content>We study Graver test sets for families of linear multistage stochastic integer programs with a varying number of scenarios.         We show that these test sets can be decomposed into finitely many "building blocks," independent of the number of scenarios,         and we give an effective procedure to compute them. The paper includes an introduction to Nash-Williams' theory of better-quasi-orderings,         which is used to show termination of our algorithm. We also apply this theory to finiteness results for Hilbert functions.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Lenore Blum| Felipe Cucker| Tomaso Poggio| James Renegar|  | Michael Shub</authors><title>Foreword      </title><content>Steve Smale set the agenda for FoCM in his call for the 1995 conference in Park City, Utah. No stranger he to ambitious agendas         and extraordinary accomplishments. He is one of the dominant figures in the mathematics of the second half of the twentieth         century. Smale&amp;#8217;s theory of immersions, the generalized Poincare conjecture, and H-cobordism theorems with their far-reaching         consequences are the bedrock of differential topology. His horseshoe is the hallmark of chaos, and his hyperbolic dynamics         the rejuvenation of the geometric theory of dynamical systems. He is one of the pioneers in the introduction of infinite-dimensional         manifolds for the study of nonlinear problems in the calculus of variations and partial differential equations. The list goes         on: the systematic use of differential techniques in microeconomics, electrical circuit theory, chaos in predator&amp;#8211;prey equations         and, finally, for the twentieth century, the foundations of computational mathematics and complexity theory, and now, in the         twenty-first century, the theory of learning. It has been our privilege to be among his collaborators and students in the         broadest sense of the word. With these issues (Volume 5 Number 4 and Volume 6 Number 1, as well as an earlier article appearing         in Volume 5 Number 2, are dedicated to Steve Smale&amp;#8217;s 75th Birthday) we celebrate Steve&amp;#8217;s 75th birthday and continuing vitality.         He sets the bar high. We do our best.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>James Renegar1 </authors><title>Hyperbolic Programs,  and Their Derivative Relaxations      </title><content>We study the algebraic and facial structures of hyperbolic programs, and examine natural relaxations of hyperbolic programs,         the relaxations themselves being hyperbolic programs.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Marian Mrozek1 </authors><title>Index Pairs Algorithms      </title><content>We introduce some modifications and extensions of the concept of index pair         in the Conley index theory. We then show how these concepts may be used to overcome some difficulties in obtaining efficient         algorithms computing the Conley index. We also present examples of applications to computer assisted proofs in dynamics.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Cohen-Steiner Narcowich1  | Herbert Edelsbrunner2 </authors><title>Inequalities for the Curvature of Curves and Surfaces      </title><content>In this paper we bound the difference between the total mean curvatures of two closed surfaces in                    in terms of their total absolute curvatures and the Frechet distance between the volumes they enclose. The proof relies on         a combination of methods from algebraic topology and integral geometry. We also bound the difference between the lengths of         two curves using the same methods.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Alex|er Barvinok1 </authors><title>Integration and Optimization of Multivariate Polynomials by Restriction onto a Random Subspace      </title><content>We consider the problem of efficient integration of an n-variate polynomial with respect to the Gaussian measure in &amp;#8477;n and related problems of complex integration and optimization of a polynomial on the unit sphere. We identify a class of n-variate         polynomials f for which the integral of any positive integer power fp over the whole space is well approximated by a properly scaled integral over a random subspace of dimension O(log n). Consequently,         the maximum of f on the unit sphere is well approximated by a properly scaled maximum on the unit sphere in a random subspace         of dimension O(log n). We discuss connections with problems of combinatorial counting and applications to efficient approximation         of a hafnian of a positive matrix.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Qiang Wu1 | Yiming Ying1  | Ding-Xuan Zhou1 </authors><title>Learning Rates of Least-Square Regularized Regression      </title><content>This paper considers the regularized learning algorithm associated         with the least-square loss and reproducing kernel Hilbert spaces. The target is the error analysis for the regression problem         in learning theory. A novel regularization approach is presented, which yields satisfactory learning rates. The rates depend         on the approximation property and on the capacity of the reproducing kernel Hilbert space measured by covering numbers. When         the kernel is C&amp;#8734; and the regression function lies in the corresponding reproducing kernel Hilbert space, the rate is m&amp;#950; with &amp;#950; arbitrarily close to 1, regardless of the variance of the bounded probability distribution.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Thomas Muller-Gronbach1  | Klaus Ritter2 </authors><title>Lower Bounds and Nonuniform Time Discretization for Approximation of Stochastic Heat Equations      </title><content>We study algorithms for approximation of the mild solution of stochastic heat equations on the spatial domain ]0, 1[d. The error of an algorithm is defined in L2-sense. We derive lower bounds for the error of every algorithm that uses a total of N evaluations of one-dimensional components         of the driving Wiener process W. For equations with additive noise we derive matching upper bounds and we construct asymptotically         optimal algorithms. The error bounds depend on N and d, and on the decay of eigenvalues of the covariance of W in the case         of nuclear noise. In the latter case the use of nonuniform time discretizations is crucial.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Martin Avendano1 | Teresa Krick1  | Ariel Pacetti1 </authors><title>Newton&amp;#8211;Hensel Interpolation Lifting      </title><content>The main result of this paper is a new version of Newton-Hensel lifting         that relates to interpolation questions. It allows one to lift polynomials in &amp;#8484;[x] from information modulo a prime number         p &amp;#8800; 2 to a power pk for any k, and its originality is that it  is  a mixed version that not only lifts the coefficients of the polynomial but         also its exponents. We show that this result corresponds exactly to a Newton--Hensel lifting of a system of 2t generalized         equations in 2t unknowns in the ring of p-adic  integers &amp;#8484;p. Finally, we apply our results to sparse polynomial interpolation in &amp;#8484;[x].      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Anthony M. Bloch1  | Arieh Iserles2 </authors><title>On an Isospectral Lie&amp;#8211;Poisson System and Its Lie Algebra      </title><content>         In this paper we analyze the matrix differential system X' = [N,X2], where N is skew-symmetric and X(0) is symmetric. We prove that it is isospectral and that it is endowed with a Poisson         structure, and we discuss its invariants and Casimirs. Formulation of the Poisson problem in a Lie-Poisson setting, as a flow         on a dual of a Lie algebra, requires a computation of its faithful representation. Although the existence of a faithful representation,         assured by the Ado theorem and a symbolic algorithm, due to de Graaf, exists for the general  computation of faithful representations         of Lie algebras, the practical problem of forming a "tight" representation, convenient for subsequent analytic and numerical         work, belongs to numerical algebra. We solve it for the Poisson structure corresponding to the equation X' = [N,X2].      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>M. Giusti1 | G. Lecerf2 | B. Salvy3  | J.-C. Yakoubsohn4 </authors><title>On Location and Approximation of Clusters of Zeros: Case of Embedding Dimension One      </title><content>Isolated multiple zeros or clusters of zeros of analytic maps with several variables are known to be difficult to locate and         approximate.  This paper is in the vein of the &amp;#945;-theory,  initiated by M. Shub and S. Smale in the beginning of the 1980s.         This theory restricts to simple zeros, i.e., where the map has corank zero. In this paper we deal with situations where the         analytic map has corank one at the multiple isolated zero, which has embedding dimension one in the frame of deformation theory.         These situations are the least degenerate ones and therefore most likely to be of practical significance. More generally,         we define clusters of embedding dimension one. We provide a criterion for locating such clusters of zeros and a fast algorithm         for approximating them, with quadratic convergence. In the case of a cluster with positive diameter         our algorithm stops at a distance of the cluster which is about its diameter.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Steve  Smale1  | Yuan Yao2 </authors><title>Online Learning Algorithms      </title><content>In this paper, we study an online learning algorithm in Reproducing         Kernel Hilbert Spaces (RKHSs) and general Hilbert spaces. We         present a general form of the stochastic gradient method to         minimize a quadratic potential function by an independent         identically distributed (i.i.d.) sample sequence, and show a         probabilistic upper bound for its convergence.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>A. Caponnetto1  | E. De Vito2 </authors><title>Optimal Rates for the Regularized Least-Squares Algorithm      </title><content>We develop a theoretical analysis of the performance of the regularized least-square algorithm on a reproducing kernel Hilbert         space in the supervised learning setting. The presented results hold in the general framework of vector-valued functions;         therefore they can be applied to multitask problems. In particular, we observe that the concept of effective dimension plays         a central role in the definition of a criterion for the choice of the regularization parameter as a function of the number         of samples. Moreover, a complete minimax analysis of the problem is described, showing that the convergence rates obtained         by regularized least-squares estimators are indeed optimal over a suitable class of priors defined by the considered kernel.         Finally, we give an improved lower rate result describing worst asymptotic behavior on individual probability measures rather         than over classes of priors.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Rob Stevenson1 </authors><title>Optimality of a Standard Adaptive Finite Element Method      </title><content>In this paper an adaptive finite element method is constructed for solving elliptic equations that has optimal computational         complexity. Whenever, for some s &amp;gt; 0, the solution can be approximated within a tolerance &amp;#949; &amp;gt; 0 in energy norm by a continuous         piecewise linear function on some partition with O(&amp;#949;-1/s) triangles, and one knows how to approximate the right-hand side in the dual norm with the same rate with piecewise constants,         then the adaptive method produces approximations that converge with this rate, taking a number of operations that is of the         order of the number of triangles in the output partition. The method is similar in spirit to that from [SINUM, 38 (2000), pp. 466-488] by Morin, Nochetto, and Siebert, and so in particular it does not rely on a recurrent coarsening of the partitions. Although         the Poisson equation in two dimensions with piecewise linear approximation is considered, the results generalize in several         respects.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Katsiaryna Krupchyk1 | Werner M. Seiler2  | Jukka Tuomela1 </authors><title>Overdetermined Elliptic Systems      </title><content>We consider linear overdetermined systems of partial differential equations.         We show that the introduction of weights classically used for the definition         of ellipticity is not necessary, as any system that is elliptic with respect         to some weights becomes elliptic without weights during its completion to         involution.  Furthermore, it turns out that there are systems which are not         elliptic for any choice of weights but whose involutive form is nevertheless         elliptic.  We also show that reducing the given system to lower order or to         an equivalent system with only one unknown function preserves ellipticity.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>G.W. Wasilkowski1  | H. Wozniakowski2 </authors><title>Polynomial-Time Algorithms for Multivariate Linear Problems with Finite-Order Weights: Worst Case Setting      </title><content>We consider approximation of linear multivariate problems defined over         weighted tensor product Hilbert spaces with finite-order weights. This means we         consider functions of d variables that can be represented as sums of functions of at         most q* variables. Here, q* is fixed (and presumably small) and d may be arbitrarily         large. For the univariate problem, d = 1, we assume we know algorithms A1,&amp;#949; that         use O(&amp;#949;&amp;#8722;p) function or linear functional evaluations to achieve an error &amp;#949; in the         worst case setting. Based on these algorithms A1,&amp;#949;, we provide a construction of polynomial-time algorithms Ad,&amp;#949; for the general d-variate problem with the number of evaluations bounded roughly by &amp;#949;&amp;#8722;pdq* to achieve an error &amp;#949; in the worst case setting.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Emmanuel J. C|es1  | Justin Romberg1 </authors><title>Quantitative Robust Uncertainty Principles and  Optimally Sparse Decompositions      </title><content>In this paper we develop a robust uncertainty principle for         finite signals in                    which states that, for nearly all choices                            such that                                                                                                                                        </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Serkan Hosten1 | Amit Khetan2  | Bernd Sturmfels3 </authors><title>Solving the Likelihood Equations      </title><content>Given a model in algebraic statistics and data, the likelihood function         is a rational function on a projective variety. Algebraic algorithms are presented for         computing all critical points of this function, with the aim of identifying the local         maxima in the probability simplex. Applications include models specified by rank         conditions on matrices and the Jukes&amp;#8211;Cantor models of phylogenetics. The maximum likelihood degree of a generic complete intersection         is also determined.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>I.G. Lisle1  | G.J. Reid2 </authors><title>Symmetry Classification Using  Noncommutative Invariant Differential Operators      </title><content>Given a class F of differential equations, the symmetry classification problem is to determine for each member f &amp;#8712; F the structure         of its Lie symmetry group Gf or, equivalently, of its Lie symmetry algebra. The components of the symmetry vector fields of the Lie algebra are solutions         of an associated overdetermined "defining system" of differential equations. The usual computer classification method which         applies a sequence of total derivative operators and eliminations to this associated system  often fails on problems of interest         due to the excessive size of expressions generated in intermediate computations.  We provide an alternative classification         method which exploits the knowledge of an equivalence group G preserving the class. A noncommutative differential elimination         procedure due to Lemaire, Reid, and Zhang, where each step of the procedure is invariant under G, can be applied and an existence         and uniqueness theorem for the output used to classify the structure of symmetry groups for each f &amp;#8712; F. The method is applied         to a class of nonlinear diffusion convection equations vx = u, vt = B(u) ux - K(u) which is invariant under a large but easily determined equivalence group G. In this example the complexity of the         calculations is much reduced by the use of G-invariant differential operators.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Peter Burgisser1  | Martin Lotz2 </authors><title>The Complexity of Computing the Hilbert Polynomial of Smooth Equidimensional Complex Projective Varieties      </title><content>We continue the study of counting complexity begun in [13], [14], [15] by proving upper and lower bounds on the complexity         of computing the Hilbert polynomial of a homogeneous ideal. We show that the problem of computing the Hilbert polynomial of         a smooth equidimensional complex projective variety can be reduced in polynomial time to the problem of counting the number         of complex common zeros of a finite set of multivariate polynomials. The reduction is based on a new formula for the coefficients         of the Hilbert polynomial of a smooth variety. Moreover, we prove that the more general problem of computing the Hilbert polynomial         of a homogeneous ideal is polynomial space hard. This implies polynomial space lower bounds for both the problems of computing         the rank and the Euler characteristic of cohomology groups of coherent sheaves on projective space, improving the #P-lower         bound in Bach [1].      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Daniel Wilczak1 </authors><title>The Existence of Shilnikov Homoclinic Orbits in the Michelson System: A Computer Assisted Proof      </title><content>In this paper we present a new topological tool which allows us to prove the existence of Shilnikov homoclinic or heteroclinic         solutions. We present an application of this method to the Michelson system                                                                                                                                        </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>A. Murua1 </authors><title>The Hopf Algebra of Rooted Trees, Free Lie Algebras, and Lie Series      </title><content>We present an approach that allows performing computations         related to the Baker-Campbell-Haussdorff (BCH) formula and its         generalizations in an arbitrary Hall basis, using labeled rooted         trees. In particular, we provide explicit formulas (given in         terms of the structure of certain labeled rooted trees) of the         continuous BCH formula.  We develop a rewriting algorithm (based         on labeled rooted trees) in the dual Poincare-Birkhoff-Witt         (PBW) basis associated to an arbitrary Hall set, that allows         handling Lie series, exponentials of Lie series, and related         series written in the PBW basis.  At the end of the paper we show         that our approach is actually based on an explicit description of an         epimorphism &amp;#957; of Hopf algebras from the commutative Hopf         algebra of labeled rooted trees to the shuffle Hopf algebra and         its kernel ker &amp;#957;.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>J. Maurice Rojas1 </authors><title>Book Review S. Basu, R. Pollack, and M.-F. Roy: Algorithms in Real Algebraic Geometry         Algorithms and Computation in Mathematics Series (A.M.;Cohen, H.;Cohen, D.;Eisenbud, M.F.;Singer, B.;Sturmfels, eds.), vol.;10            (2nd ed.), Springer, 2006, ISBN 978-3-540-33098-1, 662 pages, $79.95         </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>S. J. Dilworth1 | E. Odell2 | T. Schlumprecht3  | A. ZsГЎk4 </authors><title>Coefficient Quantization in Banach Spaces      </title><content>         Let (e                     i            ) be a dictionary for a separable infinite-dimensional Banach space;X. We consider the problem of approximation by linear combinations of dictionary elements with quantized coefficients drawn         usually from a;&amp;#8216;finite alphabet&amp;#8217;. We investigate several approximation properties of this type and connect them to the Banach         space geometry of;X. The existence of a total minimal system with one of these properties, namely the coefficient quantization property, is shown to be equivalent to X containing;c         0. We also show that, for every &amp;#949;&amp;gt;0, the unit ball of every separable infinite-dimensional Banach space X contains a dictionary (x                     i            ) such that the additive group generated by (x                     i            ) is (3+&amp;#949;)&amp;#8722;1-separated and 1/3-dense in;X.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Michael Shub1 </authors><title>Complexity of Bezout&amp;#8217;s Theorem VI: Geodesics in the Condition (Number) Metric      </title><content>         We introduce a new complexity measure of a path of (problems, solutions) pairs in terms of the length of the path in the condition         metric which we define in the article. The measure gives an upper bound for the number of Newton steps sufficient to approximate         the path discretely starting from one end and thus produce an approximate zero for the endpoint. This motivates the study         of short paths or geodesics in the condition metric.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Carlos BeltrГЎn1  | Michael Shub1 </authors><title>Complexity of Bezout&amp;#8217;s Theorem VII: Distance Estimates in the Condition Metric      </title><content>         We study geometric properties of the solution variety for the problem of approximating solutions of systems of polynomial         equations. We prove that given the two pairs (f                     i            ,&amp;#950;                     i            ), i=1,2, there exist a short path joining them such that the complexity of following the path is bounded by the logarithm of         the condition number of the problems.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Saugata Basu1 | Richard Pollack2  | Marie-FranГ§oise Roy3 </authors><title>Computing the First Betti Number of a Semi-Algebraic Set      </title><content>         In this paper we describe a singly exponential algorithm for computing the first Betti number of a given semi-algebraic set.         Singly exponential algorithms for computing the zeroth Betti number, and the Euler&amp;#8211;PoincarГ© characteristic, were known before.         No singly exponential algorithm was known for computing any of the individual Betti numbers other than the zeroth one. As         a consequence we also obtain algorithms for computing semi-algebraic descriptions of the semi-algebraically connected components         of any given real algebraic or semi-algebraic set in singly exponential time, which improves on the complexity of the previously         published algorithms for this problem.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Saugata Basu1 </authors><title>Computing the Top Betti Numbers of Semialgebraic Sets Defined by Quadratic Inequalities in Polynomial Time      </title><content>For any &amp;#8467;&amp;gt;0, we present an algorithm which takes as input a semi-algebraic set, S, defined by P         1&amp;#8804;0,&amp;#8230;,P                     s            &amp;#8804;0, where each P                     i            &amp;#8712;R[X         1,&amp;#8230;,X                     k            ] has degree&amp;#8804;2, and computes the top &amp;#8467; Betti numbers of S, b                     k&amp;#8722;1(S),&amp;#8230;,b                     k&amp;#8722;&amp;#8467;            (S), in polynomial time. The complexity of the algorithm, stated more precisely, is                   . For fixed &amp;#8467;, the complexity of the algorithm can be expressed as                   , which is polynomial in the input parameters s and;k. To our knowledge this is the first polynomial time algorithm for computing nontrivial topological invariants of semialgebraic         sets in R            k             defined by polynomial inequalities, where the number of inequalities is not fixed and the polynomials are allowed to have         degree greater than one. For fixed s, we obtain, by letting &amp;#8467;=k, an algorithm for computing all the Betti numbers of S whose complexity is                   .      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>C. J. Cotter1  | D. D. Holm2 </authors><title>Continuous and Discrete Clebsch Variational Principles      </title><content>         The Clebsch method provides a unifying approach for deriving variational principles for continuous and discrete dynamical         systems where elements of a vector space are used to control dynamics on the cotangent bundle of a Lie group via a velocity         map. This paper proves a reduction theorem which states that the canonical variables on the Lie group can be eliminated, if         and only if the velocity map is a Lie algebra action, thereby producing the Euler&amp;#8211;PoincarГ© (EP) equation for the vector space         variables. In this case, the map from the canonical variables on the Lie group to the vector space is the standard momentum         map defined using the diamond operator. We apply the Clebsch method in examples of the rotating rigid body and the incompressible         Euler equations. Along the way, we explain how singular solutions of the EP equation for the diffeomorphism group (EPDiff)         arise as momentum maps in the Clebsch approach. In the case of finite-dimensional Lie groups, the Clebsch variational principle         is discretized to produce a variational integrator for the dynamical system. We obtain a discrete map from which the variables         on the cotangent bundle of a Lie group may be eliminated to produce a discrete EP equation for elements of the vector space.         We give an integrator for the rotating rigid body as an example. We also briefly discuss how to discretize infinite-dimensional         Clebsch systems, so as to produce conservative numerical methods for fluid dynamics.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Per Christian Moan1 | Jitse Niesen2| 3 </authors><title>Convergence of the Magnus Series      </title><content>         The Magnus series is an infinite series which arises in the study of linear ordinary differential equations. If the series         converges, then the matrix exponential of the sum equals the fundamental solution of the differential equation. The question         considered in this paper is: When does the series converge? The main result establishes a sufficient condition for convergence,         which improves on several earlier results.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Elizabeth L. Mansfield1  | Peter E. Hydon2 </authors><title>Difference Forms      </title><content>         Currently, there is much interest in the development of geometric integrators, which retain analogues of geometric properties         of an approximated system. This paper provides a means of ensuring that finite difference schemes accurately mirror global properties of approximated systems. To this end, we introduce a cohomology theory for lattice varieties, on which finite         difference schemes and other difference equations are defined. We do not assume that there is any continuous space, or that         a scheme or difference equation has a continuum limit. This distinguishes our approach from theories of &amp;#8220;discrete differential         forms&amp;#8221; built on simplicial approximations and Whitney forms, and from cohomology theories built on cubical complexes. Indeed,         whereas cochains on cubical complexes can be mapped injectively to our difference forms, a bijection may not exist. Thus our         approach generalizes what can be achieved with cubical cohomology. The fundamental property that we use to prove our results         is the natural ordering on the integers. We show that our cohomology can be calculated from a good cover, just as de Rham         cohomology can. We postulate that the dimension of solution space of a globally defined linear recurrence relation equals         the analogue of the Euler characteristic for the lattice variety. Most of our exposition deals with forward differences, but         little modification is needed to treat other finite difference schemes, including Gauss-Legendre and Preissmann schemes.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Emmanuel J. C|es1  | Justin Romberg1 </authors><title>Errata for Quantitative Robust Uncertainty Principles and Optimally Sparse Decompositions      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Andrew J. Sommese1  | Charles W. Wampler2 </authors><title>Exceptional Sets and Fiber Products      </title><content>Exceptional sets where fibers have dimensions higher than the generic fiber dimension are of interest in mathematics and in         application areas, such as the theory of overconstrained mechanisms.We show that fiber products promote such sets to become         irreducible components, whereupon they can be found using techniques from numerical algebraic geometry for computing the irreducible         decomposition. However, such a decomposition may contain components other than the exceptional loci we seek. We show that         each irreducible component of the exceptional loci gives rise to a main component in a fiber product of sufficiently high         order, and we give procedures for identifying these components. The methods are illustrated by finding the rulings of a general         quadricin C3.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Peter BГјrgisser1  | Felipe Cucker2 </authors><title>Exotic Quantifiers, Complexity Classes, and Complete Problems      </title><content>         We define new complexity classes in the Blum&amp;#8211;Shub&amp;#8211;Smale theory of computation over the reals, in the spirit of the polynomial         hierarchy, with the help of infinitesimal and generic quantifiers. Basic topological properties of semialgebraic sets like         boundedness, closedness, compactness, as well as the continuity of semialgebraic functions are shown to be complete in these         new classes. All attempts to classify the complexity of these problems in terms of the previously studied complexity classes         have failed. We also obtain completeness results in the Turing model for the corresponding discrete problems. In this setting,         it turns out that infinitesimal and generic quantifiers can be eliminated, so that the relevant complexity classes can be         described in terms of the usual quantifiers only.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>R. I. McLachlan1 | H. Z. Munthe-Kaas3 | G. R. W. Quispel2  | A. Zanna3 </authors><title>Explicit Volume-Preserving Splitting Methods for Linear and Quadratic Divergence-Free Vector Fields      </title><content>         We present new explicit volume-preserving methods based on splitting for polynomial divergence-free vector fields. The methods         can be divided in two classes: methods that distinguish between the diagonal part and the off-diagonal part and methods that         do not. For the methods in the first class it is possible to combine different treatments of the diagonal and off-diagonal         parts, giving rise to a number of possible combinations.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>I. Binder1 | M. Braverman2  | M. Yampolsky2 </authors><title>Filled Julia Sets with Empty Interior Are Computable      </title><content>We show that if a polynomial filled Julia set has empty interior, then it is computable.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>M.E. Fels1 </authors><title>Integrating Scalar Ordinary Differential Equations with Symmetry Revisited      </title><content>The process of integrating an nth-order scalar ordinary differential equation with symmetry is revisited in terms of Pfaffian         systems. This formulation immediately provides a completely algebraic method to determine the initial conditions and the corresponding         solutions which are invariant under a one parameter subgroup of a symmetry group. To determine the noninvariant solutions         the problem splits into three cases. If the dimension of the symmetry groups is less than the order of the equation, then         there exists an open dense set of initial conditions whose corresponding solutions can be found by integrating a quotient         Pfaffian system on a quotient space, and integrating an equation of fundamental Lie type associated with the symmetry group.         If the dimension of the symmetry group is equal to the order of the equation, then there exists an open dense set of initial         conditions whose corresponding solutions are obtained either by solving an equation of fundamental Lie type associated with         the symmetry group, or the solutions are invariant under a one-parameter subgroup. If the dimension of the symmetry group         is greater than the order of the equation, then there exists an open dense set of initial conditions where the solutions can         either be determined by solving an equation of fundamental Lie type for a solvable Lie group, or are invariant. In each case         the initial conditions, the quotient Pfaffian system, and the equation of Lie type are all determined algebraically. Examples         of scalar ordinary differential equations and a Pfaffian system are given.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Nira Dyn1| Armin Iske2  | Holger Wendl|3</authors><title>Meshfree Thinning of 3D;Point Clouds      </title><content>         An efficient data reduction scheme for the simplification of a surface given by a large set X of 3D;point-samples is proposed. The data reduction relies on a recursive point removal algorithm, termed thinning, which         outputs a data hierarchy of point-samples for multiresolution surface approximation. The thinning algorithm works with a point         removal criterion, which measures the significances of the points in their local neighbourhoods, and which removes a least         significant point at each step. For any point;x in the current point set Y&amp;#8834;X, its significance reflects the approximation quality of a local surface reconstructed from neighbouring points in;Y. The local surface reconstruction is done over an estimated tangent plane at x by using radial basis functions. The approximation quality of the surface reconstruction around x is measured by using its maximal deviation from the given point-samples X in a local neighbourhood of x. The resulting thinning algorithm is meshfree, i.e., its performance is solely based upon the geometry of the input 3D;surface         point-samples, and so it does not require any further topological information, such as point connectivities. Computational         details of the thinning algorithm and the required data structures for efficient implementation are explained and its complexity         is discussed. Two examples are presented for illustration.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Daqing Wan1 </authors><title>Modular Counting of Rational Points over Finite Fields      </title><content>Let Fq be the finite field of q elements, where q = ph. Let f(x) be a polynomial over Fq in n variables with m nonzero terms. Let N(f) denote the number of solutions of f(x) = 0 with coordinates in  Fq. In this paper we give a deterministic algorithm which computes the reduction of N(f) modulo pb in O(n(8m)p(h+b)p) bit operations. This is singly exponential in each of the parameters {h, b, p}, answering affirmatively an open problem         proposed by Gopalan, Guruswami, and Lipton.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Carlos Beltran1  | Luis Miguel Pardo1 </authors><title>On Smale's 17th Problem: A Probabilistic Positive Solution      </title><content>Smale's 17th Problem asks &amp;#8220;Can a zero of n complex polynomial equations in n unknowns be found approximately, on the average         [for a suitable probability measure on the space of inputs], in polynomial time with a uniform algorithm?&amp;#8221; We present a uniform         probabilistic algorithm for this problem and prove that its complexity is polynomial. We thus obtain a partial positive solution         to Smale's 17th Problem.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>H.Z. Munthe-Kaas1  | W.M. Wright2 </authors><title>On the Hopf Algebraic Structure of Lie Group Integrators      </title><content>A commutative but not cocommutative graded Hopf algebra HN, based on ordered (planar) rooted trees, is studied. This Hopf algebra is a generalization of the Hopf algebraic structure         of unordered rooted trees HC, developed by Butcher in his study of Runge-Kutta methods and later rediscovered by Connes and Moscovici in the context of         noncommutative geometry and by Kreimer where it is used to describe renormalization in quantum field theory. It is shown that         HN is naturally obtained from a universal object in a category of noncommutative derivations and, in particular, it forms a         foundation for the study of numerical integrators based on noncommutative Lie group actions on a manifold.  Recursive and         nonrecursive definitions of the coproduct and the antipode are derived. The relationship between HN and four other Hopf algebras is discussed.  The dual of HN is a Hopf algebra of Grossman and Larson based on ordered rooted trees. The Hopf algebra HC of Butcher, Connes, and Kreimer is identified as a proper Hopf subalgebra of HN using the image of a tree symmetrization operator. The Hopf algebraic structure of the shuffle algebra HSh is obtained from HN by a quotient construction. The Hopf algebra HP of ordered trees by Foissy differs from HN in the definition of the product  (noncommutative concatenation for HP and shuffle for HN) and  the definitions of the coproduct and the antipode, however, these are related through the tree symmetrization operator.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Sergio Blanes1 | Fern|o Casas2  | Ander Murua3 </authors><title>On the Linear Stability of Splitting Methods      </title><content>         A comprehensive linear stability analysis of splitting methods is carried out by means of a 2Г—2 matrix K(x) with polynomial entries (the stability matrix) and the stability polynomial p(x) (the trace of K(x) divided by two). An algorithm is provided for determining the coefficients of all possible time-reversible splitting schemes         for a prescribed stability polynomial. It is shown that p(x) carries essentially all the information needed to construct processed splitting methods for numerically approximating the         evolution of linear systems. By conveniently selecting the stability polynomial, new integrators with processing for linear         equations are built which are orders of magnitude more efficient than other algorithms previously available.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Yiming Ying1  | Massimiliano Pontil1 </authors><title>Online Gradient Descent Learning Algorithms      </title><content>This paper considers the least-square online gradient descent algorithm in a reproducing kernel Hilbert space (RKHS) without         an explicit regularization term. We present a novel capacity independent approach to derive error bounds and convergence results         for this algorithm. The essential element in our analysis is the interplay between the generalization error and a weighted         cumulative error which we define in the paper. We show that, although the algorithm does not involve an explicit RKHS regularization         term, choosing the step sizes appropriately can yield competitive error rates with those in the literature.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Hendrik Hubrechts1 </authors><title>Point Counting in Families of Hyperelliptic Curves      </title><content>         Let E         &amp;#915; be a family of hyperelliptic curves defined by                   , where                    is defined over a small finite field of odd characteristic. Then with                    in an extension degree n field over this small field, we present a deterministic algorithm for computing the zeta function of the curve                    by using Dwork deformation in rigid cohomology. The time complexity of the algorithm is                    and it needs                    bits of memory. A slight adaptation requires only                    space, but costs time                   . An implementation of this last result turns out to be quite efficient for n big enough.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>G. W. Wasilkowski1  | H. Wo&amp;#378 niakowski2| 3 </authors><title>Polynomial-Time Algorithms for Multivariate Linear Problems with Finite-Order Weights: Average Case Setting      </title><content>         We study multivariate linear problems in the average case setting with respect to a;zero-mean Gaussian measure whose covariance         kernel has a;finite-order weights structure. This means that the measure is concentrated on a;Banach space of d-variate functions that are sums of functions of at most q         * variables and the influence of each such term depends on a;given weight. Here q         * is fixed whereas d varies and can be arbitrarily large. For arbitrary finite-order weights, based on Smolyak&amp;#8217;s algorithm, we construct polynomial-time algorithms that use standard information. That is, algorithms that solve the d-variate problem to within &amp;#949; using of order                    function values modulo a;power of ln&amp;#8201;&amp;#949;         &amp;#8722;1. Here p is the exponent which measures the difficulty of the univariate (d=1) problem, and the power of ln&amp;#8201;&amp;#949;         &amp;#8722;1 is independent of;d. We also present a;necessary and sufficient condition on finite-order weights for which we obtain strongly polynomial-time algorithms, i.e., when the number of function values is independent of d and polynomial in &amp;#949;         &amp;#8722;1. The exponent of &amp;#949;         &amp;#8722;1 may be, however, larger than p. We illustrate the results by two multivariate problems: integration and function approximation. For the univariate case         we assume the r-folded Wiener measure. Then p=1/(r+1) for integration and                    for approximation.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Y. Nesterov1  | A. Nemirovski2 </authors><title>Primal Central Paths and Riemannian Distances for Convex Sets      </title><content>         In this paper, we study the Riemannian length of the primal central path in a convex set computed with respect to the local         metric defined by a self-concordant function. Despite some negative examples, in many important situations, the length of         this path is quite close to the length of a geodesic curve. We show that in the case of a bounded convex set endowed with         a &amp;#957;-self-concordant barrier, the length of the central path is within a factor O(&amp;#957;         1/4) of the length of the shortest geodesic curve.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Richard G. Baraniuk1  | Michael B. Wakin2 </authors><title>Random Projections of Smooth Manifolds      </title><content>         We propose a new approach for nonadaptive dimensionality reduction of manifold-modeled data, demonstrating that a small number of random linear projections can preserve key information about a manifold-modeled signal. We center our analysis on the effect of a random linear projection         operator &amp;#934;:&amp;#8477;            N            &amp;#8594;&amp;#8477;            M            , M&amp;lt;N, on a smooth well-conditioned K-dimensional submanifold &amp;#8499;&amp;#8834;&amp;#8477;            N            . As our main theoretical contribution, we establish a sufficient number M of random projections to guarantee that, with high probability, all pairwise Euclidean and geodesic distances between points         on &amp;#8499; are well preserved under the mapping &amp;#934;.                                             Our results bear strong resemblance to the emerging theory of Compressed Sensing (CS), in which sparse signals can be recovered               from small numbers of random linear measurements. As in CS, the random measurements we propose can be used to recover the               original data in &amp;#8477;                  N                  . Moreover, like the fundamental bound in CS, our requisite M is linear in the &amp;#8220;information level&amp;#8221; K and logarithmic in the ambient dimension N; we also identify a logarithmic dependence on the volume and conditioning of the manifold. In addition to recovering faithful               approximations to manifold-modeled signals, however, the random projections we propose can also be used to discern key properties               about the manifold. We discuss connections and contrasts with existing techniques in manifold learning, a setting where dimensionality               reducing mappings are typically nonlinear and constructed adaptively from a set of sampled training data.                           </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Stefan Kunis1  | Holger Rauhut2 </authors><title>Random Sampling of Sparse Trigonometric Polynomials, II.;Orthogonal;Matching Pursuit versus;Basis Pursuit      </title><content>         We investigate the problem of reconstructing sparse multivariate trigonometric polynomials from few randomly taken samples         by Basis Pursuit and greedy algorithms such as Orthogonal Matching Pursuit (OMP) and Thresholding. While recovery by Basis         Pursuit has recently been studied by several authors, we provide theoretical results on the success probability of reconstruction         via Thresholding and OMP for both a continuous and a discrete probability model for the sampling points. We present numerical         experiments, which indicate that usually Basis Pursuit is significantly slower than greedy algorithms, while the recovery         rates are very similar.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>A. Caponnetto1| 2  | S. Smale3 </authors><title>Risk Bounds for Random Regression Graphs      </title><content>We  consider the regression problem and describe an algorithm approximating the regression function by estimators piecewise         constant on the elements of an adaptive partition. The partitions are iteratively constructed by suitable random merges and         splits, using cuts of arbitrary geometry. We give a risk bound under the assumption that a "weak learning hypothesis" holds,         and characterize this hypothesis in terms of a suitable RKHS. Two examples illustrate the general results in two particularly         interesting cases.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Jean Bernard Lasserre1| 2 | Monique Laurent3  | Philipp Rostalski4 </authors><title>Semidefinite Characterization and Computation of Zero-Dimensional Real Radical Ideals      </title><content>         For an ideal I&amp;#8838;&amp;#8477;[x] given by a set of generators, a new semidefinite characterization of its real radical I(V         &amp;#8477;(I)) is presented, provided it is zero-dimensional (even if I is not). Moreover, we propose an algorithm using numerical linear algebra and semidefinite optimization techniques, to compute         all (finitely many) points of the real variety V         &amp;#8477;(I) as well as a set of generators of the real radical ideal. The latter is obtained in the form of a border or GrГ¶bner basis.         The algorithm is based on moment relaxations and, in contrast to other existing methods, it exploits the real algebraic nature         of the problem right from the beginning and avoids the computation of complex components.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Evelyne Hubert1  | Irina A. Kogan2 </authors><title>Smooth and Algebraic  Invariants of a Group Action: Local and Global Constructions      </title><content>We provide an algebraic formulation of the moving frame method for constructing local smooth invariants on a manifold under         an action of a Lie group. This formulation gives rise to algorithms for constructing rational and replacement invariants.         The latter are algebraic over the field of rational invariants and play a role analogous to Cartan's normalized invariants         in the smooth theory. The algebraic algorithms can be used for computing fundamental sets of differential invariants.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>E. Hairer1  | C. Lubich2 </authors><title>Spectral Semi-discretisations of Weakly Non-linear Wave Equations over Long Times      </title><content>         The long-time behaviour of spectral semi-discretisations of weakly non-linear wave equations is analysed. It is shown that         the harmonic actions are approximately conserved for the semi-discretised system as well. This permits to prove that the energy         of the wave equation along the interpolated semi-discrete solution remains well conserved over long times and close to the         Hamiltonian of the semi-discrete equation. Although the momentum is no longer an exact invariant of the semi-discretisation,         it is shown to be approximately conserved. All these results are obtained with the technique of modulated Fourier expansions.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Elena Celledoni1| David Cohen1 | Brynjulf Owren1 </authors><title>Symmetric Exponential Integrators with an Application to the Cubic SchrГ¶dinger Equation      </title><content>         In this article, we derive and study symmetric exponential integrators. Numerical experiments are performed for the cubic         SchrГ¶dinger equation and comparisons with classical exponential integrators and other geometric methods are also given. Some         of the proposed methods preserve the L         2-norm and/or the energy of the system.               </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Alan Edelman1  | Brian D. Sutton1| 2 </authors><title>The Beta-Jacobi Matrix Model, the CS Decomposition, and Generalized Singular Value Problems      </title><content>We provide a solution to the &amp;#946;-Jacobi matrix model problem posed by Dumitriu and the first author. The random matrix distribution         introduced here, called a matrix model, is related to the model of Killip and Nenciu, but the development is quite different.         We start by introducing a new matrix decomposition and an algorithm for computing this decomposition. Then we run the algorithm         on a Haar-distributed random matrix to produce the &amp;#946;-Jacobi matrix model. The Jacobi ensemble on                   , parametrized by &amp;#946; &amp;gt; 0, a &amp;gt; -1,and b &amp;gt; -1, is the probability distribution whose density is proportional to                   . The matrix model introduced in this paper is a probability distribution on structured orthogonal matrices. If J is a random         matrix drawnfrom this distribution, then a CS decomposition can be taken,                                                                  </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>N. Raj Rao1  | Alan Edelman2 </authors><title>The Polynomial Method for Random Matrices      </title><content>         We define a class of &amp;#8220;algebraic&amp;#8221; random matrices. These are random matrices for which the Stieltjes transform of the limiting         eigenvalue distribution function is algebraic, i.e., it satisfies a (bivariate) polynomial equation. The Wigner and Wishart         matrices whose limiting eigenvalue distributions are given by the semicircle law and the Mar&amp;#269;enko&amp;#8211;Pastur law are special cases.                                             Algebraicity of a random matrix sequence is shown to act as a certificate of the computability of the limiting eigenvalue               density function. The limiting moments of algebraic random matrix sequences, when they exist, are shown to satisfy a finite               depth linear recursion so that they may often be efficiently enumerated in closed form.                           </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Chek Beng Chua1 </authors><title>The Primal-Dual Second-Order Cone Approximations Algorithm for Symmetric Cone Programming      </title><content>Given any open convex cone K, a logarithmically homogeneous, self-concordant barrier for K, and any positive real number r         &amp;lt; 1, we associate, with each direction                   , a second-order cone                    containing K. We show that K is the interior of the intersection of the second-order cones                   , as x ranges over all directions in K. Using these second-order cones as approximations to cones of symmetric, positive definite         matrices, we develop a new polynomial-time primal-dual interior-point algorithm for semidefinite programming. The algorithm         is extended to symmetric cone programming via the relation between symmetric cones and Euclidean Jordan algebras.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>P.-A. Absil1 | C.G. Baker2  | K.A. Gallivan2 </authors><title>Trust-Region Methods on Riemannian Manifolds      </title><content>A general scheme for trust-region methods on Riemannian manifolds is proposed and analyzed. Among the various approaches available         to (approximately) solve the trust-region subproblems, particular attention is paid to the truncated conjugate-gradient technique.         The method is illustrated on problems from numerical linear algebra.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors> Ronald DeVore1|  Guergana Petrova2 |  Vladimir Temlyakov3</authors><title>Best Basis Selection for Approximation in L                     p                            </title><content> We study the approximation of a function class F in L                     p              by choosing first a basis B  and then using n -term approximation with the elements of B . Into the competition for best bases we enter all greedy (i.e., democratic and unconditional [20]) bases for L                     p             . We show that if the function class F is well-oriented with respect to a particular basis B  then, in a certain sense, this basis is the best choice for this type of approximation. Our results extend the recent results         of Donoho [9] from L                     2              to L                     p             , p\neq 2 .               </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors> Buhmann1|  Davydov2 |  Goodman3</authors><title>Cubic Spline Prewavelets on the Four-Directional Mesh                </title><content>                           Dedicated to Professor M. J. D. Powell on the occasion                           </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors> DeVore1|  Iserles1 |  Todd1</authors><title>Editorial                </title><content> No abstract.               </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors> Nira Dyn1|  David Levin2 |  Ariel Luzzatto3</authors><title>Exponentials Reproducing Subdivision Schemes                </title><content> This paper is concerned with a family of nonstationary, interpolatory subdivision schemes that have the capability of reproducing         functions in a finite-dimensional subspace of exponential polynomials. We give conditions for the existence and uniqueness         of such schemes, and analyze their convergence and smoothness. It is shown that the refinement rules of an even-order exponentials         reproducing scheme converge to the Dubuc&amp;#8212;Deslauriers interpolatory scheme of the same order, and that both schemes have the         same smoothness. Unlike the stationary case, the application of a nonstationary scheme requires the computation of a different         rule for each refinement level. We show that the rules of an exponentials reproducing scheme can be efficiently derived by         means of an auxiliary orthogonal scheme , using only linear operations. The orthogonal schemes are also very useful tools in fitting an appropriate space of exponential         polynomials to a given data sequence.               </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors> Tisseur1|  Dedieu2|  Kim3 |  Shub4</authors><title>Implicit Gamma Theorems (I): Pseudoroots and Pseudospectra                </title><content>                  Abstract.  Let g  : E &amp;#8594;  F be an analytic function between two Hilbert spaces E and F. We study the set g(B(x, &amp;#949;)) &amp;#8834;  E, the image under g  of the closed ball about x&amp;#8712;  E with radius &amp;#949; . When g(x)  expresses the solution of an equation depending on x , then the elements of g(B(x,&amp;#949; ))  are &amp;#949; -pseudosolutions. Our aim is to investigate the size of the set g(B(x,&amp;#949; )) . We derive upper and lower bounds of the following form:                      g(x) + Dg (x) ( B(0, c                                 1                   &amp;#949; N))                                                                                                                         g(B(x,&amp;#949; ))                                                                                                                         g(x) +Dg (x) ( B(0, c                                 2                   &amp;#949; ) ),            </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors> Temlyakov1</authors><title>Nonlinear Methods of Approximation                </title><content>                  Abstract.  Our main interest in this paper is nonlinear approximation. The basic idea behind nonlinear approximation is that the elements         used in the approximation do not come from a fixed linear space but are allowed to depend on the function being approximated.         While the scope of this paper is mostly theoretical, we should note that this form of approximation appears in many numerical         applications such as adaptive PDE solvers, compression of images and signals, statistical classification, and so on. The standard         problem in this regard is the problem of m -term approximation where one fixes a basis and looks to approximate a target function by a linear combination of m  terms of the basis. When the basis is a wavelet basis or a basis of other waveforms, then this type of approximation is         the starting point for compression algorithms. We are interested in the quantitative aspects of this type of approximation.         Namely, we want to understand the properties (usually smoothness) of the function which govern its rate of approximation in         some given norm (or metric). We are also interested in stable algorithms for finding good or near best approximations using         m  terms. Some of our earlier work has introduced and analyzed such algorithms. More recently, there has emerged another more         complicated form of nonlinear approximation which we call highly nonlinear approximation. It takes many forms but has the         basic ingredient that a basis is replaced by a larger system of functions that is usually redundant. Some types of approximation         that fall into this general category are mathematical frames, adaptive pursuit (or greedy algorithms), and adaptive basis         selection. Redundancy on the one hand offers much promise for greater efficiency in terms of approximation rate, but on the         other hand gives rise to highly nontrivial theoretical and practical problems. With this motivation, our recent work and the         current activity focuses on nonlinear approximation both in the classical form of m -term approximation (where several important problems remain unsolved) and in the form of highly nonlinear approximation         where a theory is only now emerging.                </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors> Wolfgang Dahmen1|  Torben Klint2 |  Karsten Urban3</authors><title>On Fictitious Domain Formulations for Maxwell's Equations                </title><content> We consider fictitious domain-Lagrange multiplier formulations for variational problems in the space H(curl:         &amp;#937;{\bf)} derived from Maxwell's equations. Boundary conditions and the divergence constraint are imposed weakly by using Lagrange         multipliers. Both the time dependent and time harmonic formulations of the Maxwell's equations are considered, and we derive         well-posed formulations for both cases. The variational problem that arises can be discretized by functions that do not satisfy         an a-priori divergence constraint.                </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors> Parlett1</authors><title>Perturbation of Eigenpairs of Factored Symmetric Tridiagonal Matrices                </title><content> Suppose that an indefinite symmetric tridiagonal matrix permits triangular factorization T =  LDL            t             . We provide individual condition numbers for the eigenvalues and eigenvectors of T  when the parameters in L  and D  suffer small relative perturbations. When there is element growth in the factorization, then some pairs may be robust while         others are sensitive. A 4 Г— 4  example shows the limitations of standard multiplicative perturbation theory and the efficacy of our new condition numbers.               </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Warwick  Tucker1</authors><title>A Rigorous ODE Solver and Smale's 14th Problem      </title><content> We present an algorithm for computing rigorous solutions to a large class of ordinary differential equations. The main algorithm         is based on a partitioning process and the use of interval arithmetic with directed rounding. As an application, we prove         that the Lorenz equations support a strange attractor, as conjectured by Edward Lorenz in 1963. This conjecture was recently         listed by Steven Smale as one of several challenging problems for the twenty-first century. We also prove that the attractor         is robust, i.e., it persists under small perturbations of the coefficients in the underlying differential equations. Furthermore,         the flow of the equations admits a unique SRB measure, whose support coincides with the attractor. The proof is based on a         combination of normal form theory and rigorous computations.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Eitan  Tadmor1 | Jared  Tanner1</authors><title>Adaptive Mollifiers for High Resolution Recovery of Piecewise Smooth Data from its Spectral Information      </title><content> We discuss the reconstruction of piecewise smooth data from its (pseudo-) spectral information. Spectral projections enjoy         superior resolution provided the data is globally smooth, while the presence of jump discontinuities is responsible for spurious         O (1) Gibbs oscillations in the neighborhood of edges and an overall deterioration of the unacceptable first-order convergence         in rate. The purpose is to regain the superior accuracy in the piecewise smooth case, and this is achieved by mollification.                      Here we utilize a modified version of the two-parameter family of spectral mollifiers introduced by Gottlieb and Tadmor [GoTa85].               The ubiquitous one-parameter, finite-order mollifiers are based on dilation . In contrast, our mollifiers achieve their high resolution by an intricate process of high-order cancellation . To this end, we first implement a localization step using an edge detection procedure [GeTa00a, b]. The accurate recovery               of piecewise smooth data is then carried out in the direction of smoothness away from the edges, and adaptivity  is responsible for the high resolution. The resulting adaptive mollifier greatly accelerates the convergence rate, recovering               piecewise analytic data within exponential accuracy while removing the spurious oscillations that remained in [GoTa85]. Thus,               these adaptive mollifiers offer a robust, general-purpose ``black box'' procedure for accurate post-processing of piecewise               smooth data.            </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors> Cohen1|  Dahmen2 |  DeVore3</authors><title>Adaptive Wavelet Methods II&amp;#8212;Beyond the Elliptic Case                </title><content> This paper is concerned with the design and analysis of adaptive wavelet methods for systems of operator equations. Its main         accomplishment is to extend the range of applicability of the adaptive wavelet-based method developed in [17] for symmetric         positive definite problems to indefinite or unsymmetric systems of operator equations. This is accomplished by first introducing         techniques (such as the least squares formulation developed in [26]) that transform the original (continuous) problem into         an equivalent infinite system of equations which is now well-posed in the Euclidean metric. It is then shown how to utilize         adaptive techniques to solve the resulting infinite system of equations. This second step requires a significant modification         of the ideas from [17]. The main departure from [17] is to develop an iterative scheme that directly applies to the infinite-dimensional  problem rather than finite subproblems derived from the infinite problem. This rests on an adaptive application of the infinite-dimensional operator  to finite vectors representing elements from finite-dimensional trial spaces. It is shown that for a wide range of problems,         this new adaptive method performs with asymptotically optimal complexity, i.e., it recovers an approximate solution with desired         accuracy at a computational expense that stays proportional to the number of terms in a corresponding wavelet-best N -term approximation. An important advantage of this adaptive approach is that it automatically  stabilizes the numerical procedure so that, for instance, compatibility constraints on the choice of trial spaces, like         the LBB condition, no longer arise.               </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Dima Grigoriev1</authors><title>Approximation and Complexity II: Iterated Integration                </title><content> We introduce two classes of real analytic functions W \subset U  on an interval. Starting with rational functions to construct functions in W  we allow the application of three types of operations: addition, integration, and multiplication by a polynomial with rational         coefficients. In a similar way, to construct functions in U  we allow integration, addition, and multiplication of functions already constructed in U  and multiplication by rational numbers. Thus, U  is a subring of the ring of Pfaffian functions [7].                      Two lower bounds on the L                                 &amp;#8712;fty                   -norm are proved on a function f  from W  (or from U , respectively) in terms of the complexity of constructing f .                           </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors> Cucker1 |  Smale2</authors><title>Best Choices for Regularization Parameters in Learning Theory: On the Bias&amp;#8212;Variance Problem                </title><content>                  Abstract.  No abstract.               </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Piotr Zgliczynski1</authors><title>         C                     1             Lohner Algorithm               </title><content>                  Abstract.  We present a modification of the Lohner algorithm for the computation of rigorous bounds for solutions of ordinary differential         equations together with partial derivatives with respect to initial conditions. The modified algorithm requires essentially         the same computational effort as the original one. We applied the algorithm to show the existence of several periodic orbits         for RГ¶ssler equations and the 14-dimensional Galerkin projection of the Kuramoto&amp;#8212;Sivashinsky partial differential equation.               </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors> Barvinok1</authors><title>Estimating L         &amp;#8734; Norms by L                     2k             Norms for Functions on Orbits               </title><content>                  Abstract.  Let G  be a compact group acting in a real vector space V . We obtain a number of inequalities relating the L         &amp;#8734;  norm of a matrix element of the representation of G  with its L                     2k              norm for a positive integer k . As an application, we obtain approximation algorithms to find the maximum absolute value of a given multivariate polynomial         over the unit sphere (in which case G  is the orthogonal group) and for the assignment problem of degree d , a hard problem of combinatorial optimization generalizing the quadratic assignment problem (in which case G  is the symmetric group).               </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors> Lewis1 |  Olver2</authors><title>Geometric Integration Algorithms on Homogeneous Manifolds                </title><content>                  Abstract.  Given an ordinary differential equation on a homogeneous manifold, one can construct a ``geometric integrator'' by determining         a compatible ordinary differential equation on the associated Lie group, using a Lie group integration scheme to construct         a discrete time approximation of the solution curves in the group, and then mapping the discrete trajectories onto the homogeneous         manifold using the group action. If the points of the manifold have continuous isotropy, a vector field on the manifold determines         a continuous family of vector fields on the group, typically with distinct discretizations. If sufficient isotropy is present,         an appropriate choice of vector field can yield improved capture of key features of the original system. In particular, if         the algebra of the group is ``full,'' then the order of accuracy of orbit capture (i.e., approximation of trajectories modulo         time reparametrization) within a specified family of integration schemes can be increased by an appropriate choice of isotropy         element. We illustrate the approach developed here with comparisons of several integration schemes for the reduced rigid body         equations on the sphere.               </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Arieh Iserles1</authors><title>On the Discretization of Double-Bracket Flows                </title><content> This paper extends the method of Magnus series to Lie-algebraic equations originating in double-bracket flows. We show that         the solution of the isospectral flow Y'=[[Y,N],Y] , Y(0)=Y                     0                     &amp;#8712;\Sym(n) , can be represented in the form Y(t)=e                     &amp;#937;(t)                      Y                     0                      e                     -&amp;#937;(t)             , where the Taylor expansion of &amp;#937;  can be constructed explicitly, term-by-term, identifying individual expansion terms with certain rooted trees with bicolor         leaves. This approach is extended to other Lie-algebraic equations that can be appropriately expressed in terms of a finite         ``alphabet.''                </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Markus  BlГ¤ser1| Peter  Kirrinnis2 | Daniel  Lauer2</authors><title>On the Multiplicative Complexity of the Inversion and Division of Hamiltonian Quaternions      </title><content> The multiplicative complexity of a finite set of rational functions is the number of essential multiplications and divisions         that are necessary and sufficient to compute these rational functions. We prove that the multiplicative complexity of inversion         in the division algebra \H  of Hamiltonian quaternions over the reals, that is, the multiplicative complexity of the coordinates of the inverse of a         generic element from \H , is exactly eight. Furthermore, we show that the multiplicative complexity of the left and right division of Hamiltonian         quaternions is at least eleven.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors> Nesterov1 |  Todd2</authors><title>On the Riemannian Geometry Defined by Self-Concordant Barriers and Interior-Point Methods                </title><content>                  Abstract.  We consider the Riemannian geometry defined on a convex set by the Hessian of a self-concordant barrier function, and its         associated geodesic curves. These provide guidance for the construction of efficient interior-point methods for optimizing         a linear function over the intersection of the set with an affine manifold. We show that algorithms that follow the primal&amp;#8212;dual         central path are in some sense close to optimal. The same is true for methods that follow the shifted primal&amp;#8212;dual central         path among certain infeasible-interior-point methods. We also compute the geodesics in several simple sets.               </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Michael H.  Freedman1</authors><title>Poly-Locality in Quantum Computing      </title><content> A polynomial depth quantum circuit affects, by definition, a poly-local unitary transformation of a tensor product state         space. It is a reasonable belief [Fe], [L], [FKW] that, at a fine scale, these are precisely the transformations which will be available from physics to solve computational         problems. The poly-locality of a discrete Fourier transform on cyclic groups is at the heart of Shor's factoring algorithm.         We describe a class of poly-local transformations, which include the discrete orthogonal wavelet transforms, in the hope that         these may be helpful in constructing new quantum algorithms. We also observe that even a rather mild violation of poly-locality         leads to a model without one-way functions, giving further evidence that poly-locality is an essential concept.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors> Lecerf1</authors><title>Quadratic Newton Iteration for Systems with Multiplicity                </title><content>             Newton's iterator is one of the most popular components of polynomial equation system solvers, either from the numeric or               symbolic point of view. This iterator usually handles smooth situations only (when the Jacobian matrix associated to the system               is invertible). This is often a restrictive factor. Generalizing Newton's iterator is still an open problem: How to design               an efficient iterator with a quadratic convergence even in degenerate cases? We propose an answer for an m -adic topology when the ideal m  can be chosen generic enough: compared to a smooth case we prove quadratic convergence with a small overhead that grows               with the square of the multiplicity of the root.                           </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Raphael A.  Hauser1 | Osman  GГјler2</authors><title>Self-Scaled Barrier Functions on Symmetric Cones and Their Classification      </title><content> Self-scaled barrier functions on self-scaled cones were axiomatically introduced by Nesterov and Todd in 1994 as a tool for         the construction of primal&amp;#8212;dual long-step interior point algorithms. This paper provides firm foundations for these objects         by exhibiting their symmetry properties, their close ties with the symmetry groups of their domains of definition, and subsequently         their decomposition into irreducible parts and their algebraic classification theory. In the first part we recall the characterization         of the family of self-scaled cones as the set of symmetric cones and develop a primal&amp;#8212;dual symmetric viewpoint on self-scaled         barriers, results that were first discovered by the second author. We then show in a short, simple proof that any pointed,         convex cone decomposes into a direct sum of irreducible components in a unique way, a result which can also be of independent         interest. We then proceed to showing that any self-scaled barrier function decomposes, in an essentially unique way, into         a direct sum of self-scaled barriers defined on the irreducible components of the underlying symmetric cone. Finally, we present         a complete algebraic classification of self-scaled barrier functions using the correspondence between symmetric cones and         Euclidean&amp;#8212;Jordan algebras.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>D. Castro1| J. L. MontaГ±a1| L. M. Pardo1 | J.   San MartГ­n1</authors><title>The Distribution of Condition Numbers of Rational Data of Bounded Bit Length      </title><content> We prove that rational data of bounded input length are uniformly distributed (in the classical sense of H. Weyl, in [42])         with respect to the probability distribution of condition numbers of numerical analysis. We deal both with condition numbers         of linear algebra and with condition numbers for systems of multivariate polynomial equations. For instance, we prove that         for a randomly chosen n\times n  rational matrix M  of bit length O(n                     4            log; n) + log; w , the condition number k(M)  satisfies k(M) &amp;#8804; w n                     5/2              with probability at least 1-2w                     -1             . Similar estimates are established for the condition number &amp;#956;_ norm of M. Shub and S. Smale when applied to systems of multivariate homogeneous polynomial equations of bounded input length.         Finally, we apply these techniques to estimate the probability distribution of the precision (number of bits of the denominator)         required to write approximate zeros of systems of multivariate polynomial equations of bounded input length.      </content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Facundo MГ©moli1  | Guillermo Sapiro2 </authors><title>A Theoretical and Computational Framework for Isometry Invariant Recognition of Point Cloud Data      </title><content>Point clouds are one of the most primitive and fundamental manifold         representations. Popular sources of point clouds are three-dimensional         shape acquisition devices such as laser range scanners. Another         important field where point clouds are found is in the representation         of high-dimensional manifolds by samples. With the increasing         popularity and very broad applications of this source         of data, it is natural and important to work directly with this         representation, without having to go through the intermediate and         sometimes impossible and distorting steps of surface reconstruction.         A geometric framework for comparing manifolds given by point clouds         is presented in this paper. The underlying theory is based on         Gromov-Hausdorff distances, leading to isometry invariant and         completely geometric comparisons. This theory is embedded in a          probabilistic setting as derived from random sampling of manifolds,         and then combined with results on matrices of pairwise geodesic distances         to lead to a computational implementation of the framework. The theoretical and         computational results presented here  are complemented with         experiments for real three-dimensional shapes.      </content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Sergio Amat1 | Rosa Donat2 | Jacques Li|rat3  | J. Carlos Trillo1 </authors><title>Analysis of a New Nonlinear Subdivision Scheme. Applications in Image Processing      </title><content>A nonlinear multiresolution scheme within Harten's framework is presented, based on a  new nonlinear, centered piecewise polynomial         interpolation technique. Analytical properties of the resulting subdivision scheme, such as convergence, smoothness, and stability,         are studied.  The stability and the compression properties of the associated multiresolution transform  are demonstrated on         several numerical experiments on images.      </content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Peter BГјrgisser1 | Felipe Cucker2  | Martin Lotz1 </authors><title>Counting Complexity Classes for Numeric Computations. III: Complex Projective Sets      </title><content>In [8] counting complexity classes #PR  and #PC in the Blum-Shub-Smale (BSS) setting of         computations over the real and complex numbers, respectively,         were introduced. One of the main results of [8] is that the problem         to compute the Euler characteristic of a semialgebraic set         is complete in the class FPR#PR.         In this paper, we prove that the corresponding result is true         over C, namely that the computation of the Euler characteristic         of an affine or projective complex variety is complete         in the class FPC#PC. We also obtain a corresponding         completeness result for the Turing model.      </content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Konstantin Mischaikow1 | Marian Mrozek2  | Pawel Pilarczyk3 </authors><title>Graph Approach to the Computation of the Homology of Continuous Maps</title><content>We introduce an efficient algorithm  to compute the homomorphisminduced in (relative) homology by a continous map.The algorithm is based on a cubical approximation of the mapand the theory of multivalued maps.A software implementation of the algorithms introduced in this paperis available at [27].</content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Alain Trouv&amp;eacute 1  | Laurent Younes2 </authors><title>Metamorphoses Through Lie Group Action</title><content>We formally analyze a computational problem which has importantapplications in image understanding and shape analysis. The problemcan be summarized as follows. Starting from a group action on a Riemannian manifold M, we  introduce a modification of the metric by partly expressing  displacements on M as an effect of the action of some  group  element. The study of   this new structure relates to evolutions on M under the combined  effect of the action and of residual displacements, called  metamorphoses. This can and has been applied to image processing  problems, providing in particular diffeomorphic matching algorithms  for pattern recognition.</content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>M. Giusti1 | G. Lecerf2 | B. Salvy3  | J.-C. Yakoubsohn4 </authors><title>On Location and Approximation of Clusters of Zeros of Analytic Functions      </title><content>At the beginning of the 1980s, M. Shub and S. Smale developed a         quantitative analysis of Newton's method for multivariate analytic         maps. In particular, their &amp;#945;-theory gives an effective         criterion that ensures safe convergence to a simple isolated zero.         This criterion requires only information concerning the map at the         initial point of the iteration. Generalizing this theory to multiple         zeros and clusters of zeros is still a challenging problem. In this         paper we focus on one complex variable function. We study general         criteria for detecting clusters and analyze the convergence of         Schroder's iteration to a cluster. In the case of a multiple root,         it is well known that this convergence is quadratic. In the case of a         cluster with positive diameter, the convergence is still quadratic         provided the iteration is stopped sufficiently early. We propose a         criterion for stopping this iteration at a distance from the cluster         which is of the order of its diameter.      </content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Jean-Pierre Dedieu1 | Gregorio Malajovich2  | Mike Shub3 </authors><title>On the Curvature of the Central Path of Linear Programming Theory</title><content>We prove a linear bound on the average total curvature of thecentral path of linear programming theory in terms of the numberof independent variables of the primal problem, and independent ofthe number of constraints.</content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>K. Meer1 </authors><title>Transparent Long Proofs: A First PCP Theorem for NPR</title><content>We introduce and study the notion of probabilistically checkable proofs (PCP) for real number algorithms. Our starting point         is the computational model of Blum, Shub, and         Smale (BSS) and the real analogue NPR of NP in that model. We define in a straightforward manner verifiers as well as complexity classes PCPR(r(n),q(n)) for the BSS model. Our main result is, to the best of our knowledge, the first PCP theorem for NPR. It states that each problem in NPR has transparent long proofs, i.e.,NPR \subseteq PCPR(poly,1),  where poly denotes the class of univariate polynomial functions. The techniques used extend ideas from  [12] for         self-testing and self-correcting certain functions over so-called rational domains to more general domains over the real numbers.         The latter arise from the particular NPR-complete problem for which we construct a verifier of the required form.      </content></document></documents>