<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><documents><document><year>1999</year><authors>Alex|er H. Sarris1 | Stavros Zografakis1</authors><title>A computable general equilibrium assessment of the impact of illegal immigration on the Greek economy      </title><content>Abstract.;; Recent years have witnessed a large inflow of illegal immigrants into Greece. Past surveys have examined the extent and nature         of this immigration, but have not analysed the impacts on the economy. This paper presents a theoretical and empirical analysis         of the impact of illegal immigration on the economy of the small open type, like that of Greece. The theoretical analysis         uses a small stylised model to show that there is no unequivocal case for illegal immigration to lead to declines in the real         wages of unskilled labour and increases in the real wages of skilled. Empirical analysis using a recently constructed applied         general equilibrium model for Greece, adapted to the purpose in hand, shows that the inflow of illegal immigrants has resulted         in declines of the real disposable incomes of two classes of households among the fifteen modelled, namely those headed by         an unskilled person, that are poor and middle income. All other households gain. The ones who lose, however, make up about         37% of the Greek population. The distributional effects are moderated, however, when rigidities in the labour market are simulated.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Thomas Lindh1 | Bo Malmberg1</authors><title>Age structure effects and growth in the OECD, 1950&amp;#8211;1990      </title><content>Abstract.;; Economic growth depends on human resources and human needs. The demographic age structure shapes both of these factors. We         study five-year data from the OECD countries 1950&amp;#8211;1990 in the framework of an age structure augmented neoclassical growth         model with gradual technical adjustment. The model performs well in both pooled and panel estimations. The growth patterns         of GDP per worker (labor productivity) in the OECD countries are to a large extent explained by age structure changes. The         50&amp;#8211;64 age group has a positive influence, and the group above 65 contributes negatively, while younger age groups have ambiguous         effects. However, the mechanism behind these age effects is not yet resolved.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>James McIntosh1</authors><title>An analysis of reproductive behaviour in Canada: Results from an intertemporal optimizing model      </title><content>Abstract.;; Results based on a sample of Canadian households challenge the findings of most studies which show significant negative effects         of schooling on the fertility of women under the age of 45. This is due to the application of methods to an optimization model         which distinguish between those households which have completed their reproductive behaviour from those which have not. Completion         status and the desired number of children are used to infer characteristics of the optimal programme which are then employed         to derive a likelihood function. Traditional demographic methods have so far not fully utilized the distinction between incomplete         and completed households in sample surveys. These methods also lead to the conclusion that completed fertility had increased         from its all time low in the nineteen seventies.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Phillip B. Levine1 | David J. Zimmerman2</authors><title>An empirical analysis of the welfare magnet debate using the NLSY      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper examines the extent to which differences in welfare generosity across states leads to interstate migration. Using         microdata from the National Longitudinal Survey of Youth (NLSY) between 1979 and 1992, we employ a quasi-experimental design         that utilizes the categorical eligibility of the welfare system. The pattern of cross-state moves among poor single women         with children, who are likely to be eligible for benefits is compared to the pattern among other poor households. We find         little evidence indicating that welfare-induced migration is a widespread phenomenon.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Carol Scotese Lehr1</authors><title>Banking on fewer children: Financial intermediation, fertility and economic development      </title><content>Abstract. ;;This paper shows that financial intermediation can influence fertility and labor allocation decisions by raising market wages.         The increase in wages induces some households to abandon &amp;#8220;traditional&amp;#8221; labor intensive methods of production managed at the         household level and supply labor to &amp;#8220;modern&amp;#8221; sector firms. Since it is optimal for households in the modern sector to have         fewer children, the labor allocation decision leads to lower national fertility. A panel VAR using financial intermediation,         fertility and industrial employment share data in 87 countries is estimated. The empirical results show that the data are         consistent with the theoretical predictions.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Gil S. Epstein1| Arye L. Hillman1 | Avi Weiss1</authors><title>Creating illegal immigrants      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper considers the prospects for successful implementation by governments of guest-worker programs that are based on         an intended temporary presence of foreign workers. A means of enforcement of temporary presence is a penalty imposed for overstaying         the permissible time period. Employers who are obliged to post bonds for their foreign workers are provided with an incentive         to ensure that their workers leave at the end of their contractually specified stay. We consider the consequences of such         a bond when foreign workers can leave legal employers for illegal employment. We also investigate the effectiveness of deferred         payments to foreign workers as a means of discouraging transition from legal employment to illegal presence. In the final         analysis, although the policy intention is a temporary stay, we conclude that if foreign workers do not wish to return home,         there is an almost inevitability to the creation of a population of illegal immigrants (whose presence may be subsequently         legalized).      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Rudolf Winter-Ebmer1 | Josef ZweimГјller3</authors><title>Do immigrants displace young native workers: The Austrian experience      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper studies the effect of increased immigration in Austria on the unemployment risk of young natives. Austria experienced         a dramatic rise in the share of alien workers as a result of the breakdown of the former communist regimes (especially from         former Yugoslavia). We concentrate on unemployment entry of young male workers, who are supposed to compete most heavily with         new immigrants. Our results indicate that the detrimental impact &amp;#8211; if it exists at all &amp;#8211; is only minor. This is irrespective         of the analyzed proxy for competition: The share of foreign workers in an industry or in a region.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Aless|ra Venturini1</authors><title>Do immigrants working illegally reduce the natives' legal employment? Evidence from Italy      </title><content>Abstract. ;;The paper uses estimates, provided by the Central Statistical Office, of standard units of labour to examine how immigrants         working (illegally) in the shadow economy affect the employment of (legal) labour in the official economy. The results of         our cross sector-time series analysis of the demand for legal labour in the Italian economy between 1980 and 1995 show that         the increase of illegal units of labour produces a reduction in the use of legal labour, albeit a very limited one. An analysis         by sectors shows that the competitive effect of illegal foreign workers is not homogeneous and is strongest in the agricultural         sector, while complementarity between the two categories of labour is evident in the non-tradable services sector. Furthermore,         when the effects of illegal foreign and illegal native workers are compared, the former is smaller than the latter one, with         illegal foreigners workers just reinforcing the impact of the illegal nationals on the labour market.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Gerard J. van den Berg1 | Jan C. van Ours3</authors><title>Duration dependence and heterogeneity in French youth unemployment durations      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper investigates the degree to which the individual exit rate out of unemployment for young job seekers changes as         a function of the elapsed unemployment duration. We use a nonparametric estimation method for population data on outflows         from different duration classes. The method also provides estimates of the amount of unobserved heterogeneity in these data.         We explicitly take into account that individual exit rates are affected by the business cycle. The method is applied to population         data on young French unemployed job seekers. The results are used for policy recommendations.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Slobodan Djaji&amp;#263 1</authors><title>Dynamics of immigration control      </title><content> This paper examines the dynamic implications of border control policies and internal enforcement measures for the pattern         of illegal immigration and the sectoral allocation of clandestine foreign workers. It is argued that efforts to control illegal         immigration in sectors where they traditionally find employment may trigger the formation of networks supporting clandestine         foreign workers in new locations and occupations where the probability of detection is relatively lower. The end result may be an increase in the overall stock of illegal immigrants residing in the economy.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors> </authors><title>Editorial                  Special Issue on Youth Labor Market</title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors> </authors><title>Editorial  Special Issue on Illegal Migration      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Jane Waldfogel1| Yoshio Higuchi2 | Masahiro Abe3</authors><title>Family leave policies and women's retention after childbirth: Evidence from the United States, Britain, and Japan      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper uses labour force survey data to examine the employment rates and employment decisions of women with young children         in the United States, Britain and Japan. Our results confirm that young children have a very strong negative effect on women's         employment; this effect is most pronounced in Britain. We then take advantage of panel data to investigate the effects of         family leave coverage on women's job retention after childbirth. We find that family leave coverage increases the likelihood         that a woman will return to her employer after childbirth in all three countries, with a particularly marked effect in Japan.         This result suggests that the recent expansions in family leave coverage in the sample countries are likely to lead to increased         employment of women after childbirth.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Jan Ekberg1</authors><title>Immigration and the public sector: Income effects for the native population in Sweden      </title><content>Abstract.;; The immigrants' age structure and labour market situation are major determinants for their net contribution to the public         sector. During the 50s, 60s and the 70s the immigrants' net contributions gave positive income effects for the native Swedes.         Nowadays there are negative income effects due to the deteriorating employment situation among the immigrants. The yearly         positive or negative income effects have at most been 1&amp;#8211;2% of the gross national product. A change in the immigrants' employment         rate by 1 percentage unit will change their yearly net contribution to the public sector by 0.1% of the gross national product.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Regina T. Riphahn1</authors><title>Income and employment effects of health shocks A test case for the German welfare state      </title><content>Abstract.;; Using data from the first eleven waves of the German Socio-Economic Panel this study investigates the dynamic effects of         health shocks on employment and economic well-being of older workers. A health shock trebles the probability of leaving the         labor force and almost doubles the unemployment risk. The financial effects of health shocks are small on average and those         individuals with the highest remaining earnings potential are least affected by the health shock. Welfare state instruments         support the poorest section of the population but do not succeed in neutralizing the effects of a health shock for these groups.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Abul M. M. Masih1 | Rumi Masih2</authors><title>Is a significant socio-economic structural change a pre-requisite for `initial' fertility decline in the LDCs? Evidence from         Thailand based on a multivariate cointegration/vector error correction modelling approach      </title><content>Abstract.;; This study is the first attempt at placing the analysis of fertility in a temporal dynamic framework in the case of a developing         Asian economy such as Thailand by binding the relationship between fertility and its determinants within a cointegrated system.         The analysis is based on the application of the following recently developed dynamic time series techniques: cointegration,         vector error-correction modelling, variance decompositions and the impulse response functions. The results tend to indicate         that in the complex dynamic interactions, the importance of the conventional `structural' hypothesis as a significant factor         in bringing fertility down in the longer term cannot be denied. However, in the short to longer term, our findings, although         not fully supportive of any particular hypothesis, appear to be broadly consistent more with the hypothesis emphasising the         critical role played by the `ideational' or diffusion forces along with the demographic variables in ensuring `initial' fertility         decline than with the conventional `structural' hypothesis emphasising a significant socio-economic structural change as a         pre-condition for `initial' fertility decline.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Barry R. Chiswick1 | Paul W. Miller2</authors><title>Language skills and earnings among legalized aliens      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper uses the data on males and females from the 1989 Legalized Population Survey (LPS), a sample of aliens granted         amnesty under 1986 Immigration Reform and Control Act, to analyse English language proficiency and earnings. We use a model         of English language proficiency that is based on economic incentives, exposure and efficiency variables that measure the costs         and benefits of aquiring English language skills. Consistent with the model, in this sample of former illegal aliens, English         language proficiency is greater for those with more schooling, who immigrated at a younger age, who have been in the United         States longer, with a more continous stay, and who have less access to other origin language speakers where they live. Earnings         are higher by about 8% for men and 17% for women who are proficient in both speaking and reading English, compared to those         lacking both skills.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Ira N. Gang1 | Robert C. Stuart1</authors><title>Mobility where mobility is illegal: Internal migration and city growth in the Soviet Union      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper examines an important anomaly in the internal migration history of the former Soviet Union (FSU). While many cities         were closed in the sense of explicitly limiting growth of city population from migration, it was difficult to assess the effectiveness         of these controls. We analyze a sample of 308 Soviet cities to isolate the impact of closure regulations controlling for city         size. We find that while there are pervasive patterns of city growth, the rate increasing through the 1960s and declining         thereafter, there are also pervasive differences between controlled and uncontrolled cities, the later growing significantly         faster in almost all cases, controlling for city size.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Berthold U. Wigger1</authors><title>Pay-as-you-go financed public pensions  in a model of endogenous growth and fertility      </title><content>Abstract.;; Employing an overlapping generations endogenous growth model in which parents derive utility from having children and, additionally,         expect children to support them in old age, this paper explores the interrelation between growth, fertility, and the size         of pay-as-you-go financed public pensions. It is shown that small sized public pensions stimulate per capita income growth,         but further increases in public pensions eventually reduce it. Fertility, on the other hand, falls by an increase in public         pensions if they are either small or large. Medium sized public pensions, however, may stimulate fertility.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Alan Barrett1| Tim Callan1 | Brian Nolan1</authors><title>Returns to education in the Irish youth labour market      </title><content>Abstract.;; Using data from two large-scale household surveys in 1987 and 1994, we estimate wage equations which show substantial increases         in returns to university education for young Irish workers over the period, despite the exceptional increase in numbers with         these qualifications. Returns to non-degree third level certificates and diplomas fell in relative terms, but returns to qualifications         obtained by those leaving school at about 16 years of age rose. We argue that the increased return to university education         primarily reflects the generalised shift in demand towards skilled labour internationally and the open nature of the Irish         labour market. However, a floor may have been placed under earnings for low-skilled youth by the increased generosity of income         support available to them.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Rowena A. Pecchenino1 | Kelvin R. Utendorf2</authors><title>Social security, social welfare and the aging population      </title><content>Abstract.;; This study examines the effects of pay-as-you-go social security programs in aging economies when the middle-aged both educate         their dependent children and subsidize the retirement of the old. Using an overlapping generations framework in which agents         are three-period lived but timing of death in the third period is uncertain, we analyze the effects of social security tax         schemes, under various demographic assumptions, on capital accumulation, education expenditures, social welfare, and economic         growth. We find that in many cases social security crowds out education, and reduces economic growth and social welfare.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>FranГ§ois Bourguignon1</authors><title>The cost of children: May the collective approach to household behavior help?      </title><content>Abstract.;; The collective approach to household consumption behavior tries to infer from variables supposed to affect the general bargaining         position of household members information on the allocation of consumptions goods and tasks among them. This paper investigates         the extension of previous work to the case where children may be considered as a public consumption good by the two adult         members of a household. The main question being asked is whether it is possible to retrieve from the aggregate consumption         behaviour of the household and the relative earnings of the parents information on the allocation of goods between them and         children. This alternative approach to the estimation of the &amp;#8216;cost of children&amp;#8217; is contrasted with the conventional approach         based on a &amp;#8216;unitary&amp;#8217; representation of and demographic separability assumptions on household consumption behaviour.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Spiros Bougheas1 | Yannis Georgellis2</authors><title>The effect of divorce costs on marriage formation and dissolution      </title><content>Abstract.;; Exploiting the theoretical parallels between the matching of workers to jobs in the labour market and the matching of individuals         in the marriage market, we use a search theoretic model of marriage formation and dissolution to examine the effect of divorce         costs on both decisions. By introducing learning at both stages of the marital decision process, we show that divorce costs         not only affect the probability of divorce but also the probability of marriage. Interestingly, to what extent divorce costs         affect the marital status distribution depends on the information regarding the quality of the potential marriage that individuals         receive while encountering marital offers.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Diane J. Macunovich1</authors><title>The fortunes of one's birth: Relative cohort size and the youth labor market in the United States      </title><content>Abstract.;; Using two different measures of relative cohort size &amp;#8211; one indicating the size and placement of an individual's own birth         cohort, and the other, the ratio of young to prime age adults in the United States in that year &amp;#8211; it has been possible to         isolate strong effects of the population age structure on wages in the United States over the past thirty-three years. These         effects have been strong enough that virtually all of the observed change in the experience premium, and a substantial proportion         of the changes in the college wage premium, can be explained by the relative cohort size variables alone. Even changes in         the amount of within-group variance in wages appear to be largely a function of changing age structure, and absolute wage         levels have been strongly affected by these demographic changes, suggesting that population growth can have positive effects         on the economy.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Patricia Rice1</authors><title>The impact of local labour markets on investment in further education: Evidence from the England and Wales youth cohort studies      </title><content>Abstract.;; The paper focuses on the individual's choice of activity on completion of compulsory schooling &amp;#8211; to remain in full-time education         or to seek employment &amp;#8211; and the factors influencing this decision. Information from the England and Wales Youth Cohort Studies,         coupled with labour market data, is used to estimate of logit model of choice and assess the role played by social and market         factors. The results show that labour market conditions play an influential role in determining outcomes, particularly in         the case of young males with weaker academic qualifications. Consistent with the time-series evidence, we find that participation         rates in further education for both males and females are positively related to the unemployment rate in the local labour         market, the effects being greater at times of economic recession when unemployment rates are rising.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Jill Tiefenthaler1</authors><title>The sectoral labor supply of married couples in Brazil: Testing the unitary model of household behavior      </title><content>Abstract.;; An assumption of the unitary model of household decision-making is that household members maximize one household utility         function. This assumption implies that households pool their income and, therefore, the ownership of nonwage income has no         effect on household demand. In this paper, this implication is tested by estimating multi-sector labor supply equations for         men and women in Brazil. The results indicate that the unitary model is rejected in the informal and self-employment sectors         for men and the formal and informal sectors for women; in these cases own nonwage income has a significantly negative effect         on labor supply while spousal nonwage income has no significant effect.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>David C. Ribar1</authors><title>The socioeconomic consequences of young women's childbearing: Reconciling disparate evidence      </title><content>Abstract.;; Recent studies have begun to examine rigorously the links between early childbearing and subsequent socioeconomic status.         Prominent in this literature has been a set of analyses that have used sibling fixed effects models to control for omitted         variables bias. These studies report that the siblings difference procedure leads to smaller estimates of the effects of teen         fertility than does standard regression analysis. While it is well known that the siblings fixed effects procedure makes strong         assumptions regarding the type of omitted variables and is not necessarily robust to alternative assumptions, the assumptions         of the procedure have not been explicitly examined. This paper uses 1979&amp;#8211;1992 data from the National Longitudinal Survey of         Youth to compare estimates of the income and education consequences of teenage and young adult fertility from standard regression         and siblings fixed effects models with estimates from more general, alternative siblings models.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Paul Levine1</authors><title>The welfare economics of immigration control      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper develops a Harris-Todaro (HT) type model of East-West migration in which labour market imperfections prevent market         clearing in both blocs. The model encompasses two extremes of perfectly flexible wages with full employment on the one hand,         and the HT scenario where the real wage in the host country is fixed, on the other. Welfare analysis compares the laissez-faire         migration equilibrium based on explicit calculations of potential migrants without immigration controls in the West, with         the socially optimal level of migration. The paper examines the issue of immigration control by developing a model of illegal         immigration in which the incentives facing the potentially illegal immigrant are explicitly modelled.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Francisco L. Rivera-Batiz1</authors><title>Undocumented workers in the labor market: An analysis of the earnings of legal and illegal Mexican immigrants in the United         States      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper studies the differences in earnings between Mexican legal and illegal immigrants in the United States. The analysis         includes a cross-sectional examination of the wage differences between legal and undocumented workers as well as a longitudinal         analysis examining the impact of legalization on the earnings of previously-undocumented workers. It is shown that the average         hourly wage rate of male Mexican legal immigrants in the United States was 41.8% higher than that of undocumented workers         while female legal immigrants earned 40.8% more. Though illegal immigrants have lower education and English proficiency, and         a shorter period of residence in the United States, than legal immigrants, it is shown that differences in the observed characteristics         of legal and illegal immigrants explain only 48% of the log-wage gap between male legal and illegal workers and 43% of the         gap for women. An analysis of undocumented immigrants legalized after the 1986 U.S. immigration policy reform shows significant         wage growth in the four years following legalization. These gains are due mostly to the change in legal status itself, not         to changes in the characteristics of immigrants over time.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>Ian Preston1 | Ian Walker2</authors><title>Welfare measurement in labour supply models with nonlinear budget constraints      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper is concerned with the measurement of individual welfare in labour supply models which allow for the impact of         income taxation and income support schemes on labour supply decisions. The paper is motivated by the concern over the need         to have measures which can be interpreted easily, which can be compared with net income, and which can be meaningfully aggregated.         To illustrate the issues we use estimates of a discrete choice model of labour supply for United Kingdom lone mothers to compute         alternative welfare measures which might be considered as having intuitive appeal to policy-makers. We compute welfare change         based on these measures arising from a recent reform of the child support payments system.      </content></document><document><year>1999</year><authors>J. Michael Orszag1 | Dennis Snower1</authors><title>Youth unemployment and government policy      </title><content>Abstract.;; Young people of working age tend to be particularly prone to labor market inefficiencies that keep their wages excessively         high and their employment excessively low. These inefficiencies are usually magnified through unemployment benefit systems.         This paper examines how these problems can be tackled through &amp;#8220;employment vouchers,&amp;#8221; i.e. hiring subsidies or tax breaks for         the unemployed. It examines how vouchers to the young unemployed should differ from those to the adult unemployed. The employment         vouchers considered here reduce unemployment and impose no cost on the government, since they are financed by the induced         fall in government expenditures on unemployment benefits. Among other things, we find that young workers should receive lower         vouchers as displacement of the old rises and as deadweight from providing vouchers to the old increases.      </content></document><document><year>2004</year><authors>Jere R. Behrman1 | Paul Taubman2</authors><title>A comparison and latent variable test of two fertile ideas</title><content>Perhaps the two most important recent strands in the economics of fertility have been developed by Becker and Easterlin. Both suggest possible biases due to unobserved variables. Becker earlier emphasized changing shadow prices for child quantity and quality and, more recently, intergenerational serially-correlated endowments, all with given preferences. Easterlin has focused on intergenerational serially-correlated preferences. Some demographers have suggested that the Becker and Easterlin approaches are converging and may not be identified from each other.We demonstrate that while the Becker endowment and Easterlin taste models can be expressed in terms of the same variables, it is possible to identify each of the models because of different signs in a latent variable system that uses information from individuals, siblings, and cousins. Estimates of this model are consistent with the Easterlin, but not the Becker formulation. But neither model results in significant income coefficient estimates.</content></document><document><year>2004</year><authors>Karel Van den Bosch1| Tim Callan2| Jordi Estivill3| Pierre Hausman4| Bruno Je|idier5| Ruud Muffels6 | John Yfantopoulos7</authors><title>A comparison of poverty in seven European countries and regions using subjective and relative measures</title><content>This paper presents comparative results on poverty in seven countries and regions of the European Community: Belgium, The Netherlands, Luxembourg, Lorraine, Ireland, Catalonia and Greece. The data are obtained from comparable socio-economic surveys in each country. Subjective as well as relative poverty lines are used. The results indicate that the subjective poverty lines are plausible in a comparative context, although the levels of the subjective standards are rather generous. The estimated equivalence scales are much flatter than the one recommended by the OECD. The extent of poverty is much greater in the peripheral EC-countries than in the central ones. Though similar factors are found to be associated with poverty in all countries, there are also important differences in the characteristics of the poor across countries. The impact of social security transfers on poverty appears to be much smaller in the southern countries Greece and Catalonia, than in the Benelux and Lorraine.</content></document><document><year>2004</year><authors>Wolfgang Franz1| Ursula Oser2 | Peter Winker2</authors><title>A macroeconometric disequilibrium analysis of current and future migration from Eastern Europe into West Germany</title><content>This paper attempts to evaluate the impact of current and future immigration flows on major macroeconomic variables of the West German economy. The analysis is based on a macroeconometric disequilibrium model for the West German economy. This model is extended until 1995 and used for several simulation experiments. Special attention is given to the notion that the effects of immigration are regime-specific, i.e., they depend on the type of disequilibrium prevailing on the goods and labor market.</content></document><document><year>2004</year><authors>T. Barmby1 | A. Cigno2</authors><title>A sequential probability model of fertility patterns</title><content>The present paper analyses the fertility histories of a sample of women within a stochastic framework. Recognising the sequential nature of reproductive decisions, the probability that a birth will occur at any given date is related to the realisations of past decisions and to all new information accrued since the last decision date, as well as to the characteristics of the potential mother. Time series are combined with survey data to provide information about the changing economic environment facing all women in the sample. The results of the analysis show the effects of wage rates, child benefits and various personal characteristics on birth probability profiles. The conclusions of the econometric analysis are related to existing theory and to the results of other empirical studies of the economic factors affecting the timing and spacing of births.</content></document><document><year>2004</year><authors>Siegfried Berninghaus1 | Hans G&amp;uuml nther Seifert-Vogt2</authors><title>A temporary equilibrium model for international migration</title><content>This paper is concerned with the existence of temporary equilibria of migration with an overlapping generation structure and analyzes some of its properties. In the first part of the paper sufficient conditions for the existence of a temporary equilibrium of migration (in a given period) are given. In the second part some interesting properties of migration equilibria are analyzed. In particular the effects of differing degrees of information of the individuals on migration equilibria are investigated. Furthermore, it is shown that incomplete information alone suffices to induce migration flows even between countries that can be regarded as identical from an economic point of view.</content></document><document><year>2004</year><authors>Acknowledgement to editorial collaborators</authors><title/></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Diane J. Macunovich1</authors><title>A conversation with Richard Easterlin      </title><content>Abstract. ;;After an introduction touching on various biographical highlights, this paper summarizes a wide-ranging discussion with Richard         Easterlin which occurred in the Autumn of 1996. We considered the Easterlin Hypothesis &amp;#8211; its genesis and current status, together         with Easterlin&amp;#8216;s views on attempts to develop measures of relative income &amp;#8211; and then moved on to &amp;#8220;The Fertility Revolution&amp;#8221;         and questions regarding the applicability of the theory of household choice in modernizing societies. This was followed by         a discussion of his early career development and influences on him at that time, ending with ruminations regarding the current         state of economics, and the validity of training given to young economists today.                                                   JEL classification: J10, J11, J13            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Chong K. Yip1 | Junxi Zhang2</authors><title>A simple endogenous growth model with endogenous fertility: Indeterminacy and uniqueness      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper studies the equilibrium dynamics and indeterminacy of equilibria in an endogenous growth model with endogenous         fertility choice. We characterize the conditions that give rise to an unique equilibrium as well as multiple equilibria. Whenever         there exists a unique equilibrium, it will be globally determinate; when multiple equilibria arise, indeterminacy occurs.         In particular, we find that two equilibria occur &amp;#8211; one is associated with high fertility and low growth, while the other is         associated with low fertility and high growth. A parameterized example is given to assess the empirical feasibility of our         results. The validity of the neo-Malthusian relation between fertility and growth is then re-examined. Finally, we study the         relation between growth and welfare and compare different balanced growth equilibria in terms of their lifetime-attained utility.                                                   JEL classifications: O41, J13            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Huan Nguyen-Dinh1</authors><title>A socioeconomic analysis of the determinants of fertility: The case of Vietnam      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper is an economics-based quantitative analysis of the determinants of individual fertility in Vietnam, measured as         the number of children ever born. In addition  to the conventional linear model, two limited dependent variable models, Poisson         and ordered-logit, are estimated using data from the 1988 Vietnam Demographic and Health Survery. We find, among other things, that husbands&amp;#8216; characteristics are almost as important as those of wives in determining fertility,         perhaps a reflection of the still dominant role of husbands in Vietnamese families. Both paternal and maternal education have         important impacts on fertility. Of special interest is the evidence that supports the attitudinal effect of education over the opportunity-cost effect.      </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Erik Canton1 | Lex Meijdam1</authors><title>Altruism and the macroeconomic effects of demographic changes      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper we show that the macroeconomic effects of demographic changes strongly depend on the degree of altruism and         on the specification of the intertemporal utility function. We allow for agents either to be altruistic in the sense of Barro         (1974) or non-altruistic. In the latter case, generations are heterogeneous like in the &amp;#8222;unloved children&amp;#8221; model of Weil (1989).         In the former case, where the model is a standard Ramsey model with identical agents, we distinguish a Millian and a Benthamite         intertemporal utility function. For each of these models, we study the effects of an anticipated and unanticipated permanent         decline in population growth as well as the consequences of a baby-boom/baby-bust scenario.      </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Douglas A. Galbi1</authors><title>Child labor and the division of labor in the early English cotton mills      </title><content>Abstract.;; The share of children employed in English cotton factories fell significantly before the introduction of effective child         labor legislation in the early 1830s. The early factories employed predominantly children because adults without factory experience         were relatively unproductive factory workers. The subsequent growth of the cotton industry fostered the development of a labor         market for productive adult factory workers. This effect helps account for the shift toward adults in the cotton factory workforce.                                                   JEL classification: J13, N33, O14            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>George Psacharopoulos1</authors><title>Child labor versus educational attainment Some evidence from Latin America      </title><content>Abstract.;; The paper addresses the issue of child labor in relation to the educational attainment of working children. The empirical         analysis is based on household surveys in Bolivia and Venezuela. It was found that labor force participation is non-trivial         among those below the legal working age or supposed to be in school. Working children contribute significantly to total household         income. The fact that a child is working reduces his or her educational attainment by about 2 years of schooling relative         to the control group of non-working children. Grade repetition, a common phenomenon in Latin America, is closely associated         with child labor.                                                   JEL classification: J13, J21, I21            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Peter Jensen1 | Helena Skyt Nielsen1</authors><title>Child labour or school attendance? Evidence from Zambia      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper we investigate what affects school attendance and child labour in an LDC, using data for Zambia. Since the         data comes from a household survey with information on all household members it allows us to take account of unobserved household         effects by introducing household-specific effects in a logit model. The empirical analysis suggests that both economic and         sociological variables are important determinants for the choice between school attendance and child labour. In particular,         we find some support for the hypothesis that poverty forces households to keep their children away from school.                                                   JEL classification: J24, I21, O15            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>C. Y. Cyrus Chu1 | Ronald D. Lee2</authors><title>Corrigendum  Famine, revolte, and the dynastic cycle Population dynamics in historic China      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Cristino R. Arroyo1 | Junsen Zhang2</authors><title>Dynamic microeconomic models  of fertility choice: A survey      </title><content>Abstract.;; We review existing approaches to the specification and estimation of dynamic microeconomic models of fertility. Dynamic fertility         models explain the evolution of fertility variates over the life-cycle as the solution to a dynamic programming model involving         economic choices. Dynamic models may be classified into structural and reduced-form models. Structural models generally require         solution of the underlying dynamic programming problem. Reduced-form models, while based on a structural specification, do         not. Recent innovations in estimation methodologies make both types practical and realistic alternatives to static models         of lifetime fertility.  JEL classification: J13, C41, C61      </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors> </authors><title>                  Editorial                  The second decade                        </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Robert Kollmann1</authors><title>Endogenous fertility in a model with non-dynastic parental altruism      </title><content>Abstract.;; A model of fertility choice is studied in which the utility of parents depends on how much they consume, on how many children         they have and on the consumption of their children. Hence, parents are altruistic towards their children, but in a more limited         sense than in the much discussed dynastic fertility model presented by Becker and Barro (1988). The concept of a (subgame         perfect) bequest equilibrium is used to solve the non-dynastic model considered here. The steady state birth rate is lower         in the non-dynastic model than in the Becker-Barro model. However, the key qualitative predictions concerning the dynamic         behavior of fertility are strikingly similar in both models. JEL classification: J13, J11, D90.      </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Susan Harkness1| Stephen Machin2 | Jane Waldfogel3</authors><title>Evaluating the pin money hypothesis: The relationship between women&amp;#8216;s labour  market activity, family income and poverty in         Britain      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper we evaluate the hypothesis that the over-representation of women amongst the low paid is of little importance         because women&amp;#8216;s earnings account for only a small proportion of total family income. Data from the General Household Survey         (GHS), together with attitudinal evidence from three cross-sectional data sources, indicate that women&amp;#8216;s earnings are in fact         an important and growing component of family income. The majority of the growth in the share of women&amp;#8216;s earnings occurs as         a result of changing family labour structures; women&amp;#8216;s earnings are playing an increasingly important role in keeping their         families out of poverty.                                                   JEL classification: J16; J31.            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Harry Anthony Patrinos1 | George Psacharopoulos2</authors><title>Family size, schooling and child labor in Peru &amp;#8211; An empirical analysis      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper analyzes the effects of being indigenous, number of siblings, sibling activities and sibling age structure on         child schooling progress and child non-school activity. The analysis is based on the Peru 1991 Living Standards Survey. The         analysis shows that family size is important. However, the analysis also demonstrates the importance of taking into consideration         the activities of siblings. The number of siblings not entrolled in school proves to be an important control variable in at         least one specification of the empirical model. However, more research is needed on the interactions between siblings, their         activities and their age structure. In other words, an attempt must be made to find ways of taking into account the &amp;#8220;life         cycle effects&amp;#8221; of one&amp;#8216;s siblings on their schooling performance and labor force activity. The analysis also shows that the         age structure of siblings is important, but in conjunction with their activities. That is, having a greater number of younger         siblings implies less schooling, more age-grade distortion in the classroom and more child labor.                                                   JEL classification: J22, J23, I21            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Rainer Winkelmann1</authors><title>How young workers get their training: A survey of Germany versus the United States                  </title><content>Abstract. ;;The recent economic literature on the incidence of various forms of post-secondary on-the-job and off-the-job training in         Germany and the United States, as well as on the effects of training on wages, inequality, and labor mobility is surveyed.         Young workers in Germany receive substantially more company-based (apprenticeship) training than United States workers. In         the United States, high turnover deters firms from investing in general skills while it results in improved job matches. The         received literature consents that key institutional elements required to make the German apprenticeship system work are absent         in the United States.                                                   JEL classification: I2, J3, J24            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Martin Kolmar1</authors><title>Intergenerational redistribution in a small open economy with endogenous fertility      </title><content>Abstract.;; For pay-as-you-go financed pension systems, claims may be calculated according to individual contributions (income) or the         number of children of a family. We analyse the optimal structure of these parameters in a model with endogenous fertility.         It is shown that for both structural determinants there exists no interior solution of the problem of intragenerational utility         maximisation. Thus, pure systems are always welfare maximizing. Furthermore, children-related pension claims induce a fiscal         externality that tends to be positive. The determination of the optimal contribution rate shows that the widely accepted Aaron-condition         is in general a misleading indicator for the comparison of fully funded and pay-as-you-go financed pension systems.      </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Dietmar Harhoff1 | Thomas J. Kane2</authors><title>Is the German apprenticeship system  a panacea for the U.S. labor market?      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper explores the structure of incentives undergirding the German system of apprenticeship training. We first describe         characteristics of the German labor market which may lead firms to accept part of the cost of general training, even in the         face of worker turnover. We then compare labor market outcomes for apprentices in Germany and high school graduates in the         United States. Apprentices in Germany occupy a similar position within the German wage structure as held by high school graduates         in the United States labor market. Finally, we provide evidence that &amp;#8211; in both countries &amp;#8211; the problem of forming labor market         bonds is particularly acute for minority youth.                                                   JEL classification: J24, J31, J60            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Holger Strulik1</authors><title>Learning-by-doing, population pressure,  and the theory of demographic transition      </title><content>Abstract.;; The present paper discusses the long-run effects of two interdependent relations between economic and population growth.         According to a frequently used formulation of the population-push hypothesis, learning-by-doing effects in production lead         to increasing returns to scale and, therefore, to a positive correlation between economic and population growth. In accordance         to the theory of demographic transition the population growth rate initially increases with rising income levels and then         declines. Regarding this relationship, the existence and stability of a low-income equilibrium and a high-income equilibrium         will be shown in a neoclassical growth model. Under plausible conditions a demo-economic transition from the first to the         second steady-state takes place. The result yields a meaningful interpretation of the population-push hypothesis, which is         consistent with the empirical findings on the correlation between economic and population growth.      </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Weiren Wang1 | Felix Famoye2</authors><title>Modeling household fertility decisions with generalized Poisson regression      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper models household fertility decisions by using a generalized Poisson regression model. Since the fertility data         used in the paper exhibit under-dispersion, the generalized Poisson regression model has statistical advantages over both         standard Poisson and negative binomial regression models, and is suitable for analysis of count data that exhibit either over-dispersion         or under-dispersion. The model is estimated by the method of maximum likelihood. Approximate tests for the dispersion and         goodness-of-fit measures for comparing alternative models are discussed. Based on observations from the Panel Study of Income         Dynamics of 1989 interviewing year, the empirical results support the fertility hypothesis of Becker and Lewis (1973).      </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Amartya Sen1</authors><title>Population policy:  Authoritarianism versus cooperation      </title><content>Abstract.;; The people whose interests are most adversely affected by frequent bearing and rearing of children are young women. Social         changes that expand the decisional power of young women (such as expansion of female literacy, or enhancement of female employment         opportunity) can, thus, be major forces in the direction of reducing fertility rates. This &amp;#8220;cooperative&amp;#8221; route seems to act         more securely &amp;#8211; and often much faster &amp;#8211; than the use of &amp;#8220;coercion&amp;#8221; in reducing family size and birth rates. This essay examines         the comparative evidence from India and China on this subject as well as the interregional contrasts within India.  JEL classification: J11, J13, O15      </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Mark B. Cronshaw1 | Till Requate2</authors><title>Population size and environmental quality      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper presents a simple general equilibrium analysis of first best allocations in an economy where a consumption good         is produced using labor. Production results in pollution, which is a public bad. Pollution abatement can be achieved either         by restricting production or by using additional labor. We consider how the first best allocation and Pigouvian tax vary with         population size. Consumers are unambiguously worse off when the population is larger, but not necessarily due to increased         pollution. In fact, optimal policy on how pollution and labor should vary with population size is very sensitive to preferences         and technology. The best response to an increase in population size might be either to increase or to decrease emissions and/or         labor, depending on functional forms and parameters. However, given separable preferences and some convexity, the optimal         emissions tax increases, and the first best level of per-capita consumption decreases with population size. The paper also         considers the extent to which exogenous technical progress can overturn these conclusions.      </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Wing Suen1</authors><title>Retirement patterns in Hong Kong:  A censored regression analysis      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper provides an overview of retirement patterns in Hong Kong on the basis of limited data. A censored regression model         is used to infer the retirement age from people&amp;#8216;s current retirement status and their current age. This model is equivalent         to a restricted probit model, and the interpretation of parameters is straightforward. The results clearly show a negative         income effect on the retirement decision. The retirement age seems to be positively related to lifetime earnings but negatively         related to the rate of decline of earnings with age.                                                   JEL classification: C24, J14, J26            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Julie L. Hotchkiss1| Mary Mathewes Kassis2 | Robert E. Moore3</authors><title>Running hard and falling behind:  A welfare analysis of two-earner families      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper investigates the commonly asserted proposition that long term economic changes have put the family in a financial         bind. Structural parameters of a family utility model are obtained by estimating simultaneous labor supply functions for a         two-earner household. We find evidence indicating that the average 1990&amp;#8216;s two-earner family would prefer to receive the 1980&amp;#8216;s         real wage package (were it available) instead of the real wage package it actually faces. The degree to which the 1990&amp;#8216;s family         is worse off (in terms of the changes in the real wage package) is roughly equivalent to an hour of leisure per week.      </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Christian Dustmann1| Najma Rajah2 | Stephen Smith1</authors><title>Teenage truancy, part-time working and wages      </title><content>Abstract.;; Part-time work whilst still in full-time education is common in many industrialized countries, and teenagers constitute a         significant component of the work force in some sectors of the labour market. In Britain, in the early 1990&amp;#8216;s, some 60% of         16&amp;#8211;18 year olds still in full time education also worked part-time. Although the determinants of teenager participation in         the labour market have been studied previously (both in the United States and the United Kingdom), there remain a number of         neglected questions. We address some of these in this paper, basing our analysis on data taken from the UK National Child         Development Study. We first examine how teenagers divide their time between working and studying. We further analyse what         explains teenage wages and labour supply. We utilise a rich set of variables describing parental background, as well as parents&amp;#8216;         labour force status and draw on information on physical stature to explain variations in wages.                                                   JEL classification: I20, J20, J31            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>James B. Davies1 | Junsen Zhang2</authors><title>The effects of gender control on fertility and children&amp;#8216;s consumption      </title><content>Abstract.;; Effects of sex preference on investments in children&amp;#8216;s human capital, bequests and fertility are studied, with and without         sex selection, in a model based on parental altruism. Both pure sex preference, a feature of the parental utility function,         and indirect preference, which arises from gender-related differences in earnings opportunities, are examined. When there         is no gender control the impact of pure sex preference is seen in smaller consumption for daughters than for sons. However,         when gender control is exerted, sex preference raises the sex ratio and it is possible that sisters may, on average, consume         no less than their more numerous brothers. In an example of the model with specific functional forms, parents who practise         gender control have larger families than if sex selection techniques were unavailable. The effect is magnified if sons&amp;#8216; earnings         opportunities are better than daughters&amp;#8216;.                                                   JEL classification: D11, J13, J16            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Sik|ar Siddiqui1</authors><title>The pension incentive to retire:  Empirical evidence for West Germany      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper, the impact of the West German pension system on the retirement decisions of elderly citizens is analyzed within         the framework of a discrete-time hazard rate model deduced from a micro-economic decision rule. The model is estimated using         a panel dataset of elderly West German citizens. In order to improve the precision of the estimates obtained, the data from         the sample are combined with aggregate-level information on the labour force participation behaviour of the elderly. Policy         simulations based on the estimates reveal that the probability of early retirement can be reduced significantly by appropriate         changes in the pension system.                                                   JEL classification: C32, C41, J26            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Jonathan R. Veum1</authors><title>Training and job mobility among young workers  in the United States      </title><content>Abstract. ;;Using data from the National Longitudinal Survey of Youth from 1987 to 1992, the determinants of training and the impact of         training on job turnover are examined for young private sector workers in the United States. It is found that the receipt         of company training is positively correlated with education, ability, and prior tenure at the job. The results provide only         limited evidence that company training reduces turnover. There is substantial evidence, however, that training which is not         financed by employers increases job mobility. The results imply that training plays an important role in the job search and         job matching process among young workers.                                                   JEL classification: J24, J41, J63            </content></document><document><year>1997</year><authors>Wiji Arulampalam1 | Alison L. Booth2</authors><title>Who gets over the training hurdle? A study of the training experiences of young men and women in Britain      </title><content>Abstract.;; Using longitudinal data from the British National Child Development Study, this paper examines gender differences in the         determinants of work-related training. The analysis covers a crucial decade in the working lives of this 1958 birth cohort         of young men and women &amp;#8211; the years spanning the ages of 23 to 33. Hurdle negative binomial models are used to estimate the         number of work-related training events lasting at least three days. This approach takes into account the fact that more than         half the men and two thirds of the women in the sample experienced no work-related training lasting three or more days over         the period 1981 to 1991. Our analysis suggests that reliance on work-related training to improve the skills of the work force         will result in an increase in the skills of the already educated, but will not improve the skills of individuals entering         the labor market with relatively low levels of education.                                                   JEL classification: C25, I21, J24.            </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors/></document><document><year>2008</year><authors/></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Chengze Simon Fan1</authors><title>A model of endogenous divorce and endogenous fertility      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper examines the interaction between decisions on divorce and fertility. The analysis generates two major implications.         Firstly, it complements the existing literature on endogenous fertility to explain why population growth and economic growth         can be negatively correlated after an economy develops to a certain level. Secondly, it indicates that economic development         leads to a simultaneous increase in divorce rates and decrease in fertility rates.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors> </authors><title>Acknowledgement to editorial collaborators      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Avner Ahituv1</authors><title>Be fruitful or multiply: On the interplay between fertility and economic development      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper develops and estimates an empirical model of the interplay between fertility and economic development. Using panel         data, this study finds that a one-percent decrease in population growth increases GDP per capita growth by more than three         percent. In addition, because families with low levels of human capital choose to have more children, income per capita grows         faster in developed countries than in developing countries. Finally, this study shows that the estimates of the interplay         between fertility and output obtained from single cross-country regressions are biased downward because that method of estimation         is unable to control for unobservable country effects and measurement errors. The neoclassical approach fails to account for         these effects. The present study contributes to the now-standard growth model, and provides a better description of international         differences in standards of living.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Bruno Decreuse1</authors><title>Can skill-biased technological change compress unemployment rate differentials across education groups?      </title><content>Abstract.;; Our aim is to explain why the pattern of relative unemployment rates by education groups was non monotonic in most of the         OECD countries. In a two-sector matching model, a simple unexpected productivity shock biased against unskilled labor can         replicate the observed dynamics. Demographic effects of skill-biased shocks can be related to inequality in the distribution         of wealth.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Martha S. Hill1| Wei-Jun J. Yeung1 | Greg J. Duncan2</authors><title>Childhood family structure and young adult behaviors      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper examines a wide variety of forms, and full histories, of family structure to test existing theories of family         influences and identify needs for new theories. The focus is on links between childhood family structure and both completed         schooling and risk of a nonmarital birth. Using a 27-year span of panel (PSID) data for U.S. children, we find that: (a) change         is stressful, (b) timing during childhood is relevant, (c) adults other than parents are important, and (d) two more recently         studied family structures (mother-with-grandparent(s) and mother-with-stepfather) do not fit the molds of existing theories.         The findings suggest that new theories should consider allocation of resources and reasons people group into family structures.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Claus Chr. PГ¶rtner1</authors><title>Children as insurance      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper presents a dynamic model of fertility decisions in which children serve as an incomplete insurance good. The model         incorporates uncertainty about future income and the survival of children as well as a discrete representation of the number         of children. It contributes to the understanding of the negative relation between fertility and education, shows why parents         may demand children even if the return is negative, and explains why fertility might rise with increasing income when income         is low and decrease when income is high. Furthermore, the model can account for the decline in fertility when the risk of         infant and child mortality decreases. Finally, the implications for empirical tests of the demand for children are also examined.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Christoph M. Schmidt1 | Jochen Kluve2</authors><title>Comparing the Comparable Nobel Price Winner James J. Heckman      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>JГ¶rn-Steffen Pischke1</authors><title>Continuous training in Germany      </title><content>Abstract.;; Using data from the German Socio Economic Panel, I analyze the incidence, financing, and returns to workplace training in         Germany for the years 1986 to 1989. Much of this training seems general, and is provided to workers by their employer at no         direct cost. While workers typically report larger productivty gains from the training during work hours, such training has         lower returns than training undertaken during leisure time. Workers with higher earnings growth seem more likely to participate         in training. I deal with this selection problem by estimating models that allow for inidividual level heterogeneity in earnings         growth rates.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Michael Rosholm1</authors><title>Cyclical variations in unemployment duration      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper I study how individual unemployment durations vary over the business cycle, using unemployment spells of a         sample of Danish workers. A compositional, an outflow, and a residual calendar-time component are identified, and they all         contribute to explaining the variations in unemployment duration. Based on the analysis it is concluded that long-term unemployment         is a phenomenon that is associated with periods of high unemployment, but nothing should prevent the long-term unemployed         finding jobs again as aggregate unemployment eventually starts falling. In particular, there is no evidence of negative duration         dependence, not even at long durations, and not when aggregate unemployment is high.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Pieter Bevel|er1 | Helena Skyt Nielsen2</authors><title>Declining employment success of immigrant males in Sweden: Observed or unobserved characteristics?      </title><content>Abstract.;; Focusing on Nordic and Yugoslavian immigrant males, we study the determinants of employment success of natives and immigrants         in Sweden. Furthermore, we investigate the reasons behind the arising gap in employment success between Swedes and immigrants         from 1970 to 1990. In a decomposition analysis, we find that the main part of the decline in the employment probability of         immigrants relative to Swedes over time is explained by a change in coefficients (unobserved characteristics) rather than         a change in determinants (observed characteristics).      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Friedrich Breyer1 | Klaus Stolte1</authors><title>Demographic change, endogenous labor supply and the political feasibility of pension reform      </title><content>Abstract.;; Options for reforming unfunded public pension schemes that are now being discussed all share the feature that the burden         induced by demographic change would be shifted towards presently living and away from unborn generations. Existing models         of the political economy of pension reform can not explain why such reform options are being discussed at all. We present         an alternative model in which the possibility of evasion of workers from payment of social security taxes is taken into account         by modelling a labor supply function. It turns out that the burden of demographic change may fall completely or at least predominantly         on the pensioners. Thus this type of model can much better explain recent trends in legislature on unfunded public pension         systems in industrial democracies.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>C. Y. Cyrus Chu1 | Ching Tai2</authors><title>Ecosystem resilience, specialized adaptation and population decline: A modern Malthusian theory      </title><content>Abstract. ;;The purpose of this article is to construct a theoretical framework characterizing the interactions among economic development,         ecosystem equilibrium and possible population decline, and to discuss the population dynamics in the very long run. In our         framework, economic activities bridge population and environment. On the one hand, human beings reform the environment through         economic activities; on the other hand, economic activities decrease environmental resilience and increase the possibility         of an environmental change in a discontinuous and irreversible pattern, as described in Arrow et al. (1995). Furthermore,         a highly developed economy also causes over-specialization of human adaptation, which tends to exaggerate the impact of an         environmental change on human population size.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Alex|ra Rillaers1</authors><title>Education and income inequality: The role of a social protection system      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper we aim to understand the role a welfare state can play in stimulating risky but profitable activities like         investment in education, and in reducing income inequality. We analyze how unemployment benefits may affect investment in         education when the latter is characterized by uncertain returns. This is done in an overlapping generations model in which         endogenous growth is introduced through human capital accumulation. We develop a numerical example of the model in order to         reproduce some key differences between the European versus the North American economy; differences that, according to this         model, result from the different degree of social protection characterizing both economies.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Thomas Aronsson1| Sven-Olov Daunfeldt1 | Magnus WikstrГ¶m1</authors><title>Estimating intrahousehold allocation in a collective model with household production      </title><content>Abstract.;; The purpose of this paper is to estimate the intra-family distribution of income and the individual demand for leisure and         household production from Swedish cross-sectional household data. As a basis for the analysis, we use a collective model where         each individual is characterized by his or her own utility function and divides total time between leisure, household production         and market work. For the purpose of comparison, we also estimate a version that is consistent with a more traditional model         of labor supply, the unitary model.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>John F. Ermisch1 | Marco Francesconi1</authors><title>Family structure and children's achievements      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper we estimate the relationships between several outcomes in early adulthood (educational attainment, economic         inactivity, early childbearing, distress and smoking) and experience of life in a single-parent family during childhood. The         analysis is performed using a special sample of young adults, who are selected from the first five waves of the British Household         Panel Survey (1991&amp;#8211;95) and can be matched with at least one sibling over the same period. We also perform level (logit) estimation         using another sample of young adults from the BHPS. We find that: (i) experience of life in a single-parent family is usually         associated with disadvantageous outcomes for young adults; (ii) most of the unfavourable outcomes are linked to an early family         disruption, when the child was aged 0&amp;#8211;5; and (iii) level estimates, whose causal interpretation relies on stronger assumptions,         confirm the previous results and show that, for most outcomes, the adverse family structure effect persists even after controlling         for the economic conditions of the family of origin.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors> </authors><title>Fifteenth ESPE Conference and General Assembly in Athens 2001         Report, General Assembly</title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Steven Garasky1| R. Jean Haurin2 | Donald R. Haurin3</authors><title>Group living decisions as youths transition to adulthood      </title><content>Abstract.;; This study follows teens through young adulthood as they transition to independent living. We focus on a little studied issue:         why some youths live in groups rather than alone or with parents. This choice is important because the size of the group has         a substantial impact on the demand for dwelling units; the more youths per dwelling the lower is aggregate demand and the         greater is population density. Our study also adds to the knowledge of which factors influence youths' choice of destination         as they leave the parental home. The empirical testing uses a discrete hazard model within a multinomial logit framework to         allow for more than one possible state transition. We find that economic variables have little impact on the decision of whether         to exit to a large versus a small group, while socio-demographic variables matter. We also test a new push-pull hypothesis         and find that the pull of economic variables on the probability of exiting the parental home increases as youths reach their         mid to late twenties.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>BjГ¶rn Gustafsson1 | Torun Г–sterberg1</authors><title>Immigrants and the public sector budget &amp;#8211; accounting exercises for Sweden      </title><content>Abstract.;; Net contributions to the public sector budget in Sweden are investigated using large samples of foreign born and native born.         The accounts build on various assumptions including that expenditures on public consumption are allocated according to the         age of the person. The results indicate that during the period 1983 to 1992 net contributions of immigrants deteriorated.         Upon arrival to Sweden, immigrants on average place a burden on the public sector budget but after a few years this no longer         applies. Refugees initially put a larger burden on the public sector budget than other immigrants, but such a difference declines         with years since immigration.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Damien Gaumont1 | Alice Mesnard2</authors><title>Inheritance, land, and capital mobility linked to labour mobility      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper presents a two-country migration model, following Galor (1986), in which the world population consists of two         types individuals. Individuals with a high (low) degree of altruism give to their children a high (low) level of bequest.         Production uses three inputs: immobile land, mobile labour, and capital. Capital mobility is linked to labour mobility since         individuals move with their inheritance. The model shows that countries are homothetic in the post-migration equilibrium with         equal factor prices and equal densities of population. Migration flows are bilateral and the number of each type of migrants         is uniquely determined. In some cases, migration leads to a Pareto improvement in both countries.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Harry Papapanagos1 | Peter Sanfey2</authors><title>Intention to emigrate in transition countries: the case of Albania      </title><content>Abstract.;; We analyse the profile of potential emigrants from Albania using data from the Central and Eastern Europe Eurobarometer in         1992. Respondents were asked to rate on a four-point scale the likelihood that they would go to live in Western Europe. Our         results show that intention to emigrate is correlated positively with males, education and certain occupations, and negatively         with age. There is little relation between emigration and income. Those who support the introduction of a free market in Albania         are also more likely to emigrate than those who do not.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Donna K. Ginther1 | Madeline Zavodny1</authors><title>Is the male marriage premium due to selection? The effect of shotgun weddings on the return to marriage      </title><content>Abstract.;; In standard cross-sectional wage regressions, married men appear to earn 10 to 20% more than comparable never married men.         One proposed explanation for this male marriage premium is that men may be selected into marriage on the basis of characteristics         valued by employers as well as by spouses or because they earn high wages. This paper examines the selection hypothesis by         focusing on shotgun weddings, which may make marital status uncorrelated with earnings ability. We compare the estimated marriage         premium between white men whose first marriages are soon followed by a birth and other married white men in the United States.         The return to marriage differs little for married men with a premarital conception and other married men, and the results         suggest that at most 10% of the estimated marriage premium is due to selection.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Namkee Ahn1 | Pedro Mira2</authors><title>Job bust, baby bust?: Evidence from Spain      </title><content>Abstract.;; The unemployment rate in Spain has been exceptionally high for more than two decades by now. During the same period the fertility         rate dropped dramatically reaching the lowest level in the world. In this study we look for evidence of a link between the         `unemployment crisis' and the `fertility crisis' in Spain. We examine the factors that affect individuals' ages at marriage         and childbirth, focusing on the effects of male employment status. Our results show that spells of non-employment have a strong negative effect on the hazard of marriage.         We also find negative (but smaller) effects of part-time or temporal employment on the hazard of marriage. The estimated direct         effects of joblessness and part-time work on birth hazards conditional on marriage are smaller and/or not significant for         most birth intervals and sample groups. Simulations based on the estimated models confirm the potential for large `delaying'         effects of joblessness on marriage. However, the delaying effect is not so large in simulations which control for the actual         incidence of non-employment in the sample.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Emmanuel Thibault1</authors><title>Labor immigration and long-run welfare in a growth model with heterogenous agents and endogenous labor supply      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper examines the consequences of labor immigration in an OLG economy in which agents have an elastic labor supply         and differ with respect to degrees of altruism and rates of time preference. It focuses on three substantive questions. First,         how do immigrants influence the bequest motive of altruistic natives? Second, what impact do immigrants have on the labor         supply of natives? Finally, how does immigration affect the long-run welfare of both altruistic and non altruistic natives?      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>KГҐre BГ¦vre1| Christian Riis2 | Tore Thonstad1</authors><title>Norwegian cohort emigration      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper introduces a counterfactual technique to estimate net emigration from Norwegian birth cohorts from 1846 to 1900.         A main finding is that despite strong fluctuations in annual emigration, the percentage reduction of each cohort due to emigration         was surprisingly stable for all cohorts from 1846 to 1886, with net emigration of about 30% for males and about 20% for females.         Estimating an econometric model of annual male gross emigration by single years of age 15&amp;#8211;60 in the period 1870&amp;#8211;1914, we find         that previous net emigration from a cohort reduces later gross emigration from the same cohort. The estimations also give         some justification for attributing this to selectivity of emigration, in the sense that only a certain proportion of each         cohort were potential migrants.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Steinar Vagstad1</authors><title>On private incentives to acquire household production skills      </title><content>Abstract.;; In non-cooperative family models, being good at contributing to family public goods like household production may reduce         one's utility, since it tends to crowd out contributions from one's spouse. Similar effects also arise in cooperative models         with non-cooperative threat point: improved contribution productivity entails loss of bargaining power. This strategic effect         must be traded against the benefits of household production skills, in terms of increased consumption possibilities. Since         cooperation involves extensive specialization, incentives to acquire household production skills are strikingly asymmetric,         with the one not specializing in household production having strong disincentives for household skill acquisition.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Hans-Peter Kohler1 | Eugene A. Hammel2</authors><title>On the role of families and kinship networks in pre-industrial agricultural societies: An analysis of the 1698 Slavonian census      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper uses the 1698 Slavonian census to illuminate features of social organization and productive activity of an eastern         European population under the New Feudalism of the 17th century. In particular we investigate the ability of community or         kinship networks to provide substitutes for missing markets in securities and production factors. It is found that kinship         networks increase the efficiency of agricultural production by facilitating the exchange of oxen. This confirms contemporary         reports that draft animals were the critical constraint to the expansion of agricultural output. We also find that kinship         networks fail to reduce the variability of output through mutual harvest insurance.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Siv Gustafsson1</authors><title>Optimal age at motherhood. Theoretical and empirical considerations on postponement of maternity in Europe      </title><content>Abstract.;; The age at which women become mothers has increased to an all time high in most European countries in the past decennia.         This increase of age at first birth is the main explanatory variable for the rapid decrease in fertility in European countries         which has occurred at different points of time earlier in North and West Europe than in South Europe. To understand the development         of the period fertility rate it is therefore crucial to understand the determinants of optimal age at maternity. This paper         reviews empirical and theoretical literature and tries to give suggestions on future research directions. The econometric         so called timing and spacing literature has used current female wages and male incomes as the main explanatory variables.         However, theoretical research identifies on the one hand consumption smoothing, and on the other hand career planning of the         woman as the main explanations to the postponement of maternity.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Paul Fronstin1| David H. Greenberg2 | Philip K. Robins3</authors><title>Parental disruption and the labour market performance of children when they reach adulthood      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper uses data from the age 33 wave of the British National Child Development Survey (NCDS) to analyze the effects         of a parental disruption (divorce or death of a father) on the labour market performance of children when they reach adulthood.         The NCDS is a longitudinal study of all children born during the first week of March 1958 in England, Scotland, and Wales.         Controlling for a rich set of pre-disruption characteristics, the results indicate that a parental disruption leads to moderately         less employment among males and considerably lower wage rates among females at age 33. If pre-disruption characteristics are         not controlled for, larger effects are estimated for both males and females. Parental disruption also seems to cause substantial         reductions in educational attainment for both males and females.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>GГЎbor GyГЎrfГЎs1 | Marko Marquardt1</authors><title>Pareto improving transition from a pay-as-you-go to a fully funded pension system in a model of endogenous growth      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper we investigate the possibility of Pareto improving social security reforms within a framework of endogenous         growth. Belan et al. (1998) propose a transition from a pay-as-you-go (PAYG) pension system to a system of savings&amp;#8211;subsidization.         We follow this approach and prove that a Pareto improving conversion from the PAYG system to a fully funded one is possible.         Finally, we compare the subsidy system with the fully funded system and discuss the problem of implementing the transition         to the fully funded system.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Aless|ra Guariglia1</authors><title>Saving behaviour and earnings uncertainty: Evidence from the British Household Panel Survey      </title><content>Abstract.;; For the first time, this paper uses a panel data set, the British Household Panel Survey, to analyse saving behaviour in         Britain. One objective is to test the precautionary saving hypothesis, according to which households save to self-insure against         uncertainty. Our results show that in accordance with this hypothesis, various measures of uncertainty based on earnings variability         have a statistically significant effect on households' saving decisions. Moreover, in accordance with the life cycle model,         households save more if they expect their financial situation to deteriorate.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors> </authors><title>Siv Gustafsson                  1999 President of the European Society for Population Economics</title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Alfonso Sousa-Poza1| Hans Schmid1 | Rolf Widmer1</authors><title>The allocation and value of time assigned to housework and child-care: An analysis for Switzerland      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper, data from the 1997 Swiss Labour Force Survey are used to analyse the allocation and value of time assigned         to housework and child-care. It is shown that men's allocation of time to housework and child-care is largely invariant to         changes in socio-economic factors. Women's allocation of time to housework and child-care, on the other hand, is shown to         depend on several social, economic, and demographic factors. The value of time assigned to housework and child-care is calculated         with two market replacement cost methods and three opportunity cost methods. The results show that the value of time assigned         to housework and child-care ranges from 27% to 39% and from 5% to 8% of GDP (in 1997), respectively. The value of time assigned         to housework and child-care is also calculated for different household structures.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>SГ©bastien Lecocq1</authors><title>The allocation of time and goods in household activities: A test of separability      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper, we test for the weak separability hypothesis imposed by the household production model between goods and time         inputs used in the production of different commodities. Our data come from a French survey which reports both expenditures         and time that households devote to some activities. The results allow us to show that the weak separability assumption cannot         be rejected only when households are strongly time constrained. In the opposite case, home time uses are found to be nonseparable.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>JoAnn Kingston-Riechers1</authors><title>The association between the frequency of wife assault and marital dissolution in Canada      </title><content>Abstract.;; A strong positive association between wife abuse in the first marriage and the probability of that marriage ending is documented         and investigated using the 1993 Violence Against Women survey (VAWS) for Canada and controlling for the endogeneity of abuse.         A sensitivity analysis suggests that systematic reporting differences are not likely to account for the findings.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Louise Grogan1 | Gerard J. van den Berg2</authors><title>The duration of unemployment in Russia      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper uses longitudinal survey data to assess factors affecting the duration of unemployment in Russia. We examine four         types of marginalised labour force participants, according to ILO guidelines and survey responses, and we estimate duration         models for each type. It turns out that the sets of characteristics with the strongest effects on the duration are remarkably         similar across the different unemployment definitions and model specifications. Therefore, despite the formidable practical         measurement problems, problematic groups of individuals can actually be identified.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Stephen Wheatley Price1</authors><title>The employment adjustment of male immigrants in England      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper the employment performance of native and foreign born men in England is examined, using 1993&amp;#8211;1994 data from         the Quarterly Labour Force Survey of the United Kingdom. Chiswick's (1982) hypotheses of immigrant employment adjustment are         investigated using logistic regression analysis. We show that there are interesting and important employment effects arising         from immigrant characteristics. Recent white immigrants experience a transitory employment disadvantage. However non-white         immigrants never attain employment equality with native born white men. Education, potential experience, family characteristics         and country of birth are also found to be important determinants of employment.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Chulhee Lee1</authors><title>The expected length of male retirement in the United States, 1850&amp;#8211;1990      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper estimates the expected length of retirement for each labor market cohort between 1850 and 1990. Since 1850, the         expected length of retirement has increased by more than six-fold and now represents up to 30% of male length of life after         entry into the labor force. The rise of the duration of retirement during the twentieth century is analyzed according to the         effects of mortality decline and of decreased age of retirement. Implications of the result for a number of economic issues,         including the relative importance of life-cycle savings and the potential saving effect of Social Security, are discussed.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Jacques Poot1 | Jacques J. Siegers2</authors><title>The macroeconomics of fertility in small open economies: A test of the Becker-Barro model for The Netherlands and New Zealand      </title><content>Abstract.;; Becker and Barro (1988) formulated a theoretical model which identified a range of macroeconomic variables which can temporarily         or permanently affect fertility in small open economies. This article tests the Becker-Barro model with relevant data which         covers most of the 20th century for two small open economies, namely The Netherlands and New Zealand. The results show that         government subsidies for having children have a strong positive effect on fertility, while the provision of public pensions         has a strong negative effect. The degree of intergenerational altruism appears to have been declining. Moreover, there is         only weak support for the hypothesis that real interest rates positively influence fertility.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>M. Asghar Zaidi1 | Klaas de Vos2</authors><title>Trends in consumption-based poverty and inequality in the European Union during the 1980s      </title><content>Abstract.;; Most recent studies on poverty and inequality in developed countries focus on income. In contrast, this paper presents trends         in consumption-based poverty and inequality in nine member countries of the European Union. During the 1980s, both poverty         and inequality increased in Italy, France, the United Kingdom, Germany and Belgium, while decreases in both poverty and inequality         are observed for Spain and Portugal. In Greece only inequality increased. For most countries for which income-based results         are available, these move in the same direction as the consumption-based results. However, this sensitivity analysis yields         considerable differences in the ranking of countries and the magnitude of the changes.      </content></document><document><year>2001</year><authors>Akira Yakita1</authors><title>Uncertain lifetime, fertility and social security      </title><content>Abstract.;; Investigating the effects of population aging on fertility and economic growth, we show that an increase in life expectancy         lowers the fertility rate and raises life-cycle savings, and that a pay-as-you-go social security does not reverse the effect         on fertility.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>            20th Anniversary of the European Society for Population Economics (ESPE): Researching the Major Social Challenge of Our Time        </authors><title/></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>Lex Meijdam1  | Harrie A. A. Verbon1 </authors><title>Aging and political decision making on public pensions      </title><content>In this paper decision making on public pensions in a representative democracy is modeled within the framework of the well-known         two-overlappinggenerations (OLG) general-equilibrium model with rational expectations. The model is used to analyze the effects         of aging on the economy in general and on the evolution of public pension schemes in particular, where aging is interpreted         as a combination of a decrease in the rate of population growth and an increase in the political influence of pensioners.         Analytical results are derived for the long run as well as for the short run by the method of comparative statics and comparative         dynamics respectively. It appears that an increase in transfers to the old is not guaranteed if due to aging their political         power increases.      </content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>Alan Barrett1 </authors><title>Did the decline continue?         Comparing the labor-market quality of United States immigrants from the late 1970&amp;#8217;s and late 1980&amp;#8217;s</title><content>The issue addressed in this paper is whether or not the decline in immigrant labor-market quality in the U.S. observed in         the late 1960&amp;#8217;s and 1970&amp;#8217;s continued in the 1980vs. Two other papers, Borjas (1995) and Funkhouser and Trejo (1995), have         addressed the issue and have come up with contradictory results. In this paper I use a different data set, one that has advantages         over the data sets used in the other studies. Given the rise in earnings inequality that has occurred in the United States         over the 1980&amp;#8217;s, the returns to immigration for the more highly skilled will have increased relative to the low skilled, ceteris         paribus. For this reason, it is possible that the skill decline of immigrants may have halted in the 1980&amp;#8217;s as immigrants         of differing skill levels respond to the altered circumstances they would face in the United States. The empirical results         show that the skill decline did indeed halt, a result which gives support to the Funkhouser/ Trejo result.      </content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>Klaus F. Zimmermann1 </authors><title>Editorial      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>Barry R. Chiswick1  | Paul W. Miller2 </authors><title>Ethnic networks and language proficiency among immigrants      </title><content>Recent research on the linguistic adjustment of minority-language speaking immigrants in several destinations has found that         acquisition of destination language skills is inhibited by living in an area where many others speak the same minority language.         This paper uses a unique data set for Australia (1988) that includes a variety of ethnic network variables to analyze the         role of the language concentration measure. These ethnic variables, in particular, ethnic press, relatives in Australia, and         spouse&amp;#8217;s origin language, are highly statistically significant. Their inclusion in the equation eliminates the effect of the         minority-language concentration variable. The model for analyzing the determinants of English reading and English writing         skills in Australia is also shown to be very similar to the model for speaking fluency, including the effect of the ethnic         network variables.      </content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>Elise S. Brezis1  | Paul R. Krugman2 </authors><title>Immigration, investment, and real wages      </title><content>When a country is the recipient of large-scale, politically motivated immigration &amp;#8212; as has been the case for Israel in recent         years &amp;#8212; the initial impact is to reduce real wages. Over the longer term, however, the endogenous response of investment,         together with increasing returns, may well actually increase real earnings. If immigration itself is not wholly exogenous,         but respond to real wages, they may be multiple equilibria, that is, optimism or pessimism about the success of the economy         at absorbing immigrants may constitute a self-fulfilling prophecy. Since World War II, a number of countries have experienced         surges of politically motivated immigration. Examples include West Germany during the early postwar years, which was the destination         of millions of refugees from the East; Portugal, faced during the mid-1970s with the return of several hundred thousand citizens         from its newly independent African colonies; and Israel, which absorbed a massive wave of immigrants in the years following         independence and has recently received a new surge of immigration from the former Soviet Union. Such waves of immigration         often present considerable short-run economic difficulties, leading to some mix of upward pressure on unemployment and downward         pressure on real wages. Nonetheless, over the longer run it is arguable that immigration not only brings considerable benefits,         it may well tend to raise real wages. The problem is one of getting through the transition. The purpose of this paper is to         offer a simple model that is suggestive of the mix of difficulties and opportunity presented by large-scale immigration. It         shows why immigration may well have a negative effect on real wages in the short run but a positive effect in the long run.         It also suggests the possibility that the outcome of waves of immigration is not predetermined: the question of whether the         immigrants are successfully absorbed may depend crucially on both policy and expectations.      </content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>Ted Bergstrom1  | Robert F. Schoeni2 </authors><title>Income prospects and age-at-marriage      </title><content>This paper provides an empirical investigation of a theoretical model of the marriage market. In the model, women are valued         more for their ability to bear children and men are valued more for their ability to make money. Men cannot reveal their labor         market ability to potential spouses until they enter the labor force. At the same time, the relevant information for evaluating         females as spouses is revealed at a younger age. The model predicts that the income of males will be positively associated         with age-at-first-marriage. We find empirical support for the model. However, we also find the association between male earnings         and age-at-first-marriage becomes negative for those who married after age 30, which was not predicted by the model. Consistent         with the model, we do not find a strong relationship between earnings and age-at-first-marriage among females.      </content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>Philippe Michel1 | Anne Perrot2  | Jacques-FranГ§ois Thisse3 </authors><title>Interregional equilibrium with heterogeneous labor      </title><content>The impact of labor migration on interregional equilibrium is studied when workers are heterogeneous in productivity and regional         mobility. The skilled respond to market disequilibrium by moving into the most attractive region. The unskilled are immobile         in the short-run and move with the skilled in the long-run. Both regions have a neoclassical production function affected         by an externality depending on the number of skilled. Workers move according to the utility differential when regional amenities         vary with population or according to the wage differential. The equilibrium pattern depends on the unskilled&amp;#8217;s mobility and         on migration incentives. Typically, regional imbalance characterizes the equilibrium which is often suboptimal.      </content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>Matthias Staat1  | Gerhard Wagenhals2 </authors><title>Lone mothers: A review      </title><content>This paper briefly reviews recent empirical studies on the economic behaviour of lone mothers concentrating on the duration         of lone motherhood, on labour supply, and on the determinants of their welfare participation. We start out by sketching some         stylised facts about lone-mother-families in various countries. With this background we give a guided tour through the empirical         literature followed by a summary of the policy implications of the results presented.      </content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>Gabriella A. Bucci1  | Rafael Tenorio2 </authors><title>On financing the internal enforcement of illegal immigration policies      </title><content>We introduce a government budget constraint into an illegal immigration model, and show that the effect of increasing internal         enforcement of immigration laws on the host country&amp;#8217;s disposable national income depends on the mix of employer fines and         income taxation used to finance the added enforcement. These issues are addressed under alternative assumptions about (a)         the ability of host country employers to discern between legal and illegal workers, and (b) host country labor market conditions.         Empirical evidence for the United States indicates that the employer sanctions program may have had a negative impact on disposable         national income.      </content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>Evelyn L. Lehrer1 </authors><title>Religion as a determinant of marital fertility      </title><content>This paper develops hypotheses about the effects of husbands&amp;#8217; and wives&amp;#8217; religious affiliations on fertility. The hypotheses         are based on two central ideas. First, religions differ in their fertility norms and corresponding tradeoffs between the quality         and quantity of children; differences in religious beliefs between husband and wife may thus lead to conflict regarding fertility         decisions and possible resolution through bargaining. Second, a low level of religious compatibility between the spouses may         raise the expected probability of marital dissolution and thereby decrease the optimal amount of investments in spouse-specific         human capital. Analyses of data from the 1987&amp;#8212;1988 National Survey of Families and Households conducted in the United States         suggest that both of these effects play important roles in explaining the observed linkages between the religious composition         of unions and fertility behavior.      </content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>David C. Ribar1 </authors><title>The effects of teenage fertility on young adult childbearing      </title><content>Numerous studies of fertility behavior find that an early age at first birth increases the rate of subsequent childbearing.         Typically, however, these studies do not account for the possibility of serial correlation in the unobserved determinants         of fertility. Using 1979&amp;#8211;1992 individual-level data from the National Longitudinal Survey of Youth, this paper employs the         Method of Simulated Moments to estimate panel probit models of annual birth outcomes. The panel probit models account for         several alternative sources of serial correlation. Estimation reveals that once serial correlation is taken into account,         the subsequent fertility effects of early childbearing are either statistically eliminated or reversed.      </content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>Christian Dustmann1 </authors><title>The social assimilation of immigrants      </title><content>Although there is some considerable empirical research on the economic assimilation of migrants to the labor markets of the         host countries, little or no analysis exists on the social assimilation and integration of migrant workers. This is surprising         since the integration of migrants is not only of political importance, but it should strongly interact with their economic         behavior. This paper provides an empirical analysis of the determinants of migrants&amp;#8217; integration, using data for Germany.         Ordered probit models are estimated, where the dependent variable is an ordered response on the feeling of national identity.         The results show that personal characteristics, the nationality and the family context affect the migrant&amp;#8217;s integration, while         labor market variables appear to be quite unimportant.      </content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>John Broome1 </authors><title>The value of life and the value of population      </title><content>This paper first distinguishes structured and unstructured approaches to valuing life. The unstructured approach bases its         valuations on people&amp;#8217;s raw preferences, whereas the structured approach imposes a theoretical framework about the structure         of value. The paper recommends the structured approach. This opens the way to considering the value of adding people to the         population. The paper examines a common intuition that adding people is not in itself valuable, and explains the difficulties         this intuition encounters.      </content></document><document><year>1996</year><authors>Rainer Winkelmann1 </authors><title>Unskilled labor and wage determination: An empirical investigation for Germany      </title><content>This article contributes to the ongoing debate on native wage impacts of immigration. I propose a mobile-fixed factor distinction         as a framework in which to think about the differential impact of immigration on various labor market groups. Skilled workers         are treated as a fixed factor of production since the strong reliance on skill certification in Germany inhibits mobility         and shelters from competition. Unskilled workers, in contrast, receive competitive wages. Using data from the German Socio-Economic         Panel for 1984&amp;#8211;1989 I estimate panel wage regressions for groups of workers separated by skill certification. I find that         university graduates&amp;#8217; wages increase, and the wages of workers without postsecondary degree decrease, as the industry share         of unskilled workers increases. The effect for apprentices is ambiguous.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Jinkook Lee1  | Hyungsoo Kim2 </authors><title>A longitudinal analysis of the impact of health shocks on the wealth of elders      </title><content>We investigate the impact of health shocks on wealth, using all four waves of the Health and Retirement Study, and estimate         not only the short-term effect but also the long-term effect of health shocks on wealth of the elderly. We find that new health         events lower wealth in elders during the period in which such health shocks occur, but the impact tends to disappear over         time. We also find that health shocks result in greater wealth depletion when they occur later in life. Together with existing         health problems, the overall impact of health problems on wealth increases over time.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Martin Nordin1 </authors><title>Ability and rates of return to schooling&amp;#8212;making use of the Swedish enlistment battery test      </title><content>Using the Swedish military enlistment test, this paper estimates the return to schooling for individuals belonging to different         parts of the ability distribution. It also attempts to predict whether an endogenous test score causes bias in the &amp;#8220;ability-specific&amp;#8221;         returns to schooling that varies with the test score. A significant finding is that a higher score in the test is associated         with a higher return to schooling, but that the positive association is diminishing in the test score. In general, the bias         in the ability-specific returns to schooling does not seem to vary with the test score level.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors/></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>PГҐl Longva1 | OddbjГёrn Raaum2</authors><title>Earnings assimilation of immigrants in Norway &amp;#8211; A reappraisal      </title><content>Abstract.;; The relative earnings growth for immigrants in Norway is computed. Unlike Hayfron (1998, this journal) we define immigrants         by country of origin rather than citizenship and perform separate studies of immigrants from inside and outside the OECD region.         Replicating Hayfron op.cit. we find that the earnings assimilation is considerably weaker. Further, we find that the earnings         of OECD immigrants are comparable to those of natives, while Non-OECD immigrants earn considerably less than natives at the         time of entry, but that their relative earnings improve gradually over time. Earnings of different immigrant cohorts converged         from 1980 to 1990, indicating a non-linear rate of assimilation.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Helmuth Cremer1| Arnaud Dellis2 | Pierre Pestieau3</authors><title>Family size and optimal income taxation      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper studies the role of family size in the design of optimal income taxation. We consider a second best setting where         the government observes the number of children and the income of the parents but not their productivity. With a linear tax schedule the marginal tax rate is shown to decrease with the number of children, while the relationship between the demogrant         and family size appears to be ambiguous. With two ability levels, optimal non-linear income tax implies zero marginal tax rates for the higher ability parents; low ability parents have positive marginal tax rates that         decrease with family size.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>BegoГ±a ГЃlvarez1 | Daniel Miles1</authors><title>Gender effect on housework allocation: Evidence from Spanish two-earner couples      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper we study the reasons behind the asymmetric distribution of housework within Spanish two-earner couples. Spouses'         housework times are estimated jointly in a bivariate framework using data from the 1991 Work Situation and Time Use Survey.         In order to understand the impact of gender-specific factors on the observed allocation of housework, we perform estimations         that are in line with the Oaxaca decomposition. Our results suggest that the unequal division of domestic work between wives         and husbands in our sample is mainly explained by gender-specific effects rather than by differences in their observable characteristics.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Gianna Claudia Giannelli1 | Chiara Monfardini2</authors><title>Joint decisions on household membership and human capital accumulation of youths. The role of expected earnings and local         markets      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper analyses the effects of expected earnings and local markets conditions on the behaviour of young adults with high         school diplomas. Decisions to either remain in the parental home or form a new household are modelled jointly with those of         either gaining work experience or investing in a university education. Expected lifetime earnings are found to play a crucial         role in determining the choice of studying and residing with parents. Poor labour market opportunities discourage young people         from working and induce them to study. The cost of housing greatly influences the choice of working and leaving the parental         home.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Manon Domingues Dos Santos1 | Fabien Postel-Vinay2</authors><title>Migration as a source of growth: The perspective of a developing country      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper analyses the dynamics of migratory flows and growth in a developing economy. We show that when workers freely         choose their location, some natives can rationally decide to return to their home country after they have accumulated a certain         amount of knowledge abroad, while some prefer to stay permanently in the same economy (either at home or abroad). We point         out that worker mobility can have an expansionary effect on the developing economy. Moreover, we show that in the long-run,         as the sending economy develops, fewer natives are likely to emigrate and more migrants are likely to return.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>R. Rees1| John Komlos1| Ngo V. Long2 | Ulrich Woitek3</authors><title>Optimal food allocation in a slave economy      </title><content>Abstract.;; We propose a model of food allocation in an economy in which property rights exist in human beings. We assume that a slave-owner         allocates food over the slave's lifetime so as to maximise his own wealth. The slave's productive capacity is determined endogenously         by food consumption. Food allotment during childhood and adolescence determines productive capacity over the life course.         The slave owner chooses optimal time paths of food allotment in light of the contribution food makes to both the level and         growth of physical capacity, as a function of the price of food and of the value of the slave's productivity. Though conceived         for an economy in which property rights exist in human beings, the model can be modified so as to apply to resource allocation         within a household economy in which parents provide both nourishment and schooling for their children, in order to enhance         their current or future productivity.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Antoine Bommier1 | Ronald D. Lee2</authors><title>Overlapping generations models with realistic demography      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper revisits the literature on overlapping generations models in the demographic context of a continuous age distribution         and a general age schedule of mortality. We show that most of the static results known for the 3 or N age-group models can be extended to the continuous model. Some results, previously established for economies without capital,         are extended to productive economies. We also make some progress on the existence of some steady states as well as on the         dynamic properties.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Andreas Wagener1</authors><title>Pensions as a portfolio problem: fixed contribution rates vs. fixed replacement rates reconsidered      </title><content>Abstract.;; Pay-as-you-go (PAYG) pension schemes can contribute to better intergenerational risk-sharing and diversification. However,         different variants of PAYG schemes entail different properties in these respects. In a stochastic 2-OLG model we compare PAYG         schemes with fixed contribution rates and such with fixed replacement rates. The literature has shown that the former are         preferable to the later from an ex ante perspective. We derive the opposite result for the ex post perspective. Here, schemes with fixed replacement rates are unambiguously preferable: they enhance intergenerational risk-sharing,         lead to a higher savings and higher utility levels. We further show that, from an ex ante (veil-of-ignorance), perspective both schemes are non-comparable if the effect that fixed-replacement schemes serve as an         insurance device for old-age income is properly accounted for.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Pietro Senesi1</authors><title>Population dynamics and life-cycle consumption      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper presents a model where aggregate consumption depends on both the level of wealth and the age structure of population.         The explicit consideration of an endogenous rate of time preference permits to analyze the important role of population ageing         as a determinant of aggregate saving.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Shuanglin Lin1 | Xiaowen Tian2</authors><title>Population growth and social security financing      </title><content>Abstract.;; By allowing the population growth to be flexible, this paper analyzes the effect of a tax reform that involves an introduction         of consumption taxation for social security financing. It is found that population growth and labor supply play an important         role in determining the effect of the tax reform. If population growth and labor supply are exogenous, then an introduction         of a consumption tax for social security financing, with the payroll tax rate being endogenous, decreases the interest rate         and increases capital accumulation. However, if population growth and labor supply are endogenous, then an introduction of         a consumption tax for social security financing increases the interest rate and reduces capital accumulation.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Anh Ngoc Nguyen1 | Jim Taylor1</authors><title>Post-high school choices: New evidence from a multinomial logit model      </title><content>Abstract.;; A multinomial logit model is estimated to investigate the destination of students one-year after graduating from high school.         The appropriate specification of the choice set available to high school leavers is as follows: private four-year college,         public four-year college, private two-year college, public two-year college, employed and unemployed. We test for several         possible combinations of these choices and find that these pooled models are all rejected in favour of the full model. The         transition from high school to college and to work is more complex than previous studies have recognised.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Kazutoshi Miyazawa1</authors><title>Private versus public financing of education and endogenous growth: A comment on BrГ¤uninger and Vidal      </title><content>Abstract.;; This note shows that the long-run effect in the case of a low skill trap in BrГ¤uninger and Vidal (Journal of Population Economics         (2000) 13:387&amp;#8211;401) contains a mistake. While not affecting the paper's basic intuition, this implies that the discussion in         the short-run analysis also applies in the long-run.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Leonor Modesto1</authors><title>Should I stay or should I go? Educational choices and earnings: An empirical study for Portugal      </title><content>Abstract.;; We analyse educational choices and earnings of individuals at two different levels in the Portuguese educational system.         At each exit we consider two decisions: the decision to continue studying and the employment decision. We find empirical support         for the existence of selectivity bias as the errors of the earnings functions are in general correlated with the disturbances         of the decision functions. The obtained rates of return to education vary between 2.4 and 9.4 percent, depending on whether         or not selectivity and quantity effects are excluded from the computations. Note that selectivity represents three quarters         of this difference.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors> </authors><title>Sixteenth ESPE Conference and General Assembly in Bilbao 2002      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Tetsuo Ono1</authors><title>Social security policy with public debt in an aging economy      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper analyzes a social security policy with public debt in an overlapping generations growth model. In particular,         the paper considers a situation in which population aging causes a heavy burden of social security payments where public debt         is issued by the government to finance the payment. In the model presented below, an economy with an aging population may         achieve two dynamically inefficient equilibria. Under certain conditions, the effects of pension reform and population aging         on capital accumulation are entirely different between the two equilibria.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Hans Fehr1| Wenche IrГ©n Sterkeby2 | Г&#152;ystein ThГёgersen3</authors><title>Social security reforms and early retirement      </title><content>Abstract.;; Many reform proposals of the social security systems in various OECD economies suggest to scale down the non-actuarial parts         of the pension systems. These reforms have a flavor of increased efficiency at the costs of welfare losses for low-income         individuals. Assessing the economic effects, we investigate five different reform proposals by means of a numerical overlapping         generations model for the Norwegian economy. The model features an endogenous retirement age and heterogeneous individuals         within generations. It turns out that the various reforms, which scale down the public non-actuarial pension system, lead         to increases in the retirement age and steady-state welfare gains for all income classes.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Arnaud Chevalier1| Tarja K. Viitanen1 | Tarja K. Viitanen2</authors><title>The long-run labour market consequences of teenage motherhood in Britain      </title><content>Abstract.;; Common wisdom states that teenage childbearing reduces schooling, labour market experience and adult wages. However, the         decisions to be a teenage mother, to quit school, and be less attached to the labour market might all stem from some personal         or family characteristics.                     &amp;#8195;Using the National Child Development Study (NCDS), we find that in Britain teenage childbearing decreases the probability               of post-16 schooling by 12&amp;#8211;24%. Employment experience is reduced by up to three years, and the adult pay differential ranges               from 5% to 22%. The negative impact of teen motherhood on various adult outcomes is not only due to some pre-motherhood characteristics;               hence policies aiming to encourage return to school and participation in the labour market may be an efficient way to reduce               the long-term consequences of teenage pregnancy.            </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Irwin Garfinkel1| Chien-Chung Huang2| Sara S. McLanahan3 | Daniel S. Gaylin4</authors><title>The roles of child support enforcement and welfare in non-marital childbearing      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper examines the effects of stronger child support enforcement and declines in welfare benefits on changes in non-marital         childbearing between 1980 and 1996. Economic theory suggests that stricter child support enforcement will increase the costs         of children for unwed fathers, making them less likely to have a child outside marriage. Reductions in welfare benefits also         are expected to increase the costs of non-marital childbearing for both mothers and fathers. We examine these hypotheses,         using aggregate state-level data and fixed effects regression models to identify the effects of policies on non-marital birth         rates. We find that both stricter child support enforcement and declines in welfare benefits deter non-marital births. However,         the estimated effects of child support enforcement are more robust and larger than those of welfare. The estimates imply that         in the 1980&amp;#8211;1996 period, increases in child support enforcement led to a decline in non-marital birth rates in the range of         6% to 9%, whereas decreases in welfare benefits led to a decline in the range of 2% to 4%.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Daniel Hallberg1 | Anders Klevmarken1</authors><title>Time for children: A study of parent's time allocation      </title><content>Abstract.;; The trade-off between parents' time with their own kids and market work, and its dependence on out-of-home day care is analyzed         in a simultaneous equation framework. Economic incentives primarily work through decisions about market work, while the direct         effects on time with children are weak. The results suggest that a change in the mother's working hours has less influence         on the parents' time with their children than a change in the father's working hours. This would imply that a policy working         to increase the time with people's own children should primarily influence the father's work hours. We also find that parents         prefer joint activities with their children, and that out-of-home child care is not chosen as a substitute for own time with         children.      </content></document><document><year>2003</year><authors>Dan Anderberg1</authors><title>Voluntary income sharing and the design of unemployment insurance      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper uses a model of search unemployment to discuss the interaction between publicly provided insurance and informal         insurance through voluntary income sharing, e.g., between spouses. Income sharing reduces the optimal level of public unemployment         insurance. While it is always individually rational for partners to share income, the effect of voluntary income sharing on         welfare will be negative unless partners can either observe each other's search behavior or are sufficiently altruistic towards         each other. The model is also used to examine a family-based policy. The welfare gains from using such policy are argued to         be small.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>James R. Walker1</authors><title>A Comment on Ali Tas&amp;#731;&amp;#305;ran's `Wage and income effects on the timing and spacing of births in Sweden and in the United States'      </title><content>Abstract.;; This note reviews and evaluates Ta&amp;#351;&amp;#305;ran's (1995) claim that estimated female wage effects on Swedish fertility dynamics reported         by Heckman and Walker (1990) are not robust to the use of microwage data. The results reported here indicate that once individual         wage measures have been purged of measurement error, estimated female wage effects are not sensitive to the introduction of         microwages. The results reported by Heckman and Walker (1990) persist even with the use of microwage data.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Namkee Ahn1 | Pedro Mira2</authors><title>A note on the changing relationship between fertility and female employment rates in developed countries      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper we look at a panel of OECD aggregate fertility and labor market data between 1970 and 1995 and we report some         striking recent developments. Total Fertility Rates (TFR) were falling and Female Participation Rates (FPR) were increasing,         conforming to a well known long-run trend. Along the cross-sectional dimension, the correlation between TFR and FPR was negative         and significant during the 1970's and up to the early 1980's. This seemed consistent with secular comovements. However, by         the late 1980's the correlation had become positive and equally significant. We discuss our findings within the framework         of standard neoclassical models of fertility and labor supply adapted to macro data, as in Butz and Ward (1979).      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Ali C. Ta&amp;#351 iran1</authors><title>A reply to Walker&amp;#8217;s note: A comment on Ta&amp;#351;iran&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Wage and income effects on the timing and spacing of births in Sweden and         in the United States&amp;#8217;      </title><content>Abstract.;; Walker (1997) criticizes one of the conclusions in my book TasВё\iran (1995), that Heckman and Walker&amp;#8217;s very high negative         wage rate and positive income effects on Swedish fertility are very sensitive. In this paper, I explain, first, that my results         are not only based on the series Walker mentions, but also on other series in both SFS and HUS data sets. Second, the combined         aggregate and micro wage series he criticizes is mainly derived with Heckman and Walker. Third, by discussing the points he         raises for the combination strategy, I show that his revised results are also supporting my conclusion.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Peter Kuhn1 | Arthur Sweetman2</authors><title>Aboriginals as unwilling immigrants: Contact, assimilation and labour market outcomes      </title><content>Abstract.;; Like immigrants, aboriginal populations' economic success may be enhanced by the acquisition of skills and traits appropriate         to the &amp;#8220;majority&amp;#8221; culture in which they reside. Using 1991 Canadian Census data, we show that Aboriginal labour market success         is greater for Aboriginals whose ancestors intermarried with non-Aboriginals, for those who live off Indian reserves, and         for those who live outside the Yukon and Northwest Territories. While these three &amp;#8220;facts&amp;#8221; could also be explained by a combination         of other processes, such as discrimination, physical remoteness, and selection, only the skill/trait acquisition, or &amp;#8220;assimilation&amp;#8221;         hypothesis is consistent with all three.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors> </authors><title>Acknowledgement to editorial collaborators      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Irwin Garfinkel1| Dana Glei2 | Sara S. McLanahan3</authors><title>Assortative mating among unmarried parents: Implications for ability to pay child support      </title><content>Abstract.;; Assortative mating is of interest to both theoretical and applied social scientists. Previous research is based almost entirely         on married couples and parents. In this paper we use data from the NSFG to examine assortative mating among unmarried parents         in the US and to examine the robustness of estimates of nonresident fathers' income based on assortative mating assumptions.         We find that never married parents are similar, though not identical, to married parents in their choice of partners. White         unmarried women are much more likely to have a child with a non-white male than white married women. On the other hand, unmarried         women are more likely than married women to have a child with a more educated male.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Huei-Chung Lu1| Mingshen Chen2 | C. Y. Cyrus Chu3</authors><title>Bequest division and population growth: A lineal extinction probability approach      </title><content>Abstract.;; This study uses a lineal-extinction-probability-minimization approach proposed by Chu (1991) to study the relation between bequest division and population growth. Using a Markov branching process         and &amp;#8220;first-degree stochastic dominance&amp;#8221; technique, our model's results imply that any specific bequest division, primogeniture         or equal divisions, does not necessarily increase or reduce the population growth by itself. Whether the population does grow,         or by how much, will be determined by the concurrent social-economic conditions. We find that if all family heads faced an         increasing MRTS technology and/or a relatively unfair market chance, then they would tend to choose an unequal division as their optimal bequest policy, and population growth would increase. However, if an equal         division was adopted involuntarily by family heads or was enforced by laws, then the population growth might decline.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Anders BjГ¶rklund1| Tor Eriksson2| Markus JГ¤ntti3| OddbjГ¶rn Raaum4 | Eva Г–sterbacka5</authors><title>Brother correlations in earnings in Denmark, Finland, Norway and Sweden compared to the United States      </title><content>Abstract.;; The correlation in economic status among siblings is a useful &amp;#8220;omnibus measure&amp;#8221; of the overall impact of family and community         factors on adult economic status. In this study we compare brother correlations in long-run (permanent) earnings between the         United States, on one hand, and the Nordic countries (Denmark, Finland, Norway and Sweden) on the other. Our base case results,         based on very similar sample criteria and definitions for all countries, show that this correlation is above 0.40 in the United         States and in the range 0.14&amp;#8211;0.26 in the Nordic countries. Even though these results turn out to be somewhat sensitive to         some assumptions that have to be made, we conclude that the family and community factors are more important determinants of         long-run earnings in the United States than in the Nordic countries.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Gordon H. Clevel|1 | Douglas E. Hyatt2</authors><title>Child care workers' wages: New evidence on returns to education, experience, job tenure and auspice      </title><content>Abstract.;; Child care workers receive low hourly pay, modest returns to education, experience and job tenure, and have high rates of         turnover. These stylized facts have caused analysts to characterize child care workers as secondary labour market participants.         We use Canadian data to challenge this characterization and to examine the disputed effects of auspice (non-profit vs. for-profit         status) on wages. In contrast to Mocan and Viola (1997), improved controls for the differential availability of resources         and firm size do not make the positive wage effects experienced by workers in non-profit day care centres disappear.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Jane Waldfogel1</authors><title>Child care, women's employment, and child outcomes      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper reviews the evidence on the impact of child care and maternal employment in the pre-school years on child outcomes.         This topic has long been of interest to economists, developmental psychologists, and scholars from other disciplines, and         has been the focus of increased attention in recent years, as research has provided additional evidence about the processes         of development in the earliest days, weeks, and years of life.1                                       &amp;#8195;In this paper, I review the evidence on two broad sets of questions: what we know about the potential benefits of early intervention               child care programs, and what we know about the effects (whether positive or negative) of maternal employment and child care               in the first years of life. The evidence reviewed in this paper suggests that we now know a good deal about both sets of questions.               But, this review also suggests that there are important gaps in our knowledge that future work by economists could fruitfully               address.            </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Andrew McCulloch1 | Heather E. Joshi2</authors><title>Child development and family resources: Evidence from the second generation of the 1958 British birth cohort      </title><content>Abstract.;; Studies of American and recently British children suggest that there is a link between family income and child development,         in particular that one consequence of child poverty is to hold back cognitive development. This paper investigates the impact         of family income, material deprivation, maternal education and child-rearing behaviour on an indicator of cognitive functioning,         using British data on children aged 6 to 17 whose mothers are members of the 1958 Birth Cohort Study. The poorer average cognitive         functioning among children from the lowest income groups could largely be accounted for, statistically, by the greater material         disadvantage of these groups. These analyses provide evidence to suggest that low income has detrimental effects on children's         cognitive functioning through the operation of longer-term material disadvantage, and that these effects may be mitigated         by positive parental behaviours.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>George Hondroyiannis1 | Evangelia Papapetrou2</authors><title>Demographic transition and economic growth: Empirical evidence from Greece      </title><content>Abstract.;; Over the past decades, due to a combination of declining fertility rates and rising life expectancies, most industrialized         countries have experienced aging populations and low numbers of young populations that may pose economic problems in the future.         This paper investigates the relationship first between fertility rate and infant mortality rate and second among demographic         changes, real wages and real output in Greece over the period 1960&amp;#8211;96. When we control for fluctuations in overall economic         activity and the labor market on the bivariate relationship between fertility and mortality rates, the evidence suggests that         Granger-causation must exist in at least one direction. The results show that in the long run a decrease in infant mortality         rates, taking into consideration economic performance and the labor market, causes a reduction in fertility rates. Also, employing         the vector error-correction models, the variance decomposition analysis and the impulse response functions, the empirical         results support the endogeneity of fertility choice to infant mortality, the labor market and the growth process.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Gerard J. van den Berg1| Anders Holm2 | Jan C. van Ours3</authors><title>Do stepping-stone jobs exist? Early career paths in the medical profession      </title><content>Abstract.;; In the Netherlands, students who want to become a medical specialist have to enrol in a training program which is in limited         supply. During the search for a position as trainee (or &amp;#8220;junior medical specialist&amp;#8221;), they may accept a temporary job as a         medical assistant. We use a micro data set to investigate whether such work experience increases the probability of becoming         junior medical specialist. To deal with selectivity, we simultaneously model the transitions from unemployment to trainee,         from unemployment to medical assistant, from medical assistant to trainee and from medical assistant to unemployment. We find         that a job as medical assistant helps to become a medical specialist.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors> </authors><title>EditorialВ¶Symposium on &amp;#8220;Child care&amp;#8221;      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Linda Adair1| David Guilkey1| Eilene Bisgrove2 | Socorro Gultiano3</authors><title>Effect of childbearing on Filipino women's work hours and earnings      </title><content>Abstract.;; The effects of childbearing and work sector on women's hours and earnings in the 8 years following an index pregnancy were         examined in a cohort of more than 2,000 women in the Cebu Longitudinal Health and Nutrition Survey. Change in cash earnings         and hours worked were each modeled jointly with sector of labor force participation using an estimation strategy that deals         with endogeneity of childbearing decisions and selectivity into sector of work. Two or more additional children born in the         8 year interval significantly reduced women's earnings, while having an additional child under 2 years of age in 1991 reduced         hours worked.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Charles Michalopoulos1 | Philip K. Robins2</authors><title>Employment and child-care choices of single-parent families in Canada and the United States      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper examines employment and child-care choices of single-parent families with young children in the United States         and Canada, using a pooled data set based on recent national surveys in each country. We find that the employment and child-care         choices of Canadian families are similar to those of U.S. families. Estimates of a model of employment and child-care choices         indicate significant effects of child-care subsidies, child-care prices, and wage rates on employment and child-care choices.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Kenneth Clark1 | Stephen Drinkwater2</authors><title>Enclaves, neighbourhood effects and employment outcomes: Ethnic minorities in England and Wales      </title><content>Abstract.;; Ethnic minorities in England and Wales are spatially concentrated in relatively-deprived urban areas. Both geographic clustering         and the economic characteristics of ethnically-concentrated neighbourhoods can impact upon the opportunities and constraints         facing residents of such areas. This paper explores the relationship between the existence of enclaves and the employment         prospects of ethnic minorities in England and Wales. It is shown that there is considerable spatial variation in employment         outcomes. There is a lower incidence of self-employment in more ethnically-concentrated urban areas, which contradicts the         view of ethnic entrepreneurship as an enclave phenomenon. Unemployment rates are also higher for minorities living in more         concentrated areas. Enclaves in England and Wales do not appear to offer many economic benefits to minority individuals.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Barry R. Chiswick1 | Paul W. Miller2</authors><title>Immigrant earnings: Language skills, linguistic concentrations and the business cycle      </title><content>Abstract.;; This study of the determinants of earnings among adult foreign-born men using the 1990 Census of Population focuses on the         effects of the respondent's own English language skills, the effects of living in a linguistic concentration area, and the         effects of the stage of the business cycle at entry into the U.S. labor market. The analysis demonstrates the importance of         English language fluency among the foreign born from non-English speaking countries. There is also strong evidence for the         complementarity between language skills and other forms of human capital. Furthermore, there is strong evidence using selectivity         correction techniques for the endogeneity between language and earnings.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors> </authors><title>Jacob Mincer receives IZA Prize in Labor Economics      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors> </authors><title>Kuznets Prize for David C. Ribar      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Magnus Lofstrom1</authors><title>Labor market assimilation and the self-employment decision of immigrant entrepreneurs      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper uses data from the 1980 and 1990 U.S. Censuses to study labor market assimilation of self-employed immigrants.         Separate earnings functions for the self-employed and wage/salary workers are estimated. To control for endogenous sorting         into the sectors, models of the self-employment decision are estimated. Self-employed immigrants are found to do substantially         better in the labor market than wage/salary immigrants. Earnings of self-employed immigrants are predicted to converge with         natives' wage/salary earnings at about age 30 and natives' self-employed earnings at about age 40. Including the self-employed         in the sample reduces the immigrant-native earnings gap by, on average, 14%.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Olympia Bover1 | Manuel Arellano2</authors><title>Learning about migration decisions from the migrants: Using complementary datasets to model intra-regional migrations in Spain      </title><content>Abstract.;; We investigate the determinants of the remarkable increase in intra-regional migrations since the 1980's in Spain, using         a large administrative micro dataset on migrants. Conditional migration probabilities are identified by comparing the migrants'         joint distribution of characteristics to the corresponding distribution from the Spanish Labour Force Survey. The proportion         of employment in the service industry, unemployment, house prices and education, all have an important positive effect on         the individual probabilities of intra-regional migration.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Ronald Lee1 | Michael Anderson2</authors><title>Malthus in state space: Macro economic-demographic relations in English history, 1540 to 1870      </title><content>. The history of preindustrial Europe provides an opportunity to examine the causes and consequences of population change         at a macro level. However, serious statistical problems arise from the endogeneity of all observed variables in a Malthusian         system (fertility, mortality, population size, and real wages), and from unobserved influences such as shifts in the demand         for labor and variations in health. These problems have undermined both informal inference from the data and more complex         econometric investigations. This paper takes a new statistical approach, finding the maximum likelihood estimate of a state         space representation of the Malthusian system by repeated application of Kalman filter methods, using annual data from England,         1540 to 1870. The new estimates confirm some findings of the earlier literature and contradict others. Some variables are         estimated for the first time. Implications are discussed for the interpretation of English economic-demographic history.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Ulrich Kohli1</authors><title>Migration and foreign trade: Further results      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this note, we use the production-theory approach to immigration in an open-economy setting to investigate the role of         nonresident workers in Swiss aggregate production. Unlike earlier work in this area, exports are explicitly taken into account.         Indeed, a statistical test for global separability between inputs and outputs reveals that exports and products intended for         domestic use cannot be aggregated. Our results show that immigration tends to stimulate imports and to shift the output mix         towards nontraded goods, thereby impacting negatively on the trade account.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Timothy J. Hatton1 | Roy E. Bailey1</authors><title>Natives and migrants in the London labour market, 1929&amp;#8211;1931      </title><content>Abstract.;; Migrants are sometimes regarded as marginal workers in metropolitan labour markets. London has long been a major destination         for migrants from elsewhere in Britain and abroad. In this paper we examine the earnings and unemployment experience in 1929&amp;#8211;1931         of male workers who migrated to London, or within London. We use data from the New Survey of London Life and Labour, a large survey of working class households, the records from which have recently been computerised. Our findings indicate         that migrants were not marginal, in fact they enjoyed slightly higher earnings and lower unemployment incidence than native         Londoners. Much of the advantage can be explained by differences in average skill levels and personal characteristics.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Bertr| Crettez1 | Patricia Le Maitre2</authors><title>Optimal age of retirement and population growth      </title><content>Abstract.;; The purpose of this paper is to study intergenerational optimal resources sharing when the social planer can choose the retirement         age in addition to consumptions and investment. We use the extension of the Diamond analysis by Hu [1979] that incorporates         endogenous retirement age. We found that the optimal retirement age is an increasing function of the population growth rate         if the elasticity of substitution of old agents' labor for young agents' labor is lower than one. In the millian case, when         the size of a population does not matter, and when the elasticity of substitution of old agents' labor for young agents' labor         is strictly higher than one, the optimal retirement age is a decreasing function of the population growth rate. In the benthamite         case, the change in the optimal retirement age is indeterminate.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Eli Feinerman1 | Edward J. Seiler2</authors><title>Private transfers with incomplete information: A contribution to the &amp;#8220;altruism-exchange motivation for transfers&amp;#8221; debate      </title><content>Abstract.;; We examine the role of altruism in determining optimal transfers from a principal (a mother) to selfish agents (her children)         in return for attention services. Transfer-attention contracts are studied in a setting in which informational asymmetries         arise from the inability of a parent to determine the extent of her children's selfishness. We find a predominating exchange         motive for transfers in the symmetric informational regime we study. However, both altruism and exchange are important motives         under asymmetric information. We show that altruism facilitates transfer-attention exchange arrangements with certain trade         partners under incomplete information, but diminishes trade with others.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Regina T. Riphahn1</authors><title>Residential location and youth unemployment: The economic geography of school-to-work transitions      </title><content>Abstract.;; In response to increased international policy attention to youth unemployment this study investigates post-secondary school         transitions of school leavers. Multinomial logit models are estimated for male and female German youth. The models control         for individual, parent, and household characteristics, for those of the youth's region of residence and local labor markets.         The findings suggest that immigrant youth has particularly low participation rates in continued education, and that youth         unemployment is centered in high unemployment states and metropolitan areas. More generous academic benefit policies seem         to be correlated with increased academic enrollment, and men's transitions to the military do reflect recent changes in defense         policies.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Michael J. Brien1| Gregory E. Loya2 | John V. Pepper3</authors><title>Teenage childbearing and cognitive development      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper we examine how having a child as a teen affects the cognitive development of young women as measured on standardized         tests. The research in this paper makes use of the National Education Longitudinal Study of 1988, a biennial survey that contains         information on a cohort of young women from the time they were in the 8th grade in 1988 until, the latest wave, 1994. By observing         two test scores before a woman has a child and one test score after, we can control for both the level and growth in test         scores experienced prior to childbirth. The results indicate that although teenage mothers have lower cognitive test scores         than their counterparts without children, the effects of childbearing itself are negligible.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Maite MartГ­nez-Granado1 | Javier Ruiz-Castillo1</authors><title>The decisions of Spanish youth: A cross-section study      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper presents a simultaneous model for the joint decisions of working, studying and leaving the parental household         by young people in Spain. Using cross-section data from the 1990&amp;#8211;1991 Encuesta de Presupuestos Familiares, the model is estimated by a two stage estimation method. Endogeneity of the three decisions proves to be important in order         to understand the dynamics of household formation. Our results also confirm a number of plausible intuitions about the effect         of individual characteristics and economic variables on these decisions, and provide some new insights into the reasons for         young people in Spain remaining in large numbers in the parental home. Most of the results are gender independent.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Jutta M. Joesch1 | Bridget G. Hiedemann2</authors><title>The demand for nonrelative child care among families with infants and toddlers: A double-hurdle approach      </title><content>Abstract.;; Despite the increasing prevalence of nonparental child care, many parents in the United States care exclusively for their         young children, even when both parents work. We examine reasons for non-consumption of child care by estimating double-hurdle,         tobit and dominance models of the demand for nonrelative child care. Our results indicate that parents' decision whether to         use any nonrelative child care is guided by different considerations than the decision of how much care to use. Furthermore,         our findings are consistent with the hypothesis that some parents are not interested in nonrelative care, regardless of its         price or nonmaternal income.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Daniela Del Boca1</authors><title>The effect of child care and part time opportunities on participation and fertility decisions in Italy      </title><content>Abstract.;; Economic models of household behavior typically yield the prediction that increases in schooling levels and wage rates of         married women lead to increases in their labor supply and reductions in fertility. In Italy, low labor market participation         rates of married women are observed together with low birth rates. Our explanation involves the Italian institutional structure,         particularly as reflected in rigidities and imperfections in the labor market and characteristics of the publicly-funded child         care system. These rigidities tend to simultaneously increase the costs of having children and to discourage the labor market         participation of married women. We analyze a model of labor supply and fertility, using panel data. The empirical results         show that the availability of child care and part time work increase both the probability of working and having a child.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Mukesh Eswaran1</authors><title>The empowerment of women, fertility, and child mortality: Towards a theoretical analysis      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper examines one avenue through which female autonomy impinges on fertility and child mortality in developing countries.         A simple model is set out in which couples are motivated to have children for old age security purposes. The decisions of         a couple regarding fertility and allocation of resources for the healthcare of their children are made within a bargaining         framework. An increase in female autonomy translating into an increase in the relative bargaining power or the threat point         utility of mothers is shown to reduce fertility and also to reduce child mortality rates. Paradoxically, the increase in female         autonomy within a household may increase the disadvantage suffered by female children in that household with respect to survival.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Michael A. Shields1 | Stephen Wheatley Price1</authors><title>The English language fluency and occupational success of ethnic minority immigrant men living in English metropolitan areas      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper examines two crucial aspects of the assimilation experience of ethnic minority immigrants in the United Kingdom.         It explores the determinants of their English language (speaking) fluency and the key role such skills play in their occupational         success. Our sample is derived from the Fourth National Survey of Ethnic Minorities undertaken in 1994. Uniquely this data         contains an interviewer-assessed measure of English language fluency. Importantly, we also attempt to control for possible         endogeneity bias in the estimates of the effect of language fluency on occupational success. We find that fluency is associated         with significantly higher mean hourly occupational wages.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Richard Davies1| Eskil Heinesen2 | Anders Holm3</authors><title>The relative risk aversion hypothesis of educational choice      </title><content>Abstract.;; Analysing young people's educational choices, we derive and test implications of a relative risk aversion hypothesis: that         educational choices are made so as to minimize the risk of ending up with a lower level of education than one's parents. These         implications are in general different from what one would expect from human capital theory. We use a unique data set which         combines data from administrative registers on young people's pathways through the educational system and their family background         with survey data on their academic abilities at lower secondary school. The evidence is partly in favour of the relative risk         aversion hypothesis.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Daniel S. Hamermesh1</authors><title>Timing, togetherness and time windfalls      </title><content>Abstract.;; With appropriate data the analysis of time use, labor supply and leisure can move beyond the standard questions of wage and         income elasticities of hours supplied. I present four examples: 1) American data from 1973 through 1997 show that the amount         of evening and night work in the U.S. has decreased. 2) The same data demonstrate that workers whose relative earnings increase         experience a relative diminution of the burden of work at unpleasant times. 3) U.S. data for the 1970s and 1990s demonstrate         that spouses' work schedules are more synchronized than would occur randomly; synchrony among working spouses diminished after         the 1970s; and the full-income elasticity of demand for it was higher among wives than among husbands in the 1970s but equal         in the 1990s. 4) Dutch time-budget data for 1990 show that the overwhelming majority of the windfall hour that occurred when         standard time resumed was used for extra sleep.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>James P. Smith1| Duncan Thomas2| Elizabeth Frankenberg1| Kathleen Beegle1 | Graciela Teruel3</authors><title>Wages, employment and economic shocks: Evidence from Indonesia      </title><content>Abstract.;; After over a quarter century of sustained economic growth, Indonesia was struck by a large and unanticipated crisis at the         end of the 20th Century. Real GDP declined by about 12% in 1998. Using 13 years of annual labor force data in conjunction         with two waves of a household panel, the Indonesia Family Life Survey (IFLS), this paper examines the impact of the crisis         on labor market outcomes.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Michael Lundholm1 | Henry Ohlsson2</authors><title>Who takes care of the children? The quantity-quality model revisited      </title><content>Abstract.;; We study the Becker and Lewis (1973) quantity-quality model of children adding an explicit child care time constraint for         parents. Parents can take care of the children themselves or purchase day care. Our results are: (i) If there only is own         care, a quantity-quality trade-off, different from that of Becker and Lewis (1973), arises. The income effect on fertility         is positive if child quantity is a closer complement than child quality to the consumption of goods. (ii) If, instead, there         is a combination of purchased and own care, the effect of income on fertility is ambiguous, even if quantity of children is         a normal good in the standard sense. This is the Becker and Lewis (1973) result extended to a situation with a binding child         care time constraint. The conclusion is that the Becker and Lewis (1973) result holds as long as at least some child care         is purchased.      </content></document><document><year>2002</year><authors>Padma Rao Sahib1 | Xinhua Gu2</authors><title>&amp;#8220;Living in sin&amp;#8221; and marriage: A matching model      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper develops a two sided matching model of premarital cohabitation and marriage in which premarital cohabitation serves         as a period of learning. We solve for the optimal policy to be followed by individuals by treating the model as a three stage         dynamic programming problem. We find that couples are more discriminating when forming marital unions than when forming cohabiting         unions. Cohabitation unions arise among members of the same &amp;#8220;class&amp;#8221; and there is overlap between the classes formed by marital         unions and cohabiting unions. This implies that some cohabiting unions progress to marriage while others do not, a finding         borne out by empirical studies.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>J.M.C. Santos Silva1 | Francisco Covas2</authors><title>A modified hurdle model for completed fertility      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper it is argued that models for completed fertility have to take into consideration that childless couples and         couples with an only child are qualitatively different from couples with two or more children. Indeed, these differences may         be the cause of the underdispersion that characterizes completed fertility data. An empirical illustration using Portuguese         data suggests that accounting for the qualitative difference between having zero, one, or more children leads to considerable         improvements over a model of the type generally used to describe this sort of data.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Eric R. Eide1 | Mark H. Showalter1</authors><title>A note on the rate of intergenerational convergence of earnings      </title><content>Abstract.;; We show that &amp;#8220;convergence&amp;#8221; to mean earnings in intergenerational earnings mobility models will be a function not only of         the single-generation correlation of earnings, but also of the properties of the unobserved stochastic distribution of shocks         to earnings.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Damien Gaumont1 | Alice Mesnard2</authors><title>Altruism and international labour migration      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper investigates the effect of altruism on the pattern of labour migration in a two-country overlapping generations         model. We show that differences in degrees of altruism across countries lead to bilateral migration flows. Starting from the         autarkic steady-state equilibrium, restrictions on labour migration are relaxed. In temporary post-migration equilibrium factor         prices are equal across countries. We then characterize the unique stable steady-state equilibrium: both countries are populated         and this equilibrium is not a Pareto improvement. Some individuals prefer to live in autarky, others in an integrated world         economy.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Ranjan Ray1</authors><title>Analysis of child labour in Peru and Pakistan: A comparative study      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper analyses child labour participation and its key determinants using data sets from Peru and Pakistan. The results         include tests of the &amp;#8216;Luxury&amp;#8217; and &amp;#8216;Substitution&amp;#8217; hypotheses that play key roles in recent studies on child labour and child         schooling. The results reject both hypotheses in the context of child labour in Pakistan and suggest that income and related         variables do not have the expected negative effect on children's work input. Rising wages of adult female labour in Pakistan,         and falling adult male wage in Peru lead to increased participation of children in the labour market. The results on the combined         country data formally establish the presence of strong individual country effects in the estimated regressions. For example,         ceteris paribus, a Peruvian child is more likely to experience schooling than a Pakistani child. However, both countries agree on the positive         role that adult female education and infrastructure investment in basic amenities can play in discouraging child labour and         encouraging child schooling.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>BjГ¶rn Gustafsson1 | Shi Li2</authors><title>Economic transformation and the gender earnings gap in urban China      </title><content>Abstract.;; The gender wage gap and its development in urban China is analysed utilising two large scale surveys covering 10 provinces         for the years 1988 and 1995. The results indicate that from an international perspective, the gender wage gap in urban China         appears to be relatively small. It is, however, increasing. Decompositions based on estimated regression-models show that         somewhat less than half of the average gender wage gap can be attributed to differences in variables but much less of its         increase. The earnings situation of young women and women with limited education has especially deteriorated if compared to         men having the same characteristics.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors> </authors><title>Editorial                  Symposium on fertility studies using count data methods</title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>David de la Croix1 | Philippe Monfort2</authors><title>Education funding and regional convergence      </title><content>Abstract.;; The aim of this paper is to discuss the process of regional convergence within the framework of an overlapping generations         model in which the engine of growth is the accumulation of human capital. In particular, we consider different education funding         systems and compare their performance in terms of growth rates and pace of convergence between two heterogeneous regions.         The analysis suggests that the choice of a particular education system incorporates a possible trade-off between long run         growth rate and short run convergence. In such choice, the initial capital stock and the extent of regional human capital         discrepancy appear as central variables.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Wing Suen1</authors><title>Estimating the effects of immigration in one city      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper presents a new method of estimating the effects of immigration on the labor market that does not require variations         in immigration across cities. With a two-stage CES model that aggregates immigrant groups by age cohorts and aggregates cohorts         into effective labor, the econometric estimation and the interpretation of parameters are particularly straightforward. The         paper uses data from Hong Kong to estimate the elasticities of complementarity associated with increased immigration. A simulation         study indicates that a 40% increase in the stock of new immigrants will lower wages by no more than one percent.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Jochen Mayer1 | Regina T. Riphahn1</authors><title>Fertility assimilation of immigrants: Evidence from count data models      </title><content>Abstract.;; This study applies count data estimation techniques to investigate the fertility adjustment of immigrants in the destination         country. Data on completed fertility are taken from the 1996 wave of the German Socioeconomic Panel (GSOEP). While the economic         literature stresses the role of prices and incomes as determinants of fertility, the demographic literature discusses whether         assimilation or disruption effects dominate immigrants' fertility after migration. We find evidence in favor of the assimilation         model according to which immigrant fertility converges to native levels over time. In addition, we confirm the negative impact         of female human capital on fertility outcomes.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Peter G. Moffatt1 | Simon A. Peters2</authors><title>Grouped zero-inflated count data models of coital frequency      </title><content>Abstract.;; Various count data models are applied to data collected from a sample of Norfolk young persons, who were asked how many times         they had had sexual intercourse during the previous two-week period. The models take account of the fact that the data are         &amp;#8220;grouped&amp;#8221;, meaning that for some observations, the count is not known exactly but is known to fall in a particular range.         Using a formal testing procedure, we find overwhelming evidence of the presence of excess zeros, and this we attribute to         the fact that, at any time, a certain proportion of the population are sexually inactive. Our final model contains two equations,         the first being the participation equation which determines whether an individual is sexually active, and the second being         the frequency equation which determines the count, conditional on being active. Age, gender, salary, occupational status,         marital status and type of living environment all have interesting effects on either participation or frequency. Since a significant         proportion of the original sample declined to reveal coital frequency, we address the potential problem of selection bias         by including a Heckman-type correction term during the model selection process.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Timothy J. Hatton1</authors><title>How much did immigrant &amp;#8220;quality&amp;#8221; decline in late nineteenth century America?      </title><content>Abstract.;; Early twentieth century observers argued that recent American immigrants were inferior, and in particular less skilled, than         the old. I estimate wage equations for 1909 allowing for different effects by nationality and for different characteristics         on arrival. I then apply the estimated wage differentials to the immigrant composition to measure the effect of changing composition         on immigrant earnings. Finally I ask how immigrant earning power changed relative to that of native Americans. I conclude         that immigrant &amp;#8220;quality&amp;#8221; in terms of earnings did decline due to shifting composition but these effects are very small compared         with those reported in studies of the post-second World War period.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Peter Groote1 | Vincent Tassenaar2</authors><title>Hunger and migration in a rural-traditional area in the nineteenth century      </title><content>Abstract.;; The factors that influenced migration decisions in a nineteenth century rural-traditional area of the Netherlands are assessed.         This is done in a micro-setting. Applying a new data set with individual characteristics of both migrants and non-migrants         a logit-model is estimated. The analysis supports the revisionist and relatively positive picture of the standard of living         in pre-modern rural-traditional areas. Instead of hunger driving the masses away from these areas, it seems to have tied rationally         acting people to a socio-economic system that contained buffer mechanisms to cope with short run stresses.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Sherrie A. Kossoudji1 | Deborah A. Cobb-Clark2</authors><title>IRCA's impact on the occupational concentration and mobility of newly-legalized Mexican men      </title><content>Abstract.;; We examine the occupational concentration and mobility of a group of unauthorized Mexican men who received amnesty under         IRCA to shed light on the role of legal status in the assimilation process. Initially these men are concentrated in a small         number of traditional migrant jobs. Although their occupational mobility rate is high, it partly represents churning through         these same occupations. When we consider the direction &amp;#8211; either upward or downward &amp;#8211; of occupational change, we find that         English language ability and the characteristics of the occupation, itself, are strongly correlated with mobility before legalization.         After legalization, few characteristics surpass in importance the common experience of having received amnesty.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors> </authors><title>Kuznets Prize for James R. Walker      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Rolf Aaberge1| Ugo Colombino2 | Steinar StrГёm3</authors><title>Labor supply responses and welfare effects from replacing current tax rules by a flat tax: Empirical evidence from Italy,         Norway and Sweden      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper employs a microeconometric framework to examine the labor supply responses and the welfare effects from replacing         current tax systems in Italy, Norway and Sweden by a flat tax on total income. The flat tax rates are determined so that the         tax revenues are equal to the revenues as of 1992. The flat tax rates vary from 23 per cent in Italy, 25 per cent in Norway,         to 29 per cent in Sweden. In all three countries the labor supply responses decline sharply with pre-reform disposable income.         The results show that the efficiency costs of the current tax systems relative to a flat tax may be rather high in Norway         and much lower, but positive, in Italy and Sweden. In all three countries &amp;#8220;rich&amp;#8221; households &amp;#8211; defined by their pre-tax-reform         income &amp;#8211; tend to benefit (in terms of welfare) more than &amp;#8220;poor&amp;#8221; households. In Italy and Sweden a majority will lose from         a shift to a flat tax, while in Norway a majority is predicted to win.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Peter F. Orazem1 | Milan Vodopivec2</authors><title>Male-female differences in labor market outcomes during the early transition to market: The cases of Estonia and Slovenia      </title><content>Abstract.;; Changes in women's relative wages and employment are analyzed, using social security data from Slovenia (1987&amp;#8211;1992) and a         retrospective labor force survey in Estonia (1989&amp;#8211;1994). Estonia adopted liberal labor market policies. Slovenia took an interventionist         approach. Nevertheless, relative wages for women rose in both countries. Factors favoring women included: returns to human         capital rose in transition, benefiting women; relative labor demand shifted toward predominantly female sectors; low-wage         women had a disproportionate incentive to exit the labor market, especially in Estonia. However, women were less mobile across         jobs in both countries, so men disproportionately filled new jobs in expanding sectors.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Maria Melkersson1 | Dan-Olof Rooth2</authors><title>Modeling female fertility using inflated count data models      </title><content>Abstract.;; For modeling complete female fertility we propose a zero-and-two-inflated count data model, which accounts for a relative         excess of both zero and two children. As the underlying distribution of counts we use the standard Poisson distribution and         the more general Gamma count distribution. We compare our proposed model with standard count data models by using data on         complete fertilities for a sample of Swedish women. The preferred specification for Swedish fertility data is the zero-and-two         inflated Gamma count data model. The estimated &amp;#8220;extra&amp;#8221; probabilities of zero and two children, when modelled as individual         specific probabilities, vary substantially across individuals, with mean of 0.05 and 0.16, respectively. These extra probabilities         show that women who formed a family later in life have a higher probability of being childless, and women of our youngest         cohort have a higher probability of forming a two-child family.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Stephen P. Jenkins1</authors><title>Modelling household income dynamics      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper is about income and poverty dynamics and their socioeconomic correlates. The first half of the paper aims to establish         some of the salient facts for Britain, applying the pioneering methods of Bane and Ellwood (1986). Important for poverty dynamics         are changes in labour earnings from persons other than the household head, changes in non-labour income (including benefits),         and changes in household composition, in addition to changes in the heads' labour earnings. The second half of the paper is         a review and critique of the multivariate modelling frameworks which might be used to explain and forecast these salient facts         for Britain or elsewhere.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Dan Anderberg1</authors><title>Occupational risks, social insurance and investments in education      </title><content>Abstract.;; A link between social insurance and education policy is explored. Due to moral hazard full insurance against disability is         not feasible. When high- and low-risk individuals can be identified second-best social insurance system entails cross-subsidies         from the low-risk group to the high-risk group. Implementation of this second-best insurance however distorts the human capital         investment decisions when education qualifies for a low risk job. Therefore, the second-best social insurance together with         an education subsidy is a welfare improving policy. An education policy also has the role of establishing dynamic consistency         of the government's policy.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Hendrik JГјrges1</authors><title>Of rotten kids and Rawlsian parents: The optimal timing of intergenerational transfers      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper shows that altruistic parents with utilitarian preferences may fare better if they transfer resources to their children early in life instead of delaying the bulk of transfers         until after their death. Moreover, the outcome of the analysed &amp;#8220;family transfer game&amp;#8221; is not Pareto-efficient in the case         of bequests. However, if altruistic parents hold Rawlsian preferences, they will be indifferent between gifts and bequests, and Pareto-efficiency is always obtained. In intermediate         cases of Atkinson-type welfare functions, welfare losses of bequests compared to gifts disappear as the aversion to inequality         converges to infinity.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Petter Osmundsen1| Guttorm Schjelderup2 | KГҐre Petter Hagen2</authors><title>Personal income taxation under mobility, exogenous and endogenous welfare weights, and asymmetric information      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper analyses how governments should tax labour income accruing to a group of highly skilled and geographically mobile         individuals who divide their time or career between several jurisdictions. The analysis differs from previous models on migration         and taxation by addressing optimal regulation when agents work for several principals. Optimal taxation is developed for social         welfare functions with exogenous and endogenous welfare weights. Marginal income taxes are applied for screening purposes,         and the rates are lower with endogenous than with exogenous welfare weights.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Patrick A. Puhani1</authors><title>Poland on the dole: The effect of reducing the unemployment benefit entitlement period during transition      </title><content>Abstract:;; We analyse the unemployment benefit regime change that occurred in Poland in December 1991 using data from the Polish Labour         Force Survey. Before December 1991, the entitlement period to unemployment benefits was unlimited. Thereafter, it was reduced         to 12 months (with a few exceptions). Using the difference-in-differences approach within a hazard rate framework, we find         that the regime change did not have a significant effect on the duration of unemployment. The results thus give credence to         the view that the unlimited entitlement period of the old unemployment benefit regime was not the main culprit for the long durations of unemployment in Poland, although the generous eligibility criteria may have contributed to the increase in the incidence of registered unemployment at the beginning of the transition process.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Michael BrГ¤uninger1 | Jean-Pierre Vidal2</authors><title>Private versus public financing of education and endogenous growth      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper examines interactions between education policy and growth. The analysis is carried out in an OLG model with two         types of individuals: skilled and unskilled. An increase in public education reduces private costs of education, increases         the proportion of skilled individuals, and tends to promote growth. On the other hand, education spending crowds out physical         capital and reduces learning-by-doing. A marginal increase in the education subsidy can lower growth. It is yet shown that         pure public education maximizes the long-run growth rate. Importantly, a partial subsidy to education can result in lower         growth than pure private education.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Catherine Y. Co1| Ira N. Gang2 | Myeong-Su Yun2</authors><title>Returns to returning      </title><content>Abstract.;; We examine the labor market performance of return migrants using the Hungarian Household Panel Survey. Two distinct selection         issues are considered in the estimation of the earnings equation; we implement a natural method using MLE. The result that         there is a &amp;#8220;premium&amp;#8221; to work experience abroad for women is robust across the models we considered. For men, the return to         working abroad is not generally significant.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Pak-Wai Liu1| Xin Meng2 | Junsen Zhang1</authors><title>Sectoral gender wage differentials and discrimination in the transitional Chinese economy      </title><content>Abstract.;; China's economic reform has affected various ownership sectors to different degree. A comparison of gender wage differentials         and discrimination among individuals employed in the three sectors &amp;#8211; state sector, the collective sector, and the private         sector &amp;#8211; provides information on the impact of economic reform. Two Chinese data sets from Shanghai and Jinan are used to         examine the gender wage gap across the three sectors. It is found that privatization/marketization of the economy leads to         larger wage differentials as human capital characteristics are more appropriately rewarded. Both data sets show that the relative         share of discrimination in the overall gender wage differential declines substantially across ownership sectors from the state         to the private. The increase in gender wage differential due to marketization is much larger than any increase in differential         that may arise from more gender discrimination.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Alex|er Kemnitz1</authors><title>Social security, public education, and growth in a representative democracy      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper studies the relationship between public education and pay-as-you-go social security in a representative democracy,         where the government reacts both to voting and lobbying activities of workers and pensioners. While an intergenerational conflict         prevails concerning actual social security contributions, workers may prefer public education for its positive effect on later         pension benefits. Population aging diminishes the relative lobbying power of pensioners, leading to a higher contribution         rate, educational expansion, and higher per capita income growth.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Giancarlo Marini1 | Pasquale Scaramozzino2</authors><title>Social time preference      </title><content>Abstract.;; The observed practice of discounting the future should not be rationalised on the grounds of myopia or selfishness. A positive         rate of pure time preference is necessary to ensure that heterogeneous generations are treated in an egalitarian fashion.         A zero social discount rate would yield intertemporal allocations which are biased against the current generations. Endogenous         productivity growth requires that the social discount rate be set above the subjective rate of pure time preference. Positive         social time preference, far from discriminating against future generations, is essential for a fairer intertemporal allocation         of resources.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors> </authors><title>Stephen P. Jenkins      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors> </authors><title>Symposium on gender differences in transition to market economies      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>JГ¶rgen Hansen1</authors><title>The effect of work absence on wages and wage gaps in Sweden      </title><content>Abstract.;; We use unique information about short-term absence from the labor market among Swedish employees to investigate the potential         wage loss attributed to this type of absence. A reform in the Swedish health insurance system was used as an instrument. The         results indicate that women's wages are significantly reduced by work absence due to own sickness, while absence to care for         a sick child has no significant wage effect. For men, we find no support for effects on wages from short-term absence. We         also show that the distribution of the gender wage gap depends to a large extent on work absence.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Michael Vogler1 | Ralph Rotte2</authors><title>The effects of development on migration: Theoretical issues and new empirical evidence      </title><content>Abstract.;; Empirical research on the determinants of emigration from the LDCs has so far given little emphasis to the complex relationship         of development and migration. Since the beginning of the 1990s several arguments have been put forth which hint at the possibility         that in the early stages of development economic progress might lead to more migration, even if income differentials to the         potential destination regions decrease. This paper presents these arguments and tests them for the case of migration to Germany         from 86 Asian and African countries from 1981 to 1995. The results confirm the importance of financial restrictions on migration,         migration networks, and changes in the societal structure of the sending countries as well as the existence of a home preference.         The estimations also control for the political situation in the home countries and for institutional measures in the host         country.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Adriaan S. Kalwij1</authors><title>The effects of female employment status on the presence and number of children      </title><content>Abstract.;; The main concern of this paper is to analyze the effects of female employment status on the presence and number of children         in households in the Netherlands. For this purpose a hurdle count data model is formulated and estimated by the generalized         method of moments. The hurdle takes explicitly into account the interrelationship between female employment status and timing         of first birth. The number of children, once children are present in the household, is modeled conditional on female employment         status. The empirical results show that female employment status is a major determinant of the presence and number of children         in households: employed women schedule children later in life and have fewer children compared to nonemployed women, holding         educational attainment constant. After controlling for female employment status, the educational attainment of both the woman         and the man in the households are found to have relatively small effects on the presence and number of children.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Elena Glinskaya1 | Thomas A. Mroz2</authors><title>The gender gap in wages in Russia from 1992 to 1995      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper examines the gender gap in wages in Russia from 1992 to 1995. It uses data on prime aged men and women from the         Russia Longitudinal Monitoring Survey (RLMS) and focuses on those living in urban areas. Differences in hours of work appear         to explain about one half of the gender differential, but there is still a large differential in average hourly wages between         men and women. Observable differences in characteristics between men and women explain almost none of the differential or         the changes through time.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors> </authors><title>Thirteenth ESPE Conference and General Assembly in Torino 1999      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Volker Meier1</authors><title>Time preference, international migration, and social security      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper analyzes both the formation of long-run migration incentives and the consequences of a regime change from &amp;#8220;autarky&amp;#8221;         to &amp;#8220;free migration&amp;#8221; in an overlapping-generations framework with two countries. Under autarky the countries may differ with         respect to their aggregate savings rate or with respect to their pension-wage ratio. It is shown that an individual prefers         to live in a country where the capital-labor ratio is close to the Golden Rule level and where his characteristics are relatively         scarce. Both the migration incentives and the consequences of free migration are determined by these two effects.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Г&#152;ivind Anti Nilsen1| Alf Erling Risa1 | Alf Torstensen2</authors><title>Transitions from employment among young Norwegian workers      </title><content>Abstract.;; In a large representative sample of young Norwegian workers, we estimate gross transitions to unemployment, education, and         other exits in a multinomial logit. In line with received literature, we find that individuals with high education, experience,         and income have significantly lower probabilities of job exits. While female education rates have increased to surpass those         of males, female labour market outcomes are still more responsive to family related background characteristics as compared         with the outcomes for males.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Vincenzo Atella1 | Furio Camillo Rosati1</authors><title>Uncertainty about children's survival and fertility: A test using indian microdata      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper we present a non altruistic model of demand for children in the presence of uncertainty about children's survival.         Children are seen as assets, as they provide help during old age. Theoretical predictions relating to the change in the mean         and variance of the survival rate are derived. The empirical analysis is based on data from the Human Development of India         (HDI) survey. Different models for count data variables, such as Poisson and hurdle models have been employed in the empirical         analysis. The results highlight the importance of the uncertainty about children's survival in determining parental choices.         This shows that realized or expected children's death is not the only link between fertility decision and children's mortality.         The policy implications of such findings are briefly discussed.      </content></document><document><year>2000</year><authors>Laura M. Argys1| Susan L. Averett2 | Daniel I. Rees1</authors><title>Welfare generosity, pregnancies and abortions among unmarried AFDC recipients      </title><content>Abstract.;; Even before the 1996 overhaul of the U.S. welfare system, a number of states had ended the practice of paying extra benefits         to families who have additional children while receiving welfare. Proponents believe that this reform can reduce births to         recipients, however many worry that it may encourage women to obtain abortions. Using a sample of unmarried AFDC recipients         from the NLSY, we estimate a bivariate probit model of pregnancy and, conditional on becoming pregnant, the probability of         abortion. Our results lend some support for the proposition that reducing incremental AFDC benefits will decrease pregnancies         without increasing abortions.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Gunter Steinmann1| Alexia Prskawetz2 | Gustav Feichtinger2</authors><title>A model on the escape from the Malthusian trap      </title><content>Abstract.;; We consider a demoeconomic model where output is produced using physical capital, human capital and technology as inputs.         Human capital depends on the number of people and the level of education in the economy. The dynamics of labour, physical         capital, education and technology are endogenously determined such as to reflect the interdependence between economic and         demographic factors. The longrun path of the economy and in particular the possibility to escape the Malthusian trap crucially         depend on technological progress, which provides for economy wide increasing returns to scale. The build up of technology         is positively related to the stock of human capital. Our model predicts that positive population growth is sufficient to escape         the Malthusian trap.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Г&#152;ystein ThГёgersen1</authors><title>A note on intergenerational risk sharing  and the design of pay-as-you-go pension programs      </title><content>Abstract.;; Different versions of pay-as-you-go public pension programs may have entirely different effects on the intergenerational         distribution of income risk. If the pension benefit is a fixed proportion of previous labor income, a pay-as-you-go program         increases the net income risk of all generations. On the other hand, a pay-as-you-go program characterized by a fixed labor         income tax rate and uncertain pension benefits provides intergenerational risk sharing.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Roger Axelsson1 | Olle Westerlund1</authors><title>A panel study of migration, self-selection and household real income      </title><content>Abstract.;; The impact of migration on income for Swedish multi-adult households is examined using panel data pertaining to a sample         of stable household constellations during the period 1980&amp;#8211;1990. In contrast to previous studies, data on household disposable         income is employed in estimating the income function. The empirical results indicate no significant effect on real disposable         income from migration. In addition, the hypothesis of no self-selection, or zero correlation between the errors in the decision         function and the income function, cannot be rejected.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Philip Merrigan1 | Yvan St.-Pierre2</authors><title>An econometric and neoclassical analysis  of the timing and spacing of births in Canada from 1950 to 1990      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper estimates a reduced form neoclassical model of Canadian fertility dynamics using an econometric technique that         integrates several features not usually found in the demographic and economic literature. We find considerable support for         the neoclassical model. We also find that correlated unobservables and parity stopping effects play an important role in Canadian         fertility dynamics as well as other socio-demographic features of Canadian women. However, we fail to totally characterize         the important drops in the fertility rate that took place for this era.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Frederic Docquier1 | Hillel Rapoport3</authors><title>Are migrant minorities strategically self-selected?      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper we focus on the possibility of migrants' self-selection through strategic remittances. We argue that migrants         of a specific community might be pooled with migrants from other ethnic minorities on the labor market of the foreign host         country and that this could reduce the occurrence of strategic remittances. In a simple model with two types of workers, skilled         and unskilled, facing two possible actions, to migrate or not to migrate, we derive the theoretical conditions under which         strategic transfers are still operating when pooling among communities is introduced. We then show through numerical illustrations         that the case for strategic transfers is rather weak when using realistic values for the main parameters of the model.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Jonathan Haughton1 | Dominique Haughton2</authors><title>Are simple tests of son preference useful?  An evaluation using data from Vietnam      </title><content>Abstract.;; Son preference is widespread although not universal. Where it occurs it may lead to higher fertility rates. Ideally son preference         should be measured in the context of a hazards or parity progression model of fertility, or a logistic model of contraceptive         use. Such models require large amounts of survey data, particularly to measure the covariates. Can son preference be discerned         reliably using tests which rely on more limited information? The answer is yes, based on applying eight simple tests to data         from the Vietnam Living Standards Survey of 1992&amp;#8211;93 and comparing the outcomes with the benchmark results from fuller models.         Some, but not all, of the simpler tests accurately measure son preference, including estimating a simple hazards or progression         parity model, the unisex sibship test, and the sibling differentials test.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Richard P. C. Brown1</authors><title>Comparative labor market performance of visaed and non-visaed migrants: Pacific islanders in Sydney      </title><content>Abstract.;; Using survey data for Tongan and Samoan migrants in Sydney the effects of visa restrictions on labor market performance of         migrants are assessed. Univariate analysis suggests a positive association between unemployment and the unrestricted entry         of Samoan step-migrants from New Zealand. A probit model of the determinants of unemployment is estimated with controls for         human capital and demographic variables. While human capital endowments are important, visa restrictions do not have a significant         effect on either group&amp;#8216;s employability. Implications for policy are discussed highlighting the complementarities between host         country immigration policies and foreign aid programs.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Keith Blackburn1 | Giam Pietro Cipriani1</authors><title>Endogenous fertility, mortality and growth      </title><content>Abstract.;; Economic and demographic outcomes are determined jointly in a choice-theoretic model of fertility, mortality and capital         accumulation. There is an endogenous population of reproductive agents who belong to dynastic families of overlapping generations         connected through altruism. In addition to choosing savings and births, parents may reduce (infant) deaths by incurring expenditures         on health-care which is also provided by the government. A generalised production technology accounts for long-run endogenous         growth with short-run transitional dynamics. The analysis yields testable time series and cross-section implications which         accord with the empirical evidence on the relationship between demography and development.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Scott Boggess1</authors><title>Family structure, economic status, and educational attainment      </title><content>Abstract.;; This study examines the effect of family structure on high school graduation by race and gender using data from the first         twenty-one waves of the Panel Study of Income Dynamics and recently available retrospective marital histories. The nature         of the data allows for a more complete specification of family structure than has been heretofore possible. The analysis tests         the hypothesis that the negative effect on educational attainment often associated with living in a mother-only or stepfather         family stems primarily from the reduced level of economic resources available to these households. Empirical findings indicate         that living with a widowed, divorced, or separated mother has little or no effect on educational attainment once we control         for economic status. However, living in a stepfather family appears to have a persistent negative effect on high school graduation         rates.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Diane J. Macunovich1</authors><title>Fertility and the Easterlin hypothesis: An assessment of the literature      </title><content>Abstract.;; Focusing just on the fertility aspects of the Easterlin hypothesis, this paper offers a critical assessment &amp;#8211; rather than         just a selective citation &amp;#8211; of the extensive fertility literature generated by Easterlin, and a complete inventory of data         and methodologies in seventy-six published analyses. With an equal number of micro- and macro-level analyses using North American         data (twenty-two), the &amp;#8222;track record&amp;#8221; of the hypothesis is the same in both venues, with fifteen providing significant support         in each case. The literature suggests unequivocal support for the relativity of the income concept in fertility, but is less         clear regarding the source(s) of differences in material aspirations, and suggests that the observed relationship between         fertility and cohort size has varied across countries and time periods due to the effects of additional factors not included         in most models.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Aless|ro Cigno1</authors><title>Fertility decisions when infant survival is endogenous      </title><content>Abstract.;; There is evidence that fertility is positively correlated with infant mortality, and that a child&amp;#8216;s chance of surviving to         maturity increases with the level of nutrition, medical care, etc. received in the early stages of life. By modelling parental         decisions as a problem of choice under uncertainty, the paper shows that fertility and infant mortality are most likely to         move in opposite directions if, as implicitly assumed by existing economic theories, parents believe that there is nothing         they can do to improve the survival chances of their own children. By contrast, if parents realize that those chances improve         with the amount they spend for the health, nutrition, etc. of each child that they put into the world, then fertility and         infant mortality may move in the same direction. Under such an assumption, the model has the strong policy implication that         directly death-reducing public expenditures are most effective, but stimulate population growth, at low levels of development.         By contrast, at high levels of development, such expenditures tend to crowd out parental expenditures, and are a factor in         fertility decline.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Anil Deolalikar1 | Elaina Rose1</authors><title>Gender and savings in rural India      </title><content>Abstract. ;;In this study we use data from rural India to examine the impact of the birth of a boy relative to the birth of a girl (i.e.,         the &amp;#8220;gender shock&amp;#8221;) on the savings, consumption and income of rural Indian households. We find that the gender shock reduces         savings for medium and large farm households, although there is no evidence that the shock affects savings for the landless         and the small farm households. We also estimate the effect of the shock on income and consumption for the former group in         order to determine the source of the drop in savings. The results indicate that the fall in savings subsequent to the gender         shock arises from its effect on consumption in the year following the birth, and from its effect on income in other years.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors> </authors><title>Heather Joshi                  1996 President  of the European Society  for Population Economics</title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Barry R. Chiswick1</authors><title>Hebrew language usage: Determinants and effects on earnings among immigrants in Israel      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper uses the 1983 Census of Israel to analyze Hebrew speaking skills and the effects of Hebrew fluency on the earnings         of adult male immigrants. Hebrew fluency increases with a longer duration in Israel, the presence of children in the household,         marrying after immigration, living in an area in which a smaller proportion speak one&amp;#8216;s mother tongue, a younger age at migration,         a higher level of schooling and varies by country of birth. Earnings increase monotonically with the use of Hebrew. Speaking         English as a second language is associated with higher earnings, even when country of origin is held constant.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Adriaan Kalwij1| Rob Alessie1 | Peter Fontein1</authors><title>Household commodity demand and demographics in the Netherlands: A microeconometric analysis      </title><content>Abstract.;; We investigate the effects of demographics, household expenditure and female employment on the allocation of household expenditure         to consumer goods. For this purpose we estimate an Almost Ideal Demand System based on Dutch micro data. We find that interactions         between household expenditure and demographics are of significant importance in explaining the allocation to consumer goods.         As a consequence, consumer goods such as housing and clothing change with demographic characteristics from luxuries to necessities. Furthermore, this implies that budget and price-elasticities         cannot be consistently estimated from aggregated data and that equivalence scales are not identified from budget survey data         alone. We reject weak separability of consumer goods from female employment. A couple with an employed spouse has a smaller         budget share for housing and personal care and a larger budget share for education, recreation and transport and clothing compared to a couple with a non-employed spouse.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>T. Paul Schultz1</authors><title>Immigrant quality and assimilation: A review of the US literature      </title><content>Abstract.;; Empirical research on US immigrants is reviewed: their productivity and assimilation; their contribution and use of public         services; and their impact on native Americans. I discuss the characteristics of cohorts of immigrants that enter the United         States at different times, and then quantify the assimilation of immigrants, typically in terms of economic productivity of         immigrants compared with natives. Few have found quantifiable negative effects of immigrants on native wages or unemployment         in local labor markets, but a more general equilibrium approach than has been empirically implemented may be needed to draw         any conclusions regarding the distributional consequences of immigration.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>John T. Durkin Jr.1</authors><title>Immigration, assimilation and growth      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper analyzes the welfare effects of immigration and its subsequent effect on ethnic diversity in a model featuring         human capital spillovers which depend on the degree of ethnic heterogeneity, variation rates of time preference across individuals         and endogenous levels of immigration and assimilation. In the model, an increase in ethnic diversity reduces the spillovers         effect for the majority. Nonetheless, immigration can be welfare improving for the majority ethnic group even if it increases         the degree of diversity as long as it raises the average human capital level and/or growth rate by increasing the proportion         of people with low rates of time preference. However, if an economy is too homogenous, it will not be able to attract immigrants.         Finally, if the level of immigration is not too high, then immigration also raises the net benefits to assimilation which         leads to a more homogenous economy.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>T. Paul Schultz1</authors><title>Inequality in the distribution of personal income in the world: How it is changing and why      </title><content>Abstract.;; The variance in the logarithms of per capita GDP in purchasing-power-parity prices increased in the world from 1960 to 1968         and decreased since the mid 1970s. In the later period the convergence in intercountry incomes more than offset any increase         in within country inequality. Approximately two-thirds of this measure of world inequality is intercountry, three-tenths interhousehold         within country inequality, and one-twentieth between gender differences in education. If China is excluded from the world         sample, the decline in world inequality after 1975 is not evident. Measuring confidently trends in household and gender inequality         will require much improved data.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Frans van Dijk1</authors><title>Private support and social securityPrivate support and social security      </title><content>Abstract.;; The issue is addressed whether assistance to persons in need can be left to the &amp;#8216;family&amp;#8217; and the &amp;#8216;community&amp;#8217;. In that case         people depend on their social networks. The support a person receives through a given network of social ties is examined.         However, ties are diverse and subject to change. By means of a model of the dynamics of social ties, the conditions for adequate         private support are analyzed. The sustainability of private support over time is examined by incorporating the impact on social         ties of lending and receiving support. It is shown that support is only an effective alternative in a limited number of situations.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Ashish Garg1 | Jonathan Morduch2</authors><title>Sibling rivalry and the gender gap: Evidence from child health outcomes in Ghana      </title><content>Abstract.;; When capital and labor markets are imperfect, choice sets narrow, and parents must choose how to ration available funds and         time between their children. One consequence is that children become rivals for household resources. In economies with pro-male         bias, such rivalries can yield gains to having relatively more sisters than brothers. Using a rich household survey from Ghana,         we find that on average if children had all sisters (and no brothers) they would do roughly 25-40% better on measured health         indicators than if they had all brothers (and no sisters). The effects are as large as typical quantity-quality trade-offs,         and they do not differ significantly by gender.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors> </authors><title>T. Paul Schultz                  1997 President  of the European Society  for Population Economics</title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Sulayman Al-Qudsi1</authors><title>The demand for children in Arab countries: Evidence from panel and count data models      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper provides empirical evidence on fertility determinants in Arab countries. Adopting a macro and micro framework         and exploiting panel and count data models the paper estimates the impact of cultural and economic factors on the demand for         children. The results obtained strongly support the hypothesis that cross-country heterogeneity buttresses differentiated         fertility and that female education mitigates high fertility. Child mortality and parent&amp;#8216;s preferences for sons positively         affect fertility. By and large, demand for children is price and income inelastic.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Jean-Pierre Vidal1</authors><title>The effect of emigration on human capital formation      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper focuses on a possible effect of emigration on human capital formation. Emigration to a higher returns to skill         country provides an incentive to invest in human capital. The level of human capital formation in the source country can therefore         be positively correlated with the probability of emigration. Incidentally a surge in emigration can lead the source country         out of an under-development trap. The implications of the model for the convergence controversy are also discussed.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Boris A. Portnov1</authors><title>The effect of housing on migrations in Israel: 1988&amp;#8211;1994      </title><content>Abstract. ;;The analysis of 1988&amp;#8211;1994 statistical data indicates that the population of Israel simultaneously moves in two opposite directions:         while the initial distribution of new immigrants is primarily focused on the areas where jobs are available, the existing         population of these areas tends to move outward, to the less populated districts where housing is more available and affordable.         The paper thus argues that the heterogeneity of the population is indeed a crucial consideration for the proper modeling of         migration behavior. It is also argued that a) the effect of housing construction on the patterns of in-country migration appears         to be attenuated, and b) the low attractiveness of peripheral districts of the country to the new immigrants is mainly caused         by a lack of jobs rather than by low rates of housing construction or the harsh climatic conditions of these areas.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Guy Lacroix1| Michel Picot2 | Catherine Sofer2</authors><title>The extent of labour specialization in the extended family: A theoretical and empirical analysis      </title><content>Abstract.;; In this paper we present a simple model of labour supply that is cast within the framework of an extended family. The model         emphasizes a Ricardian division of labour whereby the specialization is solely driven by marginal productivity and value of         time differentials. The empirical implications of the model are derived and tested using data that was collected in France         to study the extent of trade within the family network. We find evidence that the extent of specialization is sensitive to         the value of time differentials.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Roy E. Bailey1 | Marcus J. Chambers2</authors><title>The impact of real wage and mortality fluctuations on fertility and nuptiality in precensus England      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper explores the responses of fertility and nuptiality to fluctuations in real wages and mortality that can be inferred         from annual series of English historical data over the period 1542 to 1800. The paper begins with a review of the time series         properties of the data and summarizes the long-term equilibrium relationships identified in previous work. A Vector Error         Correction Mechanism (VECM) is then proposed to study the observed short-term fluctuations in a way that is compatible with         long-term equilibria. Following estimation of the parameters of the VECM, an investigation is made of the impact of shocks         to real wages and mortality on demographic variables as measured by generalized impulse responses and persistence profiles.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Heather Joshi1</authors><title>The opportunity costs of childbearing: More than mothers&amp;#8217; business      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper is an argument about gender relations. It takes the entwined themes of men&amp;#8216;s interests in parenthood, the sex         division of labour and its evolution, policy for gender equity and policy to support the level of social reproduction. The         emphasis on women&amp;#8216;s employment as a determinant of low fertility has to be supplemented by an examination of the assumption         that only women&amp;#8216;s time use is affected by child-rearing. Many forces tend to concentrate fathers&amp;#8216; involvement on breadwinning,         but they are not immutable and are already changing. It should be in the interests of promoting social reproduction, as well         as gender equity, for policy interventions to facilitate complementarities in parenting and in its combination with paid work.         Descriptive evidence about the paid and unpaid work of couples and parents is presented, largely secondary material from the         UK.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>John E. Hayfron1</authors><title>The performance of immigrants in the Norwegian labor market      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper tests the assimilation hypothesis with Norwegian data. Using both cross-section and cohort analyses, the results         show that the 1970&amp;#8211;1979 immigrant cohort experienced an earnings growth of about 11% between 1980 and 1990, when their earnings         profile was compared to that of natives. This is lower than the 19% assimilation rate predicted by the cross-section method.         On the contrary, the results reveal a rapid earnings divergence across cohorts, and between the 1960&amp;#8211;1969 cohort and natives.         It is also shown that the &amp;#8222;quality&amp;#8221; of successive immigrant waves has declined over time, thus biasing the cross-section estimates         of assimilation.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Pierre L. Siklos1 | William L. Marr1</authors><title>The unemployment insurance compensation experience of immigrants in Canada, 1980&amp;#8211;1988      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper utilizes a new data set, compiled by Citizenship and Immigration Canada, Revenue Canada and Statistics Canada,         to examine the unemployment experience of Canadian immigrant cohorts over the time period 1980 to 1988. Using the records         of unemployment insurance benefits of persons who immigrated to Canada in those years and who filed income tax returns, the         unemployment experiences of those people are compared by landing year, gender, level of education, language ability, and country         of last permanent residence. The determinants of the proportion of each immigrant cohort that received unemployment insurance         benefits are estimated by relating the proportions to landing year, duration of time in Canada, and labour market conditions.         Briefly, we find no obvious influences on UI receipt behaviour following the immigration reforms of 1982. However, the recession         of 1981&amp;#8211;82 had a major impact on incomes which did not recover until 5 or 6 years later. Nevertheless, more generous UI benefits         did raise slightly the likelihood of UI receipts.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Bertr| Crettez1| Philippe Michel2 | Jean-Pierre Vidal3</authors><title>Time preference and capital mobility in an OLG model with land      </title><content>Abstract.;; This paper examines the pattern of capital mobility in a two-country overlapping generations world in which production uses         three inputs: capital, labor and land. The steady-state welfare consequences of opening countries to financial capital or         labor mobility are then compared. In particular, it is shown that capital mobility does not equalize standards of living across         countries. To achieve this goal, one has to rely on labor mobility.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Charles Blackorby1| Walter Bossert2 | David Donaldson3</authors><title>Uncertainty and critical-level population principles      </title><content> This paper analyzes variable-population social-evaluation principles in a framework where outcomes are uncertain. We provide         characterizations of expected-utility versions of critical-level generalized utilitarian rules. These principles evaluate         lotteries over possible states of the world on the basis of the sum of the expected values of differences between transformed         utility levels and a transformed critical level, conditional on the agents&amp;#8216; being alive in the states under consideration.         Equivalently, the critical-level utilitarian value functions applied to weighted individual expected utilities can be employed.         Weights are determined by the anonymity axiom.      </content></document><document><year>1998</year><authors>Michael Lundholm1 | Henry Ohlsson2</authors><title>Wages, taxes and publicly provided day care      </title><content>Abstract.;; Public employment growth has been parallelled by increased female labour force participation, while real wages for typical         female public sector occupations have not increased. In a theoretical model we, first, show that there is a tradeoff between         day care provision and gross wages for occupations for which day care is a complement. It is possible to combine increased         public labour demand with public day care provision leaving the wage unaffected. Second, non-parents will be in favour of         increasing day care as long as day care productivity is higher than the inverse of the tax rate. This is because the effective         labour supply and, therefore, the tax base increase. Third, parents want to push day care provision even further. They are         prepared to accept a lower day care productivity than non-parents because day care provision relaxes the constraint on their         desired labour supply. The Pareto efficient day care provision is between parents&amp;#8216; and non-parents&amp;#8216; preferred levels.      </content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Frederic Vermeulen1 </authors><title>A collective model for female labour supply with non-participation and taxation      </title><content>This paper presents a collective discrete-choice model for female labour supply. Preferences of females and the intra-household         allocation process are both econometrically identified. The model incorporates non-participation and non-linear taxation.         It is applied to Belgian micro-data and is used to evaluate two revenue-neutral versions of the 2001 Tax Reform Act. We find         small positive behavioural responses to the reforms. The reforms are not unambiguously welfare-improving. Generally, the first         revenue-neutral reform (the actual reform and a household lump-sum tax) is more beneficial to females in couples than the         second (the actual reform and a proportional decrease of household disposable incomes).      </content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Tom Kornstad1  | Thor O. Thoresen1 </authors><title>A discrete choice model for labor supply and childcare      </title><content>A discrete choice model for labor supply and childcare for mothers of preschoolers is presented. The mothers are assumed to         make choices from a finite set of job possibilities and from a finite set of childcare options. Options in the markets for         childcare are characterized by opening hours, fees and quality attributes. Similarly, jobs are characterized by a fixed wage         rate, working hours and a number of variables related to job satisfaction. In the estimation of the model, we take into account         that the number of options available might vary across work/care combinations and that some mothers are rationed in the market         for care at day care centers. The model is employed to simulate the female labor supply effects of the Norwegian home care         allowance reform.      </content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Acknowledgement to editorial collaborators</authors><title/></document></documents>