<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><documents><document><year>2009</year><authors>Robert Stalnaker1 </authors><title>A response to Abbott on presupposition and common ground      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>R. Zuber1 </authors><title>A semantic constraint on binary determiners      </title><content>A type  quantifier F is symmetric iff F(X, X)(Y) = F(Y, Y)(X). It is shown that quantifiers denoted by irreducible binary determiners in natural languages are both conservative and symmetric         and not only conservative.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Matthias Gerner1 </authors><title>Assessing the modality particles of the Yi group in fuzzy possible-worlds semantics      </title><content>Of late, evidentiality has received great attention in formal semantics. In this paper I develop &amp;#8216;evidentiality-informed&amp;#8217;         truth conditions for modal operators such as must and may. With language data drawn from Luoping Nase (a Tibeto-Burman language spoken in the P.R. of China and belonging to the Yi         Nationality), I illustrate that epistemic modals clash with clauses articulating first-hand information. I then demonstrate         that existing models such as Kratzer&amp;#8217;s graded possible-worlds semantics fail to provide accurate truth conditions for modals         tagging clauses with first-hand information. As a remedy I propose a fuzzy version of possible-worlds semantics with various         grades of belief and knowledge. In addition to preserving the expressive power of graded possible-worlds semantics, the fuzzy         model will be shown to supply appropriate truth conditions for epistemic modals appended to evidential clauses (i.e. clauses         expressing first-hand information).      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Vojislav Bozickovic1 </authors><title>Cognitive significance and reflexive content      </title><content>John Perry has urged that a semantic theory for natural languages ought to be concerned with the issue of cognitive significance&amp;#8212;of         how true identity statements containing different (utterances of) indexicals and proper names can be informative, held to         be unaccountable by the referentialist view. The informativeness that he has in mind&amp;#8212;one that has puzzled Frege, Kaplan and         Wettstein&amp;#8212;concerns knowledge about the world. In trying to solve this puzzle on referentialist terms, he comes up with the         notion of cognitive significance as a special kind of a second-order content which should account for cognitive significance         in the former sense. Focusing on his treatment of perceptual demonstratives, I argue that he fails to do so both on the level         of second-order contents containing demonstrative utterances and on the level of second-order contents containing perceptual         buffers as new notions associated with the perceptions and used to temporarily store ideas we gain from the perceptions, which         he holds to be causally connected to each other.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Luis Alonso-Ovalle1 </authors><title>Counterfactuals, correlatives, and disjunction      </title><content>The natural interpretation of counterfactuals with disjunctive antecedents involves selecting from each of the disjuncts the         worlds that come closest to the world of evaluation. It has been long noticed that capturing this interpretation poses a problem         for a minimal change semantics for counterfactuals, because selecting the closest worlds from each disjunct requires accessing         the denotation of the disjuncts from the denotation of the disjunctive antecedent, which the standard boolean analysis of         or does not allow (Creary and Hill, Philosophy of Science 43:341&amp;#8211;344, 1975; Nute, Journal of Philosophy 72:773&amp;#8211;778, 1975; Fine,         Mind 84(335):451&amp;#8211;458, 1975; Ellis et;al. Journal of Philosophical Logic 6:335&amp;#8211;357, 1977). This paper argues that the failure         to capture the natural interpretation of disjunctive counterfactuals provides no reason to abandon a minimal change semantics.         It shows that the natural interpretation of disjunctive counterfactuals is expected once we refine our assumptions about the         semantics of or and the logical form of conditionals, and (i) we assume that disjunctions introduce propositional alternatives in the semantic         derivation, in line with independently motivated proposals about the semantics of or (Aloni, 2003a; Simons, Natural Language Semantics 13:271&amp;#8211;316, 2005; Alonso-Ovalle, Disjunction in Alternative Semantics.         PhD thesis, 2006); and (ii) we treat conditionals as correlative constructions, as advocated in von Fintel (1994), Izvorski         (Proceedings of NELS 26, 1996), Bhatt and Pancheva (2006), and Schlenker (2004).      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Friederike Moltmann1 </authors><title>Degree structure as trope structure: a trope-based analysis of positive and comparative adjectives      </title><content>This paper explores a novel analysis of adjectives in the comparative and the positive based on the notion of a trope, rather         than the notion of a degree. Tropes are particularized properties, concrete manifestations of properties in individuals. The         point of departure is that a sentence like &amp;#8216;John is happier than Mary&amp;#8217; is intuitively equivalent to &amp;#8216;John&amp;#8217;s happiness exceeds         Mary&amp;#8217;s happiness&amp;#8217;, a sentence that expresses a simple comparison between two tropes, John&amp;#8217;s happiness and Mary&amp;#8217;s happiness.         The analysis received particular support from various parallels between adjectival constructions and corresponding adjective         nominalizations which make reference to tropes.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Paul Elbourne1 </authors><title>Demonstratives as individual concepts      </title><content>Using a version of situation semantics, this article argues that bare and complex demonstratives are interpreted as individual         concepts.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Itamar Francez1 </authors><title>Existentials, predication, and modification      </title><content>This paper offers a new semantic theory of existentials (sentences of the form          There be NP                     pivot                     XP                     coda            ) in which pivots are (second order) predicates and codas are modifiers. The theory retains the analysis of pivots as denoting         generalized quantifiers (Barwise and Cooper 1981; Keenan 1987), but departs from previous analyses in analyzing codas as contextual         modifiers on a par with temporal/locative frame adverbials. Existing analyses universally assume that pivots are arguments         of some predicate, and that codas are main or secondary predicates. It is shown that these analyses cannot account for the         behavior of codas with quantifiers and for the interaction of multiple codas, both of which receive a simple treatment on         the proposed theory. The assimilation of codas to frame adverbials explains several semantic properties which have not been         analyzed in the semantic literature, and that distinguish existentials from their copular counterparts. Furthermore, it highlights         important properties of the semantics of modification and its relation to predication.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Bernhard Nickel1 </authors><title>Generics and the ways of normality      </title><content>I contrast two approaches to the interpretation of generics such as &amp;#8216;ravens are black:&amp;#8217; majority-based views, on which they         are about what is the case most of the time, and inquiry-based views, on which they are about a feature we focus on in inquiry.         I argue that majority-based views face far more systematic counterexamples than has previously been supposed. They cannot         account for generics about kinds with multiple characteristic properties, such as &amp;#8216;elephants live in Africa and Asia.&amp;#8217; I then         go on to sketch an inquiry-based view.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Elisabeth Villalta1 </authors><title>Mood and gradability: an investigation of the subjunctive mood in Spanish      </title><content>In Spanish (and other Romance languages) certain predicates select the subjunctive mood in the embedded clause, while others         select the indicative mood. In this paper, I present a new analysis for the predicates that select the subjunctive mood in         Spanish that is based on a semantics of comparison. The main generalization proposed here is the following: in Spanish, a         predicate selects the subjunctive mood in its embedded proposition if the proposition is compared to its contextual alternatives         on a scale introduced by the predicate. In this proposal, predicates that select the subjunctive mood are thus analyzed as         gradable predicates. Furthermore, the subjunctive mood morpheme is claimed to make a semantic contribution, namely to evaluate         the contextual alternatives that are compared by the predicate. In comparing this proposal to other approaches, I show that         it can more straightforwardly account for a number of properties of these predicates (entailment relations, practical inferences,         and contexts with more than two alternatives). New empirical evidence for two crucial properties of the predicates that select         the subjunctive mood is provided: these predicates are focus sensitive and they are gradable, two properties that follow directly         from the proposal developed here. In the vast literature on mood, the link between the appearance of the subjunctive mood         and these important properties has never been made before.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Ora Matushansky1| 2 </authors><title>On the linguistic complexity of proper names      </title><content>While proper names in argument positions have received a lot of attention, this cannot be said about proper names in the naming         construction, as in &amp;#8220;Call me Al&amp;#8221;. I argue that in a number of more or less familiar languages the syntax of naming constructions         is such that proper names there have to be analyzed as predicates, whose content mentions the name itself (cf. &amp;#8220;quotation         theories&amp;#8221;). If proper names can enter syntax as predicates, then in argument positions they should have a complex structure,         consisting of a determiner and its restriction, like common nouns (cf. &amp;#8220;definite description theories of proper names&amp;#8221;). Further         consideration of the compositional semantics of proper names in the naming construction also shows that they have another         argument slot, that of the naming convention. As a result, we will be able to account for the indexicality of proper names         in argument positions and provide compositional semantics of complex and modified proper names (e.g., the famous detective Sherlock Holmes).      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Gerhard Schaden1| 2 </authors><title>Present perfects compete      </title><content>This paper proposes a new look at the so-called &amp;#8216;present-perfect puzzle&amp;#8217;. I suggest that it is in fact part of a bigger problem,         which also involves simple past tenses. I argue that present perfects compete with simple past tenses, and that the distribution         of these tenses shows signs of the impact of this competition. The outcome of the competition is argued to be heavily dependent         on which of the two tense-forms is the default. A pragmatic theory is proposed which accounts for the reduced distribution         of the present perfect in languages like English and (American) Spanish, and the reduced distribution of the simple past tense         in languages like French and German.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Barbara Abbott1 </authors><title>Presuppositions and common ground      </title><content>This paper presents problems for Stalnaker&amp;#8217;s common ground theory of presupposition. Stalnaker (Linguist and Philos 25:701&amp;#8211;721,         2002) proposes a 2-stage process of utterance interpretation: presupposed content is added to the common ground prior to acceptance/rejection         of the utterance as a whole. But this revision makes presupposition difficult to distinguish from assertion. A more fundamental         problem is that the common ground theory rests on a faulty theory of assertion&amp;#8212;that the essence of assertion is to present         the content of an utterance as new information. Many examples are presented of utterances which are felicitous but not informative         in this way.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Tim Fern|o1 </authors><title>Situations as indices and as denotations      </title><content>A distinction is drawn between situations as indices required for semantically evaluating sentences and situations as denotations         resulting from such evaluation. For atomic sentences, possible worlds may serve as indices, and events as denotations. The         distinction is extended beyond atomic sentences according to formulae-as-types and applied to implicit quantifier domain restrictions, intensionality and conditionals.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Eric McCready1 </authors><title>What man does      </title><content>This paper considers the meaning and use of the English particle man. It is shown that the particle does quite different things when it appears in sentence-initial and sentence-final position;         the first use involves expression of an emotional attitude as well as, on a particular intonation, intensification; this use         is analyzed using a semantics for degree predicates along with a separate dimension for the expressive aspect. Further restrictions         on modification with the sentence-initial particle involving monotonicity and evidence are introduced and analyzed. The sentence-final         use can be viewed as strengthening the action performed by the sentence. A formal semantics is given by making use of dynamic         techniques and, in a sense, dynamically simulating the modification of certain speech acts. Some empirical and theoretical         extensions of the analyses are proposed and some consequences discussed.      </content></document><document><year>2009</year><authors>Benjamin Schnieder1 </authors><title>&amp;#8216;By&amp;#8217;         A refutation of the Anscombe Thesis</title><content>The paper has two main objectives: first, it presents a new argument against the so-called Anscombe Thesis (if x &amp;#966;-s by &amp;#968;-ing, then x&amp;#8217;s &amp;#966;-ing = x&amp;#8217;s &amp;#968;-ing). Second, it develops a proposal about the syntax and semantics of the &amp;#8216;by&amp;#8217;-locution.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Paul Dekker1 </authors><title>A multi-dimensional treatment of quantification in extraordinary English      </title><content>In this paper I revive two important formal approaches to the interpretation of natural language, that of Montague and that         of Karttunen and Peters. Armed with insights from dynamic semantics (Heim, Krifka) the two turn out to stand up against age-old         criticisms in an orthodox fashion. The plan is mainly methodological, as I only want to illustrate the technical feasibility         of the revived proposals. Even so, there are illuminating and welcome empirical consequences on the subject of scope islands         (as discussed by Abusch and Kratzer, among many others), as well as unintended theoretical implications in the contextualist         debate (Grice, Recanati, Simons, Stanley, and many others again).      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Alan Clinton Bale1 </authors><title>A universal scale of comparison      </title><content>Comparative constructions form two classes, those that permit direct comparisons (comparisons of measurements as in Seymour is taller than he is wide) and those that only allow indirect comparisons (comparisons of relative positions on separate scales as in Esme is more beautiful than Einstein is intelligent). In contrast with other semantic theories, this paper proposes that the interpretation of the comparative morpheme remains         the same whether it appears in sentences that compare individuals directly or indirectly. To develop a unified account, I         suggest that all comparisons (whether in terms of height, intelligence or beauty) involve a scale of universal degrees that are isomorphic to the rational (fractional) numbers between 0 and 1. Crucial to a unified treatment, the connection         between the individuals being compared and universal degrees involves two steps. First individuals are mapped to a value on         a primary scale that ranks individuals with respect to the gradable property (whether it be height, beauty or intelligence).         Second, the value on the primary scale is mapped to a universal degree that encodes the value&amp;#8217;s relative position on the primary         scale. Direct comparison results if measurements such as seven feet participate in the primary scale (as in Seven feet is tall). Otherwise the result is an indirect comparison.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>David Braun1 </authors><title>Complex demonstratives and their singular contents      </title><content>This paper presents a semantic and pragmatic theory of complex demonstratives. According to this theory, the semantic content         of a complex demonstrative, in a context, is simply an object, and the semantic content of a sentence that contains a complex         demonstrative, in a context, is a singular proposition. This theory is defended from various objections to direct reference         theories of complex demonstratives, including King's objection from quantification into complex demonstratives.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Adrian Brasoveanu1 </authors><title>Donkey pluralities: plural information states versus non-atomic individuals      </title><content>The paper argues that two distinct and independent notions of plurality are involved in natural language anaphora and quantification:         plural reference (the usual non-atomic individuals) and plural discourse reference, i.e., reference to a quantificational dependency between sets of objects (e.g., atomic/non-atomic individuals) that is established         and subsequently elaborated upon in discourse. Following van den Berg (PhD dissertation, University of Amsterdam, 1996), plural         discourse reference is modeled as plural information states (i.e., as sets of variable assignments) in a new dynamic system         couched in classical type logic that extends Compositional DRT (Muskens, Linguistics and Philosophy, 19, 143&amp;#8211;186, 1996). Given the underlying type logic, compositionality at sub-clausal level follows automatically and standard         techniques from Montague semantics become available. The idea that plural info states are semantically necessary (in addition         to non-atomic individuals) is motivated by relative-clause donkey sentences with multiple instances of singular donkey anaphora         that have mixed (weak and strong) readings. At the same time, allowing for non-atomic individuals in addition to plural info         states enables us to capture the intuitive parallels between singular and plural (donkey) anaphora, while deriving the incompatibility         between singular (donkey) anaphora and collective predicates. The system also accounts for empirically unrelated phenomena,         e.g., the uniqueness effects associated with singular (donkey) anaphora discussed in Kadmon (Linguistics and Philosophy, 13, 273&amp;#8211;324, 1990) and Heim (Linguistics and Philosophy, 13, 131&amp;#8211;177, 1990) among others.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Juan Barba1 </authors><title>Formal semantics in the age of pragmatics      </title><content>This paper aims to argue for two related statements: first, that formal semantics should not be conceived of as interpreting         natural language expressions in a single model (a very large one representing the world as a whole, or something like that)         but as interpreting them in many different models (formal counterparts, say, of little fragments of reality); second, that         accepting such a conception of formal semantics yields a better comprehension of the relation between semantics and pragmatics         and of the role to be played by formal semantics in the general enterprise of understanding meaning. For this purpose, three         kinds of arguments are given: firstly, empirical arguments showing that the many models approach is the most straightforward         and natural way of giving a formal counterpart to natural language sentences. Secondly, logical arguments proving the logical         impossibility of a single universal model. And thirdly, theoretical arguments to the effect that such a conception of formal         semantics fits in a natural and fruitful way with pragmatic theories and facts. In passing, this conception will be shown         to cast some new light on the old problems raised by liar and sorites paradoxes.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Tamina Stephenson1 </authors><title>Judge dependence, epistemic modals, and predicates of personal taste      </title><content>Predicates of personal taste (fun, tasty) and epistemic modals (might, must) share a similar analytical difficulty in determining whose taste or knowledge is being expressed. Accordingly, they have         parallel behavior in attitude reports and in a certain kind of disagreement. On the other hand, they differ in how freely         they can be linked to a contextually salient individual, with epistemic modals being much more restricted in this respect.         I propose an account of both classes using Lasersohn&amp;#8217;s (Linguistics and Philosophy 28: 643&amp;#8211;686, 2005) &amp;#8220;judge&amp;#8221; parameter, at         the same time arguing for crucial changes to Lasersohn&amp;#8217;s view in order to allow the extension to epistemic modals and address         empirical problems faced by his account.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Rui P. Chaves1 </authors><title>Linearization-based word-part ellipsis      </title><content>This paper addresses a phenomenon in which certain word-parts can be omitted. The evidence shows that the full range of data         cannot be captured by a sublexical analysis, since the phenomena can be observed both in phrasal and in lexical environments.         It is argued that a form of deletion is involved, and that the phenomena&amp;#8212;lexical or otherwise&amp;#8212;are subject to the same phonological,         semantic, and syntactic constraints. In the formalization that is proposed, all of the above constraints are cast in a parallel         and declarative fashion, in the framework of Head-Driven Phrase Structure Grammar (Pollard and Sag Head-driven phrase structure         grammar, 1994), since the various levels of linguistic description are locally and simultaneously available. Building on recent         accounts of ellipsis, this paper proposes a unified and general account of word-part ellipsis and phrasal ellipsis.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>David Nicolas1 </authors><title>Mass nouns and plural logic      </title><content>A dilemma put forward by Schein (1993, Plurals and events. Cambridge MIT Press) and Rayo (2002, NoГ»s, 36, 436&amp;#8211;464) suggests that, in order to characterize the semantics of plurals, we should not use predicate logic, but plural         logic, a formal language whose terms may refer to several things at once. We show that a similar dilemma applies to mass nouns.         If we use predicate logic and sets when characterizing their semantics, we arrive at a Russellian paradox. And if we use predicate         logic and mereological sums, the semantics turns out to be too weak. We then develop an account where mass nouns are treated         as non-singular terms. This semantics is faithful to the intuition that, if there are eight pieces of silverware on a table,         the speaker refers to eight things at once when he says: The silverware that is on the table comes from Italy. We show that this account provides a satisfactory semantics for a wide range of sentences.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Tim Fern|o1 </authors><title>Observing events and situations in time      </title><content>Events and situations are represented by strings of temporally ordered observations, on the basis of which the events and         situations are recognized. Allen&amp;#8217;s basic interval relations are derived from superposing strings that mark interval boundaries,         and Kamp&amp;#8217;s event structures are constructed as projective limits of strings. Observations are generalized to temporal propositions,         leading to event-types that classify event-instances. Working with sets of strings built from temporal propositions, we obtain         natural notions of bounded entailment from set inclusions. These inclusions are decidable if the sets are accepted by finite         automata.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Raj Singh1 </authors><title>On the interpretation of disjunction: asymmetric, incremental, and eager for inconsistency      </title><content>Hurford&amp;#8217;s Constraint (Hurford, Foundations of Language, 11, 409&amp;#8211;411, 1974) states that a disjunction is infelicitous if its disjuncts stand in an entailment relation: #John was born in Paris or in France. Gazdar (Pragmatics, Academic Press, NY, 1979) observed that scalar implicatures can obviate the constraint. For instance, sentences of the form         (A or B) or (Both Aand B) are felicitous due to the exclusivity implicature of the first disjunct: A or B implicates &amp;#8216;not (A and B)&amp;#8217;. Chierchia, Fox, and Spector (Handbook of semantics, 2008) use the obviation of Hurford&amp;#8217;s Constraint in these cases to argue for a theory of local implicature. I present evidence         indicating that the constraint needs to be modified in two ways. First, implicatures can obviate Hurford&amp;#8217;s Constraint only         in earlier disjuncts, not later ones: #(Both A and B) or (A or B). Second, the constraint rules out not only disjuncts that stand in an entailment relation, but also disjuncts that are even         mutually consistent: #John is from Russia or Asia. I propose to make sense of these facts by providing an incremental evaluation procedure which checks that each new disjunct         to the right is inconsistent with the information to its left, before the disjunct can be strengthened by local implicature.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Patricia Amaral1| Craige Roberts1  | E. Allyn Smith1</authors><title>Review of The Logic of Conventional Implicatures by Chris Potts      </title><content>We review Potts&amp;#8217; influential book on the semantics of conventional implicature (CI), offering an explication of his technical         apparatus and drawing out the proposal&amp;#8217;s implications, focusing on the class of CIs he calls supplements. While we applaud         many facets of this work, we argue that careful considerations of the pragmatics of CIs will be required in order to yield         an empirically and explanatorily adequate account.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Roni Katzir1 </authors><title>Structurally-defined alternatives      </title><content>Scalar implicatures depend on alternatives in order to avoid the symmetry problem. I argue for a structure-sensitive characterization         of these alternatives: the alternatives for a structure are all those structures that are at most as complex as the original         one. There have been claims in the literature that complexity is irrelevant for implicatures and that the relevant condition         is the semantic notion of monotonicity. I provide new data that pose a challenge to the use of monotonicity and that support         the structure-sensitive definition. I show that what appeared to be a problem for the complexity approach is overcome once         an appropriate notion of complexity is adopted, and that upon closer inspection, the argument in favor of monotonicity turns         out to be an argument against it and in favor of the complexity approach.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Isidora Stojanovic1 </authors><title>Talking about taste: disagreement, implicit arguments, and relative truth      </title><content>In this paper, I take issue with an idea that has emerged from recent relativist proposals, and, in particular, from Lasersohn         (Linguistics and Philosophy 28: 643&amp;#8211;686, 2005), according to which the correct semantics for taste predicates must use contents         that are functions of a judge parameter (in addition to a possible world parameter) rather than implicit arguments lexically         associated with such predicates. I argue that the relativist account and the contextualist implicit argument-account are,         from the viewpoint of semantics, not much more than notational variants of one another. In other words, given any sentence         containing a taste predicate, and given any assignment of values to the relevant parameters, the two accounts predict the         same truth value and are, in that sense, equivalent. I also look at possible reasons for preferring one account over the other.         The phenomenon of &amp;#8220;faultless disagreement&amp;#8221; (cf. KГ¶lbel, Truth without objectivity, 2002) is often believed to be one such reason. I argue, against KГ¶lbel and Lasersohn, that disagreement is never faultless:         either the two parties genuinely disagree, hence if the one is right then the other is wrong, or the two parties are both         right, but their apparent disagreement boils down to a misunderstanding. What is more, even if there were faultless disagreement,         I argue that relativism would fail to account for it. The upshot of my paper, then, is to show that there is not much disagreement         between a contextualist account that models the judge parameter as an implicit argument to the taste predicate, and a relativist         account that models it as a parameter of the circumstances of evaluation. The choice between the two accounts, at least when         talking about taste, is thus, to a large extent, a matter of taste.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Stefano Predelli1 </authors><title>The demonstrative theory of quotation      </title><content>This essay proposes a systematic semantic account of Davidson&amp;#8217;s demonstrative theory of pure quotation (Davidson Theory and         decision, 11: 27&amp;#8211;40, 1979) within a classic Kaplan-style framework for indexical languages (Kaplan 1977). I argue that Davidson&amp;#8217;s         informal hints must be developed in terms of the idea of &amp;#8216;character-external&amp;#8217; aspects of meaning, that is, in terms of truth-conditionally         idle restrictions on the class of contexts in which quotation marks may appropriately be used. When thus developed, Davidson&amp;#8217;s         theory may correctly take into account the intuitively special status of disquotational sentences, such as &amp;#8220;Boston&amp;#8217; refers         to Boston&amp;#8217;, and &amp;#8220;&amp;#8216;Boston&amp;#8221; refers to &amp;#8216;Boston&amp;#8221;, and is thus immune from the important objections recently raised in Cappelen         and Lepore 2007.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Anita Mittwoch1 </authors><title>The English Resultative perfect and its relationship to the Experiential perfect and the simple past tense      </title><content>A sentence in the Resultative perfect licenses two inferences: (a) the occurrence of an event (b) the state caused by this         event obtains at evaluation time. In this paper I show that this use of the perfect is subject to a large number of distributional         restrictions that all serve to highlight the result inference at the expense of the event inference. Nevertheless, only the         event inference determines the truth conditions of this use of the perfect, the result inference being a unique type of conventional         implicature. I argue furthermore that, since the result state is singular, the event that causes it must also be singular,         whereas the Experiential perfect is purely quantificational. But in out-of-the-blue contexts the past tense is also normally         interpreted as singular. This leads to a certain amount of competition between the Resultative perfect and the past tense,         and it is this competition, I suggest, that maintains the conventional (non-truth conditional) result state inference.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Gerhard JГ¤ger1 </authors><title>The evolution of convex categories      </title><content>GГ¤rdenfors (Conceptual spaces, 2000) argues that the semantic domains that natural language deals with have a geometrical structure. He gives evidence         that simple natural language adjectives usually denote natural properties, where a natural property is a convex region of such a &amp;#8220;conceptual space.&amp;#8221; In this paper I will show that this feature of natural categories need not be stipulated         as basic. In fact, it can be shown to be the result of evolutionary dynamics of communicative strategies under very general         assumptions.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Alex|er Grosu1  | Manfred Krifka2 </authors><title>         The gifted mathematician that you claim to be: Equational intensional &amp;#8216;reconstruction&amp;#8217; relatives      </title><content>This paper investigates relative constructions as in The gifted mathematician that you claim to be should be able to solve this equation, in which the head noun (gifted mathematician) is semantically dependent on an intensional operator in the relative clause (claim), even though it is not c-commanded by it. This is the kind of situation that has led, within models of linguistic description         that assume a syntactic level of Logical Form, to analyses in which the head noun is interpreted within the CP-internal gap         by reconstruction or interpretation of a lower element of a chain. We offer a solution that views surface representation as         the input to semantics. The apparent inverted scope effects are traced back to the interpretation of the head nominal gifted mathematician as applying to individual concepts, and of the relative clause that you claim to be as including an equational statement. According to this view, the complex DP in question refers to the individual concept         that exists just in the worlds that are compatible with what is generally supposed to be the case, is a gifted mathematician         in those worlds, and is identical to you in those worlds. Our solution is related to the nonreconstructionist analysis of         binding of pronouns that do not stand in a c-command relationship to their binder, as in The woman that every man hugged was his mother in Jacobson (in: Harvey, Santelmann (eds.) Proceedings of Semantics and Linguistic Theory IV:161&amp;#8211;178, 1994) and Sharvit (in:         Galloway, Spence (eds.) Proceedings of Semantics and Linguistic Theory VI:227&amp;#8211;244, 1996), and allows us to capture both similarities         with and differences from the latter type of construction. We point out and offer explanations for a number of properties         of such relative clauses&amp;#8212;in particular their need for an internal intensional operator, their incompatibility with any determiner         other than the definite article, and the fact that some of their properties are shared by demonstrably distinct kinds of relative         clauses.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Yael Sharvit1 </authors><title>The puzzle of free indirect discourse      </title><content>The purpose of this paper is to shed some light on the familiar puzzle of free indirect discourse (FID). FID shares some properties         with standard indirect discourse and with direct discourse, but there is currently no known theory that can accommodate such         a hybrid. Based on the observation that FID has &amp;#8216;de se&amp;#8217; pronouns, I argue that it is a kind of an attitude report.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Jack Hoeksema1 </authors><title>There is no number effect in the licensing of negative polarity items: a reply to Guerzoni and Sharvit      </title><content>Guerzoni and Sharvit (Linguistics and Philosophy 30:361&amp;#8211;391, 2007) provide an argument that plural, but not singular, wh-phrases         may contain a negative polarity item in their restriction, and connect this with the semantic property of exhaustivity. I         will show that this claim is factually incorrect, and that the theory of negative polarity licensing does not need to be complicated         by taking number distinctions into account. In addition, I will argue that number distinctions do not appear to be relevant         for polarity items in the restriction of definite noun phrases either.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Uwe Reyle1 | Antje Rossdeutscher1 | Hans Kamp1</authors><title>Ups and downs in the theory of temporal reference      </title><content>This paper proposes a method for computing the temporal aspects of the interpretations of a variety of Germa sentences. The         method is strictly modular in the sense that it allows each meaning-bearing sentence constituent to make its own, separate,         contribution to the semantic representation of any sentence containing it. The semantic representation of a sentence is reached         in several stages. First, an &amp;#8216;initial semantic representation&amp;#8217; is constructed, using a syntactic analysis of the sentence         as input. This initial representation is then transformed into the definitive representation by a series of transformations         which reflect the ways in which the contributions from different constituents of the sentence interact. Since the different         constituents which make their respective contributions to the meaning of the sentence are in most instances ambiguous, the         initial representations are typically of a high degree of underspecification.      </content></document><document><year>2008</year><authors>Paul Horwich1 </authors><title>What&amp;#8217;s truth got to do with it?      </title><content>This paper offers a critique of mainstream formal semantics. It begins with a statement of widely assumed adequacy conditions:         namely, that a good theory must (1) explain relations of entailment, (ii) show how the meanings of complex expressions derive         from the meanings of their parts, and (iii) characterize facts of meaning in truth-theoretic terms. It then proceeds to criticize         the orthodox conception of semantics that is articulated in these three desiderata. This critique is followed by a sketch         of an alternative conception&amp;#8212;one that is argued to be more in tune with the empirical objectives of linguistics and the clarificatory         aims of philosophy. Finally, the paper proposes and defends a specific theoretical approach&amp;#8212;use based rather than truth based&amp;#8212;that         is suggested by that alternative conception.      </content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>M. Dolores JimГ©nez LГіpez1 </authors><title>A grammar systems approach to natural language grammar</title><content>Taking as its starting point significant similarities between a formal language model&amp;#8212;Grammar Systems&amp;#8212;and a grammatical theory&amp;#8212;Autolexical Syntax&amp;#8212;in this paper we suggest the application of the former to the topic of the latter. To show the applicability of Grammar Systems Theory to grammatical description, we introduce a formal-language-theoretic framework for the architecture of natural language grammar: Linguistic Grammar Systems. We prove the adequacy of this model by highlighting its features (modularity, parallelism, interaction) and by showing the similarity between this framework and accepted and well-known grammatical models (e.g. Autolexical Syntax).</content></document><document><year>2006</year><authors>Yiannis N. Moschovakis1 </authors><title>A Logical Calculus of Meaning and Synonymy      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Elena Guerzoni1 | Yael Sharvit1 </authors><title>A question of strength: on NPIs in interrogative clauses      </title><content>We observe that the facts pertaining to the acceptability of negative polarity items (henceforth, NPIs) in interrogative environments         complex than previously noted. Since Klima [Klima, E. (1964). In J. Fodor &amp;amp; J. Katz (Eds.), The structure of language. Prentice-Hall], it has been typically assumed that NPIs are grammatical in both matrix and embedded questions, however,         on closer scrutiny it turns out that there are differences between root and embedded environments, and between question nucleus         and wh-restrictor. While NPIs are always licensed in the nucleus of root questions, their acceptability in the restrictor of wh-phrases         and in the nucleus of any embedded question depends on the logical properties of the linguistic environment: its strength         in terms of exhaustivity [Groenendijk, J., &amp;amp; Stokhof, M. (1984). Studies on the semantics of questions and the pragmatic answers. Amserdam (NL), Post-Doctoral Dissertation. Heim, I. (1994). In R. Buchalla &amp;amp; A. Mittwoch (Eds.), Proceedings of the 9th annual IATL conference and of the 1993 IATL workshop on discourse (pp. 128&amp;#8211;144). Akademon, Jerusalem. Beck, S., &amp;amp; 16 Rullmann, H. (1999). Natural Language Semantics, 7, 249&amp;#8211;298. Sharvit, Y (2002). Natural Language Semantics, 10, 97&amp;#8211;123] and its monotonicity properties (in the sense of von Fintel [von Fintel, K. (1999). Journal of 19 Semantics, 16, 97-148]).      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Mark Jary1 </authors><title>Are explicit performatives assertions?      </title><content>This paper contributes to the study of explicit performative utterances in the following ways. First, it presents arguments         that support Austin&amp;#8217;s view that these utterances are not assertions. In doing so, it offers an original explanation of why         they cannot be true or false. Second, it puts forward a new analysis of explicit performatives as cases of showing performing,         rather than of instances of asserting or declaring that one is performing a particular act. Finally, it develops a new account         of the role of the performative prefix in signalling performative intentions that shows how the prefix can play a special         role in the interpretation of performatives utterances.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Geoffrey K. Pullum1  | Kyle Rawlins1</authors><title>Argument or no argument?      </title><content>We examine an argument for the non-context-freeness of English that has received virtually no discussion in the literature.         It is based on adjuncts of the form &amp;#8216;X or no X&amp;#8217;, where X is a nominal. The construction has been held to exemplify unbounded         syntactic reduplication. We argue that although the argument can be made in a mathematically valid form, its empirical basis         is not claimed unbounded syntactic identity between nominals does not always hold in attested cases, and second, an understanding         of the semantics of the construction removes the necessity of making reference to any syntactic reduplication.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Anthony S. Gillies1 </authors><title>Counterfactual scorekeeping      </title><content>Orthodoxy has it that counterfactuals cannot be treated as strict conditionals. But there is a loophole: if the strictness         is a function of context then maybe they can be so treated. I argue for a loophole analysis that treats &amp;#8216;would&amp;#8217;-counterfactuals         as strict conditionals that are duals to &amp;#8216;might&amp;#8217;- counterfactuals. Most of the work lies in getting straight about the interaction         between context and semantic value. I treat it as a general feature of the dynamics of conversational score.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Eric McCready1  | Norry Ogata2</authors><title>Evidentiality, modality and probability      </title><content>We show in this paper that some expressions indicating source of evidence are part of propositional content and are best analyzed         as special kind of epistemic modal. Our evidence comes from the Japanese evidential system. We consider six evidentials in         Japanese, showing that they can be embedded in conditionals and under modals and that their properties with respect to modal         subordination are similar to those of ordinary modals. We show that these facts are difficult for existing theories of evidentials,         which assign evidentials necessarily widest scope, to explain. We then provide an analysis using a logical system designed         to account for evidential reasoning; this logic is the first developed system of probabilistic dynamic predicate logic. This         analysis is shown to account for the data we provide that is problematic for other theories.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Michael W. Pelczar1 </authors><title>Forms and objects of thought      </title><content>It is generally assumed that if it is possible to believe that p without believing that q, then there is some difference between         the object of the thought that p and the object of the thought that q. This assumption is challenged in the present paper,         opening the way to an account of epistemic opacity that improves on existing accounts, not least because it casts doubt on         various arguments that attempt to derive startling ontological conclusions from seemingly innocent epistemic premises.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>F. Recanati1 </authors><title>It is raining (somewhere)      </title><content>The received view about meteorological predicates like &amp;#8216;rain&amp;#8217; is that they carry an argument slot for a location which can         be filled explicitly or implicitly. The view assumes that &amp;#8216;rain&amp;#8217;, in the absence of an explicit location, demands that the         context provide a specific location. In an earlier article in this journal, I provided a counter-example, viz. a context in         which &amp;#8216;it is raining&amp;#8217; receives a location-indefinite interpretation. On the basis of that example, I argued that when there         is tacit references to a location, it takes place for pragmatic reasons and casts no light on the semantics of meteorological         predicates. Since then, several authors have reanalysed the counter-example, so as to make it compatible with the standard         view. I discuss those attempts and argue that my account is superior.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Kimiko Nakanishi1 </authors><title>Measurement in the nominal and verbal domains      </title><content>This paper examines some aspects of the grammar of measurement based on data from non-split and split measure phrase (MP)         constructions in Japanese. I claim that the non-split MP construction involves measurement of individuals, while the split         MP construction involves measurement of events as well as of individuals. This claim is based on the observation that, while         both constructions are subject to some semantic restrictions in the nominal domain, only the split MP construction is sensitive         to restrictions in the verbal domain (namely, incompatibility with single-occurrence events and with individual-level predicates,         and (un)availability of collective readings). It is shown that these semantic restrictions can be explained by a uniform semantic         constraint on the measure function, namely, Schwarzschild&amp;#8217;s [(2002). The grammar of measurement. The Proceedings of Semantics and Linguistics Theory, 24, 241&amp;#8211;306] monotonicity constraint. In particular, I argue that, in the two constructions at issue, the measure function is         subject to the monotonicity constraint, and that we observe different semantic restrictions depending on whether the measure         function applies to a nominal or a verbal domain.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Thomas Ede Zimmermann1 </authors><title>Monotonicity in opaque verbs      </title><content>The paper is about the interpretation of opaque verbs like &amp;#8220;seek&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;owe&amp;#8221;, and &amp;#8220;resemble&amp;#8221; which allow for unspecific readings         of their (indefinite) objects. It is shown that the following two observations create a problem for semantic analysis:                                     (a);               The opaque position is upward monotone: &amp;#8220;John seeks a unicorn&amp;#8221; implies &amp;#8220;John seeks an animal&amp;#8221;, given that &amp;#8220;unicorn&amp;#8221; is more                  specific than &amp;#8220;animal&amp;#8221;.                                                      (b);               Indefinite objects of opaque verbs allow for higher-order, or &amp;#8220;underspecific&amp;#8221;, readings: &amp;#8220;Jones is looking for something Smith                  is looking for&amp;#8221; can express that there is something unspecific that both Jones and Smith are looking for.                                                                  Given (a) and (b), it would seem that the following inference is hard to escape, if the premisses are construed unspecifically               and the conclusion is taken on its under- specific reading:                                                                                             ;                        Jones is looking for a sweater.                                                                  ;                        Smith is looking for a pen.                                                                  ;                        Smith is looking for something Jones is looking for.                                                                                 </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Jon Robert Gajewski1 </authors><title>Neg-Raising and Polarity      </title><content>The representation of Neg-Raising in the grammar is a matter of controversy. I provide evidence for representing Neg-Raising         as a kind of presupposition associated with certain predicates by providing a detailed analysis of NPI-licensing in Neg-Raising         contexts. Specific features of presupposition projection are used to explain the licensing of strict NPIs under Neg-Raising         predicates. Discussion centers around the analysis of a licensing asymmetry noted in Horn (1971, Negative transportation:         Unsafe at any speed? In CLS 7 (pp. 120&amp;#8211;133)).Having provided this analysis, I go on to discuss its implications for the theory of NPI-licensing more         generally. In particular, I discuss how the present proposal reflects on von Fintel&amp;#8217;s (1999, Journal of Semantics, 16, 97&amp;#8211;148) proposal to use Strawson downward entailment in the statement of NPI-licensing principles.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Chris Barker1 </authors><title>Parasitic scope      </title><content>I propose the first strictly compositional semantic account of same. New data, including especially NP-internal uses such as two men with the same name, suggests that same in its basic use is a quantificational element taking scope over nominals. Given type-lifting as a generally available mechanism,         I show that this follows naturally from the fact that same is an adjective. Independently-motivated assumptions extend the analysis to standard examples such as Anna and Bill read the same book via a mechanism I call PARASITIC SCOPE, in which the scope of same depends on the scope of some other scopetaking element in the sentence. Although I will initially discuss the analysis in         terms of a familiar Quantifier Raising framework, I go on to implement the analysis within an innovative continuation-based         Type-Logical Grammar. The empirical payoff for dealing in continuations is that a simple generalization of the basic analysis         gives the first ever formal account of cases in which same distributes over objects other than NP denotations, as in the relevant interpretation of John hit and killed the same man.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Michela Ippolito1 </authors><title>Semantic Composition and Presupposition Projection in Subjunctive Conditionals      </title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Lisa Matthewson1 </authors><title>Temporal semantics in a superficially tenseless language      </title><content>This paper contributes to the debate about &amp;#8216;tenseless languages&amp;#8217; by defending a tensed analysis of a superficially tenseless         language. The language investigated is St&amp;#8217;ГЎt&amp;#8217;imcets (Lillooet Salish). I argue that although St&amp;#8217;ГЎt&amp;#8217;imcets lacks overt tense         morphology, every finite clause in the language possesses a phonologically covert tense morpheme; this tense morpheme restricts         the reference time to being non-future. Future interpretations, as well as &amp;#8216;past future&amp;#8217; would-readings, are obtained by the combination of covert tense with an operator analogous to Abusch&amp;#8217;s (1985) WOLL. I offer St&amp;#8217;ГЎt&amp;#8217;imcets-internal         evidence (of a kind not previously adduced) that the WOLL-like operator is modal in nature. It follows from the analysis presented         here that there are only two (probably related) differences between St&amp;#8217;ГЎt&amp;#8217;imcets and English in the area of tense. The first         is that St&amp;#8217;ГЎt&amp;#8217;imcets lacks tense morphemes which are pronounced. The second is that the St&amp;#8217;ГЎt&amp;#8217;imcets tense morpheme is semantically         underspecified compared to English ones. In each of these respects, the St&amp;#8217;ГЎt&amp;#8217;imcets tense morpheme displays similar properties         to pronouns, which may be covert and which may fail to distinguish person, number or gender. Along the way, I point out several         striking and subtle similarities in the interpretive possibilities of St&amp;#8217;ГЎt&amp;#8217;imcets and English. I suggest that these similarities         may reveal non-accidental properties of tense systems in natural language. I conclude with discussion of the implications         of the analysis for cross-linguistic variation, learnability and the possible existence of tenseless languages.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Marcus Kracht1| 2 </authors><title>The emergence of syntactic structure      </title><content>The present paper is the result of a long struggle to understand how the notion of compositionality can be used to motivate         the structure of a sentence. While everyone seems to have intuitions about which proposals are compositional and which ones         are not, these intuitions generally have no formal basis. What is needed to make such arguments work is a proper understanding         of what meanings are and how they can be manipulated. In particular, we need a definition of meaning that bans all mentioning         of syntactic structure; it is not the task of semantics to state in which way things are put together in syntax. The present         paper presents such a theory of meaning. This, in tandem with some minimal assumptions on the syntactic process (that there         can be no deletion) yield surprisingly deep insights into natural language. First, it rehabilitates a lot of linguistic work         as necessary on semantic grounds and defends it against potential claims of redundancy. For example, &amp;#952;-roles and linking are         an integral part of semantics, and not syntax. To assume the latter is to put the cart before the horse. Second, as a particular         example we shall show that Dutch is not strongly context free even if weakly context free. To our knowledge, this is the first         formal proof of this fact.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Frank Hindriks1 </authors><title>The status of the knowledge account of assertion      </title><content>According to the increasingly popular knowledge account, assertion is governed by the rule that speech acts of that kind require         knowledge of their content. Timothy Williamson has argued that this knowledge rule is the constitutive rule of assertion.         It is argued here that it is not the constitutive rule of assertion in any sense of the term, as it governs only some assertions         rather than all of them. A (qualified) knowledge rule can in fact be derived from the traditional analysis of assertion according         to which assertion is the linguistic expression of belief. Because it is more informative, this analysis provides a better         point of departure for defending the knowledge account than Williamson&amp;#8217;s view according to which the knowledge rule is part         of the analysis of assertion.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Danny Fox1  | Martin Hackl2 </authors><title>The universal density of measurement      </title><content>The notion of measurement plays a central role in human cognition. We measure people&amp;#8217;s height, the weight of physical objects,         the length of stretches of time, or the size of various collections of individuals. Measurements of height, weight, and the         like are commonly thought of as mappings between objects and dense scales, while measurements of collections of individuals,         as implemented for instance in counting, are assumed to involve discrete scales. It is also commonly assumed that natural         language makes use of both types of scales and subsequently distinguishes between two types of measurements. This paper argues         against the latter assumption. It argues that natural language semantics treats all measurements uniformly as mappings from         objects (individuals or collections of individuals) to dense scales, hence the Universal Density of Measurement (UDM). If         the arguments are successful, there are a variety of consequences for semantics and pragmatics, and more generally for the         place of the linguistic system within an overall architecture of cognition.      </content></document><document><year>2007</year><authors>Christopher Kennedy1 </authors><title>Vagueness and grammar: the semantics of relative and absolute gradable adjectives      </title><content>This paper investigates the way that linguistic expressions influence vagueness, focusing on the interpretation of the positive         (unmarked) form of gradable adjectives. I begin by developing a semantic analysis of the positive form of &amp;#8216;relative&amp;#8217; gradable         adjectives, expanding on previous proposals by further motivating a semantic basis for vagueness and by precisely identifying         and characterizing the division of labor between the compositional and contextual aspects of its interpretation. I then introduce         a challenge to the analysis from the class of &amp;#8216;absolute&amp;#8217; gradable adjectives: adjectives that are demonstrably gradable, but         which have positive forms that relate objects to maximal or minimal degrees, and do not give rise to vagueness. I argue that         the truth conditional difference between relative and absolute adjectives in the positive form stems from the interaction         of lexical semantic properties of gradable adjectives&amp;#8212;the structure of the scales they use&amp;#8212;and a general constraint on interpretive         economy that requires truth conditions to be computed on the basis of conventional meaning to the extent possible, allowing         for context dependent truth conditions only as a last resort.      </content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Maria Aloni</authors><title>A Formal Treatment of the Pragmatics of Questions and Attitudes*      </title><content>This article discusses pragmatic aspects of our interpretation of intensional constructions like questions and prepositional         attitude reports. In the first part, it argues that our evaluation of these constructions may vary relative to the identification         methods operative in the context of use. This insight is then given a precise formalization in a possible world semantics.         In the second part, an account of actual evaluations of questions and attitudes is proposed in the framework of bi-directional         optimality theory. Pragmatic meaning selections are explained as the result of specific rankings of potentially conflicting         generation and interpretation constraints.      </content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Michael Mccord1  | Arendse Bernth1 </authors><title>A Metalogical Theory of Natural Language Semantics</title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Veronica Dahl1| Fred Popowich1 | Michael Rochemont2</authors><title>A principled characterization of dislocated phrases: Capturing barriers with Static Discontinuity Grammars</title><content>Parsing according to the principles of modern linguistic theory is only now becoming a computationally interesting task. We contribute to these developments by illustrating how the account of movement introduced by Chomsky inBarriers can be incorporated into a Static Discontinuity Grammar (SDG). We are concerned with A''-movement as reflected inwh movement of arguments and adjuncts. The resulting SDG can be processed by an SDG parser to recover the thematic information and constitutency structure associated with a natural language sentence.</content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>David A. H. Elworthy1</authors><title>A theory of anaphoric information</title><content>Without Abstract</content></document><document><year>2005</year><authors>Margarita Su&amp;ntilde er1</authors><title>About indirect questions and semi-questions</title><content>Without Abstract</content></document></documents>